<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
    <monster>
        <name>Imperial Comm Operator</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Humanoid</type>
        <alignment>lawful neutral</alignment>
        <ac>12 (Combat Suit)</ac>
        <hp>18 (4d8)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>11</str>
        <dex>13</dex>
        <con>11</con>
        <int>10</int>
        <wis>10</wis>
        <cha>10</cha>
        <passive>12</passive>
        <languages>Galactic Basic</languages>
        <cr>1/4</cr>
        <action>
            <name>Blaster Pistol</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, range 40/160 ft., one target. Hit 4 (1d6+1) energy damage. Reload
                12.
            </text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Vibrodagger</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, reach 5ft., one target. Hit: 3 (1d4+1) kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Destroyer Droid</name>
        <size>L</size>
        <type>Droid</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>17 (armor plating)</ac>
        <hp>142 (15d10+60)</hp>
        <speed>15 ft. (attack form), 30 ft. (ball form)</speed>
        <str>14</str>
        <dex>18</dex>
        <con>18</con>
        <int>13</int>
        <wis>15</wis>
        <cha>7</cha>
        <skill>Perception +5</skill>
        <vulnerable>Ion</vulnerable>
        <resist>Necrotic, Poison, Psychic</resist>
        <conditionImmune>poison, disease</conditionImmune>
        <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
        <passive>14</passive>
        <languages>Binary, Galactic Basic</languages>
        <cr>7</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Ball Form</name>
            <text>As a bonus action, the destroyer droid can transform into or out of ball form. While in ball form, the
                destroyer droid has increased speed, but it can not attack.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Multiattack</name>
            <text>The destroyer droid makes two weapon attacks.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Blaster Cannons</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +7 to hit, range 100/400, one target. Hit: 11 (2d6+4) energy damage.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Blaster Volley</name>
            <text>The destroyer droid sprays a 10-foot-cube area within normal range of its blaster cannons with shots.
                Each creature in the area must make a DC 15 Dexterity saving throw, taking normal weapon damage on a
                failed save.
            </text>
        </action>
        <reaction>
            <name>Deflector Shield</name>
            <text>The destroyer droid adds 3 to its AC against one attack that would hit it. To do so, the super battle
                droid must see the attacker.
            </text>
        </reaction>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>The destroyer droid is a type of heavy battle droid originally crafted by colicoids. It has a
            reputation for deadliness due to its resilience and firepower, as well as the fear it can instill in even
            the most powerful Jedi. They are also used for executions. Destroyer droids are equipped with dual built-in
            blaster cannons and a built-in deflector shield generator. Due to their ponderous nature, destroyer droids
            have a ball-form that they can transform into, granting them great speed.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Trooper</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Humanoid (any)</type>
        <alignment>any alignment</alignment>
        <ac>15 (light battle armor)</ac>
        <hp>13 (2d8+4)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>13</str>
        <dex>16</dex>
        <con>15</con>
        <int>9</int>
        <wis>11</wis>
        <cha>10</cha>
        <senses>Dark vision 60 ft.</senses>
        <passive>10</passive>
        <languages>Galactic Basic and one other</languages>
        <cr>1/2</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Blaster Rifle</name>
            <text>Ranged weapon attack. +5 to hit, range 100/400 ft., one target. Hit: 7 (1d8+3) energy damage.</text>
            <attack>|5|1d8+3</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Stock Strike</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 3 (1d4+1) kinetic damage.</text>
            <attack>|3|1d4+1</attack>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Adolescent Acklay</name>
        <size>H</size>
        <type>Beast</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>13 (natural armor)</ac>
        <hp>95 (10d12+30)</hp>
        <speed>40 ft.</speed>
        <str>22</str>
        <dex>9</dex>
        <con>17</con>
        <int>3</int>
        <wis>11</wis>
        <cha>5</cha>
        <passive>10</passive>
        <languages>–</languages>
        <cr>5</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Trampling Charge</name>
            <text>If the acklay moves at least 20 feet straight toward a creature and then hits it with a bite attack on
                the same turn, that target must succeed on a DC 16 Strength saving throw or be knocked prone. If the
                target is prone, the acklay can make one claw attack against it as a bonus action.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Bite</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +9 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 24 (4d8+6) kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Claw</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +9 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 21 (3d10+6) kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>Acklays are amphibious reptillian crustaceans with six deadly claws and razor-sharp teeth native to
            the planet Vendaxa. They are often used as execution beasts or fodder for gladiatorial arenas.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>AT-RT</name>
        <size>L</size>
        <type>Construct</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>15 (armor plating)</ac>
        <hp>58 (9d10+9)</hp>
        <speed>50 ft.</speed>
        <str>15</str>
        <dex>16</dex>
        <con>12</con>
        <int>10</int>
        <wis>10</wis>
        <cha>7</cha>
        <save>Dexterity +5</save>
        <vulnerable>Ion</vulnerable>
        <resist>Necrotic, Poison, Psychic</resist>
        <immune>Poison, Necrotic</immune>
        <conditionImmune>poison, disease</conditionImmune>
        <senses>–</senses>
        <passive>0</passive>
        <languages>–</languages>
        <cr>4</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Circuitry</name>
            <text>The construct has disadvantage on saving throws against effects that would deal ion or lightning
                damage.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Piloted</name>
            <text>The construct requires an active pilot to take any actions, and if the pilot is subjected to any
                conditions that the construct is not immune to, the construct is also subjected to those conditions. The
                pilot may take their own action or one of the actions granted by the construct.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Multiattack</name>
            <text>The construct makes two attacks with its repeating blaster cannon or uses its mortar launcher.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Repeating Blaster Cannon</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, range 60/240 ft., one target. Hit: 10 (2d6+3) energy damage.</text>
            <attack>|5|2d6+3</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Mortar Launcher</name>
            <text>The construct launches a mortar at a point it can see within 100 feet. Each creature in a 20-foot
                radius centered on that point must make a Dexterity saving throw. A target takes 14 (4d6) damage on a
                failed save, or half as much on a succesful one.
            </text>
            <attack>||4d6</attack>
        </action>
        <reaction>
            <name>Redirect</name>
            <text>If the construct&#39;s pilot takes damage from a source the pilot is aware of and can see, the
                construct can use its reaction to instead take that damage.
            </text>
        </reaction>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>The All Terrain Recon Transport (or AT-RT) is a one-man bipedal walker used for reconnaissance and
            patrolling made by Kuat Drive Yards as part of their All Terrain series. It is equipped with a single seat
            for a pilot, as well as a repeating blaster cannon and mortar launcher.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Swarm Of Shyracks</name>
        <size>L</size>
        <type>Swarm of Small Beasts</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>12 (natural armor)</ac>
        <hp>38 (6d10+10)</hp>
        <speed>0 ft., Fly 20 ft.</speed>
        <str>6</str>
        <dex>18</dex>
        <con>11</con>
        <int>3</int>
        <wis>12</wis>
        <cha>4</cha>
        <resist>Energy, Kinetic</resist>
        <conditionImmune>Charmed, Frightened, Paralyzed, Petrified, Prone, Restrained, Stunned</conditionImmune>
        <senses>blindsight 60ft</senses>
        <passive>11</passive>
        <cr>1</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Keen Hearing</name>
            <text>The Shyrack has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on hearing.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Swarm</name>
            <text>The swarm can occupy another creature&#39;s space and vice versa, and the swarm can move through any
                opening large enough for a small shyrack. The swarm can&#39;t regain hit points or gain temporary hit
                points.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Bite</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one creature in the swarm&#39;s space. Hit: 9 (2d8)
                kinetic damage, or 4 (1d8) kinetic damage if the swarm has half of its hit points or fewer.
            </text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>Shyracks are cave-dwelling terrors that are fiercely territorial and attack any intruder with
            aggression and fervor. While typically cave bound, every sixty-three years the shyracks of Korriban spill
            from their cave habitats for an entire summer. These periods saw them fill the sky where they blotted out
            the sun and moon where they rained their bluish droppings onto everything below. Prior to the return of the
            Sith Empire, biologists from across the galaxy arrived on the planet in order to witness every sixty-third
            summer where they observed the purpling of the red Korriban terrain.

            While ungainly and slow-moving with no eyes, shyracks are potentially dangerous pests, especially when they
            converge as a swarm on an intruder. They are native to the Shyrack cave of Korriban and are natural rivals
            to the feared Tuk&#39;ata.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Commoner (SW5E)</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>humanoid (any), SW5E custom</type>
        <alignment>any alignment</alignment>
        <ac>10</ac>
        <hp>4 (1d8)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>10</str>
        <dex>10</dex>
        <con>10</con>
        <int>10</int>
        <wis>10</wis>
        <cha>10</cha>
        <passive>10</passive>
        <languages>Galatic Basic and one other</languages>
        <cr>0</cr>
        <action>
            <name>Light Pistol</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +2 to hit, range 40/160, one target. Hit: 2 (1d4) energy damage.</text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Ancient Rancor</name>
        <size>H</size>
        <type>Beast</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>17 (natural armor)</ac>
        <hp>432 (32d12+224)</hp>
        <speed>40 ft.</speed>
        <str>25</str>
        <dex>11</dex>
        <con>25</con>
        <int>7</int>
        <wis>11</wis>
        <cha>6</cha>
        <save>Strength +13</save>
        <save>Dexterity +6</save>
        <save>Constitution +13</save>
        <save>Wisdom +6</save>
        <skill>Athletics +13</skill>
        <resist>Energy, Ion, and kinetic from unenhanced weapons</resist>
        <senses>darkvision 120 ft.</senses>
        <passive>16</passive>
        <languages>–</languages>
        <cr>19</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Siege Monster</name>
            <text>The rancor deals double damage to objects and structures.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Legendary Resistance (3/day)</name>
            <text>If the Rancor fails a saving throw, it can choose to succeed instead.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Multiattack</name>
            <text>The Rancor can use its Frightful Roar. It then makes three attacks: two with its claws, and one with
                its bite. It can use its swallow instead of its bite.
            </text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Claw</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +13 to hit, reach 10ft., one target. Hit 20 (3d8 + 7) Kinetic damage.</text>
            <attack>|13|3d8+7</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Bite</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +13 to hit, reach 5ft., one target. Hit 27 (3d12 + 7) Kinetic damage. If the
                target is a creature, it is grappled (escape DC 17). Until this grapple ends, the target is restrained,
                and the rancor can&#39;t bite another target.
            </text>
            <attack>|13|3d12+7</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Throw Boulder</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +13 to hit, reach 60/240 ft., one target. Hit 33 (4d12 + 7) Kinetic damage.
            </text>
            <attack>|13|4d12+7</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Frightful Roar</name>
            <text>Each creature of the rancor&#39;s choice within 90 feet of it must succeed a DC 17 Wisdom saving throw
                or become frightened for 1 minute. A creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its
                turns, with disadvantage if the Rancor is within line of sight, ending the effect on itself on a
                success. If a creature&#39;s saving throw is successful or the effect ends for it, the creature is
                immune to the rancor&#39;s Frightful Roar for the next 24 hours.
            </text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Swallow</name>
            <text>The Rancor makes one bite attack against a Medium or smaller creature it is grappling. If the attack
                hits, the target takes the bite&#39;s damage, the target is swallowed, and the grapple ends. While
                swallowed, the creature is blinded and restrained, it has total cover against attacks and other effects
                outside the Rancor, and it takes 35 (10d6) acid damage at the start of each of the Rancor&#39;s turns.
                If the Rancor takes 35 damage or more on a single turn from a creature inside it, the Rancor must suceed
                on a DC 23 Constitution saving throw at the end of that turn or regurgitate all swallowed creatures,
                which fall prone in a space within 10 feet of the Rancor. If the Rancor dies, a swallowed creature is no
                longer restrained by it and can escape from the corpse by using 10 feet of movement, exiting prone.
            </text>
            <attack>||10d6</attack>
        </action>
        <legendary>
            <text>The Ancient Rancor can take 3 legendary actions, choosing from the options below. Only one legendary
                action option can be used at a time and only at the end of another creature&#39;s turn. The Ancient
                Rancor regains spent legendary actions at the start of their turn.
            </text>
        </legendary>
        <legendary>
            <name>Attack</name>
            <text>The Rancor makes one claw attack.</text>
        </legendary>
        <legendary>
            <name>Throw (Costs 2 Actions)</name>
            <text>The Rancor uses its throw boulder.</text>
        </legendary>
        <legendary>
            <name>Chomp (Costs 2 Actions)</name>
            <text>The Rancor makes one bite attack or uses its swallow.</text>
        </legendary>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>Rancors are large carnivorous reptomammals native to the planet of Dathomir. They are commonly kept
            as pets by affluent, less-than-reputable types.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Dark Juggernaut</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Humanoid</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>21 (heavy durasteel armor, heavy shield)</ac>
        <hp>180 (19d8+95)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>20</str>
        <dex>11</dex>
        <con>20</con>
        <int>12</int>
        <wis>19</wis>
        <cha>18</cha>
        <save>Strength +11</save>
        <save>Dexterity +6</save>
        <save>Wisdom +10</save>
        <save>Charisma +10</save>
        <skill>Athletics +11</skill>
        <resist>necrotic</resist>
        <conditionImmune>exhaustion, frightened</conditionImmune>
        <passive>13</passive>
        <cr>17</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Force Resistance</name>
            <text>The juggernaut has advantage on saving throws against force powers.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Spellcasting (Forcecasting)</name>
            <text>The juggernaut is an 19th-level forcecaster. Its forcecasting ability is Wisdom (power save DC 18, +10
                to hit with force attacks) and it has 38 force points. The juggernaut knows the following force powers:
                At-will: affect mind (universal force), denounce (dark force), feedback (dark force), lightning charge
                (dark force), saber ward (universal force)
                1st-level: force jump (universal force), improved feedback (dark force), sap vitality (dark force),
                wound (dark force)
                2nd-level: darkness (dark force), drain vitality (dark force), force sight (universal force)
                3rd-level: choke (dark force), force scream (dark force), sever force (universal force)
                4th-level: dominate beast (dark force), force immunity (universal force), shroud of darkness (dark
                force)
                5th-level: greater feedback (dark force), improved force scream (dark force), improved phase strike
                (universal force)
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Multiattack</name>
            <text>The juggernaut makes three attacks.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Lightsaber</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +11 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 9 (1d8 + 5) energy damage.</text>
            <attack>|11|1d8+5</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Conquering Presence</name>
            <text>(1/Day). Each creature within 30 feet of the juggernaut must make a DC 18 Wisdom saving throw. On a
                failed save, a creature becomes frightened of the juggernaut for 1 minute, and has its speed reduced to
                0. At the end of each of its turns, a frightened creature takes 4 psychic damage and repeats this save,
                ending the effect on a success.
            </text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Demolitions Trooper</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Humanoid</type>
        <alignment>any alignment</alignment>
        <ac>16 (durasteel armor)</ac>
        <hp>16 (2d10+6)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>13</str>
        <dex>14</dex>
        <con>16</con>
        <int>11</int>
        <wis>10</wis>
        <cha>9</cha>
        <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
        <passive>10</passive>
        <languages>Galactic Basic, one other</languages>
        <cr>1/2</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Fragmentation Grenade</name>
            <text>(3/day). The trooper throws a grenade, choosing a point within 35 ft. Each creature within 10 feet
                must make a DC 12 Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes 2d6 kinetic damage on a failed save, or half
                as much as on a successful one.
            </text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Set Mine</name>
            <text>(2/day). After setting this mine, a laser line imperceptible to normal vision extends up to 15 feet
                out. When the laser is tripped, the mine explodes, and each creature within 15 feet of it must make a DC
                13 Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 3d6 kinetic damage, or half as much on a
                successful one.
            </text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Breaching Charge</name>
            <text>(2/day). After spending at least 30 seconds setting the charge, the trooper may attach the charge to a
                surface. The charge can be set with a 6-second timer, or detonated remotely using a remote detonator,
                which the trooper has. Once detonated, the breaching charge destroys an unenhanced section of wall up to
                10 feet wide, 10 feet tall, and 5 feet deep. Additionally, each creature within 20 feet of the charge
                must make a DC 15 Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes 3d6 fire damage and 3d6 kinetic damage on a
                failed save, or half as much on a successful one. A construct makes this save with disadvantage. If the
                breaching charge is installed on the construct, it automatically fails the saving throw.
            </text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Blaster Pistol</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, range 40/160 ft., one target. Hit: 5 (1d6+2) energy damage.</text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Tauntaun</name>
        <size>L</size>
        <type>Beast</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>9 (natural armor)</ac>
        <hp>15 (2d10+4)</hp>
        <speed>50 ft.</speed>
        <str>16</str>
        <dex>8</dex>
        <con>14</con>
        <int>2</int>
        <wis>8</wis>
        <cha>5</cha>
        <passive>9</passive>
        <languages>–</languages>
        <cr>1/8</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Bite</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 5 (1d4+3) kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <environment>Arctic</environment>
        <description>Tauntauns are a species of omnivorous reptomammals who are indigenous to the icy planet of Hoth.
            Tauntauns were commonly used as pack animals by Hoth&#39;s denizens. Tauntauns are also used as patrol
            mounts since they are so well-adapted to the cold.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Adult Varactyl</name>
        <size>L</size>
        <type>Beast</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>11</ac>
        <hp>19 (3d10+32)</hp>
        <speed>50 ft., climb 30 ft.</speed>
        <str>18</str>
        <dex>12</dex>
        <con>13</con>
        <int>2</int>
        <wis>12</wis>
        <cha>7</cha>
        <passive>11</passive>
        <languages>–</languages>
        <cr>1/2</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Trampling Charge</name>
            <text>If the varactyl moves at least 20 feet straight toward a creature and then hits it with a bite attack
                on the same turn, that target must succeed on a DC 14 Strength saving throw or be knocked prone. If the
                target is prone, the varactyl can make another attack with its bite against it as a bonus action.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Bite</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 11 (2d6 + 4) kinetic damage.</text>
            <attack>|6|2d6+4</attack>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>Varactyls are a species of majestic, giant reptavian herbivores native to the world of Utapau. They
            typically have blue and green feather manes and feather ridges along their back. They are incredibly loyal
            and obedient mounts, that had strong long strides to navigate the uneven and vertical surfaces of their
            homeworld.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Dark Acolyte</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Force-wielder (any)</type>
        <alignment>any dark</alignment>
        <ac>11 (unarmored)</ac>
        <hp>9 (2d8)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>10</str>
        <dex>12</dex>
        <con>10</con>
        <int>10</int>
        <wis>14</wis>
        <cha>11</cha>
        <passive>10</passive>
        <languages>Galactic Basic and one other</languages>
        <cr>1/4</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Skills</name>
            <text>Lore +2</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Spellcasting (Forcecasting)</name>
            <text>The acolyte is a 1st-level forcecaster. Its forcecasting ability is Wisdom (power save DC 12, +4 to
                hit with force attacks) and it has 6 force points. The acolyte knows the following force powers:
                At-will: slow (Dark Force), Denounce (Dark Force), force push/pull (Universal Force), saber ward
                (Universal Force)
                1st-level: cloud mind (Light Force), saber reflect (Universal Force)
            </text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Shotosaber</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 4 (1d6+1) energy damage.</text>
            <attack>|3|1d6+1</attack>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>BX Commando Droid</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Droid</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>15 (armor plating)</ac>
        <hp>49 (9d8+9)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>12</str>
        <dex>17</dex>
        <con>13</con>
        <int>15</int>
        <wis>13</wis>
        <cha>7</cha>
        <skill>Perception +3</skill>
        <skill>Stealth +5</skill>
        <vulnerable>Ion</vulnerable>
        <resist>Necrotic, Poison, Psychic</resist>
        <conditionImmune>poison, disease</conditionImmune>
        <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
        <passive>12</passive>
        <languages>Binary, Galactic Basic</languages>
        <cr>2</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Circuitry</name>
            <text>The droid has disadvantage on saving throws against effects that would deal ion or lightning damage.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Droid Synergy</name>
            <text>Once per turn, the commando droid can deal an extra 3 (1d6) damage to a creature it hits with a weapon
                attack if that creature is within 5 feet of an ally of the commando droid that isn&#39;t incapacitated.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Stealth Field Generator</name>
            <text>The commando droid has advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks that rely on sight.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Blaster Carbine</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, range 60/240 ft., one target. Hit: 6 (1d6+3) energy damage.</text>
            <attack>|5|1d6+3</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Techblade</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 6 (1d6+3) kinetic damage.</text>
            <attack>|5|1d6+3</attack>
        </action>
        <reaction>
            <name>Redirect Attack</name>
            <text>When a creature the battle droid can see targets it with an attack, the battle droid chooses another
                battle droid within 5 feet of it. The two battle droids swap places, and the chosen battle droid becomes
                the target instead.
            </text>
        </reaction>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>The BX series commando droid is an elite battle droid model made for stealth assignments. Equipped
            with a stealth field generator, they are perfectly designed for espionage.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Sibian Hound</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Beast</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>13 (natural armor)</ac>
        <hp>11 (2d8+2)</hp>
        <speed>40 ft.</speed>
        <str>12</str>
        <dex>15</dex>
        <con>12</con>
        <int>3</int>
        <wis>12</wis>
        <cha>6</cha>
        <skill>Perception +3</skill>
        <skill>Stealth +4</skill>
        <passive>13</passive>
        <languages>–</languages>
        <cr>1/4</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Keen Hearing and Smell</name>
            <text>The hound has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on hearing or smell.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Pack Tactics</name>
            <text>The hound has advantage on attack rolls against a creature if at least one of the hound&#39;s allies
                is within 5 feet of the creature and the ally isn&#39;t incapacitated.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Bite</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 7 (2d4+2) kinetic damage. If the target
                is Large or smaller, it must succeed on a DC 11 Strength saving throw or be knocked prone.
            </text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>Sibian hounds are a type of hound native to the planet Corellia. A fleet-footed, loud-barking,
            vicious species, they are often used for attack and hunting, but do not make good pets.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Porg</name>
        <size>T</size>
        <type>Beast</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>12</ac>
        <hp>1 (1d4-1)</hp>
        <speed>10 ft, fly 50 ft.</speed>
        <str>2</str>
        <dex>14</dex>
        <con>8</con>
        <int>2</int>
        <wis>12</wis>
        <cha>6</cha>
        <skill>Perception +3</skill>
        <passive>13</passive>
        <languages>–</languages>
        <cr>0</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Keen Smell</name>
            <text>The porg has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on smell.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Bite</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 1 kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>Porgs are a species of non-sentient birds. They are stocky in nature, with two short wings, flat,
            beak-less faces, and two webbed feet. Porgs are sexually dimorphic; males are slightly larger than females,
            and males also have orange plumage around the eyes. Porgs of both sexes are covered in dense feathers, with
            white coloration on the body and face, and gray to brown on the wings and back. They are much lighter than
            they looked, thanks to a thick outer layer of waterproof feathers with a fluffy underlayer for warmth. They
            can fly short distances but not far enough to leave their native island. They can also run quite swiftly on
            the ground and are good at maneuvering into small spaces. The birds have stereoscopic vision, colored with
            brown irises and black pupils. Porgs favor cold environments.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Kaadu</name>
        <size>L</size>
        <type>Beast</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>10 (Natural Armor)</ac>
        <hp>13 (2d10+2)</hp>
        <speed>40 ft., swim 30 ft.</speed>
        <str>14</str>
        <dex>10</dex>
        <con>13</con>
        <int>2</int>
        <wis>10</wis>
        <cha>5</cha>
        <passive>10</passive>
        <languages>–</languages>
        <cr>1/8</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Sure-Footed</name>
            <text>The kaadu has advantage on Strength and Dexterity saving throws made against effects that would knock
                it prone.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Hooves</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 4 (1d4+2) kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <environment>Forest, Grassland, Swamp</environment>
        <description>Kaadu are creatures native and indigenous to the planet Naboo. Kaadu in the wild traveled in herds
            numbering in the millions. They are amphibious, being able to stay underwater for up to two hours. Kaadu
            feel most at home building their nests in muddy swamps and grassy plains, where the females lay between 100
            and 250 eggs at a time.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Security Sergeant (SW5e)</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Humanoid (any)</type>
        <alignment>lawful evil</alignment>
        <ac>10 (Combat Suit)</ac>
        <hp>22 (5d8)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>10</str>
        <dex>8</dex>
        <con>10</con>
        <int>12</int>
        <wis>11</wis>
        <cha>13</cha>
        <passive>13</passive>
        <languages>Galactic Basic , High Galactic</languages>
        <cr>1/4</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Brave</name>
            <text>The Security Sergeant has advantage on saving throws against being frightened.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>Dawn of Defiance: The Traitor’s Gambit</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Blaster Piistol</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +2 to hit, range 40/160 ft., one target. Hit: 2 (1d6-1) energy damage. Reload
                12.
            </text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Stunbaton</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 3 (1d6) subdual (nonlethal) damage.
            </text>
        </action>
        <reaction>
            <name>Leadership (Recharges after a Short or Long Rest)</name>
            <text>The sergeant can utter a special command or warning whenever a nonhostile creature that it can see
                within 30 feet of it makes an attack roll or a saving throw. The creature can add a d4 to its roll
                provided it can hear and understand the sergeant. A creature can benefit from only one Leadership die at
                a time. This effect ends if the sergeant is incapacitated.
            </text>
        </reaction>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Imperial Gunner</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Humanoid</type>
        <alignment>lawful neutral</alignment>
        <ac>12 (Heavy Combat Suit)</ac>
        <hp>33 (6d8+6)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>10</str>
        <dex>14</dex>
        <con>12</con>
        <int>11</int>
        <wis>9</wis>
        <cha>8</cha>
        <passive>12</passive>
        <languages>Galactic Basic</languages>
        <cr>1/4</cr>
        <action>
            <name>Light Repeater Burst</name>
            <text>The Imperial gunner sprays a 10-foot-cube area within 80 ft. with shots. A creature in the area takes
                the weapon&#39;s 1d8+2 energy damage, or half damage on a successful DC 13 Dexterity saving throw. The
                gunner can perform this action 3 times before reloading.
            </text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Stock Strike</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, reach 5ft., one target. Hit: 2 (1d4) kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Monkey-Lizard</name>
        <size>S</size>
        <type>Beast</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>12 (natural armor)</ac>
        <hp>3 (1d6)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>8</str>
        <dex>14</dex>
        <con>11</con>
        <int>5</int>
        <wis>12</wis>
        <cha>6</cha>
        <passive>11</passive>
        <languages>–</languages>
        <cr>0</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Pack Tactics</name>
            <text>The monkey-lizard has advantage on attack rolls against a creature if at least one of the
                monkey-lizard&#39;s allies is within 5 feet of the creature and the ally isn&#39;t incapacitated.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Bite</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +1 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 1 (1d4-1) kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>Kowakian monkey-lizards are a bipedal reptilian species native to a jungle-like Outer Rim planet
            called Kowak. Although have had no established culture, Kowakian monkeylizards were quite intelligent, and
            despite their silly, cruel nature, they are considered sentient by many sentientologists in the galaxy,
            although there was much debate over that designation. They are often kept as pets due to their mischievous
            nature.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Genetically Modified Felucian</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Humanoid</type>
        <alignment>neutral</alignment>
        <ac>11</ac>
        <hp>38 (4d8+20)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>18</str>
        <dex>13</dex>
        <con>20</con>
        <int>8</int>
        <wis>11</wis>
        <cha>8</cha>
        <skill>Stealth +3</skill>
        <passive>12</passive>
        <languages>None</languages>
        <cr>1/4</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Amphibious</name>
            <text>Felucians breathe air and water.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Mask of the Wild</name>
            <text>Felucians may attempt to hide even when they are only lightly obscured by foliage, heavy rain, falling
                snow, mist, and other natural phenomena.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Fused blade</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5ft., one target. Hit 8 (1d8+4) kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Mighty Swing</name>
            <text>The Felucian can spend their bonus action to add an additional damage dice to their melee attack. This
                dice is doubled on a critical hit.
            </text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Burst</name>
            <text>The Felucian causes the earth to burst from beneath their feet. Each creature within 5 ft., other than
                them, must succeed on a DC 10 Dexterity saving throw or take 1d6 kinetic damage.
            </text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Adolescent Reek</name>
        <size>L</size>
        <type>Beast</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>12 (natural armor)</ac>
        <hp>45 (6d10+12)</hp>
        <speed>50 ft.</speed>
        <str>21</str>
        <dex>8</dex>
        <con>15</con>
        <int>2</int>
        <wis>12</wis>
        <cha>6</cha>
        <passive>11</passive>
        <languages>–</languages>
        <cr>2</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Charge</name>
            <text>If the reek moves at least 20 feet straight toward a target and then hits it with a gore attack on the
                same turn, the target takes an extra 9 (2d8) kinetic damage. If the target is a Large or smaller, it
                must succeed on a DC 15 Strength saving throw or be knocked prone.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Gore</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +7 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 14 (2d8+5) kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>Reeks are large, muscular quadrupeds native to the planet Ylesia. Though naturally herbivores, a
            starved reek can become a ravenous meat-eater. They sport two large cheek horns that can be used for
            head-locking in combat with another Reek as a sign of dominance.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Medical Researcher</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Humanoid</type>
        <alignment>lawful evil</alignment>
        <ac>11</ac>
        <hp>13 (3d8)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>8</str>
        <dex>12</dex>
        <con>10</con>
        <int>15</int>
        <wis>12</wis>
        <cha>10</cha>
        <passive>13</passive>
        <languages>Galactic Basic</languages>
        <cr>1/8</cr>
        <action>
            <name>Blaster Pistol</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, range 40/160 ft., one target. Hit 4 (1d6+2) energy damage. Reload
                16.
            </text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Scout (SW5E)</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>humanoid</type>
        <alignment>any alignment</alignment>
        <ac>13 (combat suit)</ac>
        <hp>16 (3d8+3)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>11</str>
        <dex>14</dex>
        <con>12</con>
        <int>13</int>
        <wis>12</wis>
        <cha>11</cha>
        <skill>Nature +3</skill>
        <skill>Perception +3</skill>
        <skill>Stealth +4</skill>
        <skill>Survival +3</skill>
        <passive>13</passive>
        <languages>Galactic Basic and one other</languages>
        <cr>1/2</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Keen Hearing and Sight</name>
            <text>The scout has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on hearing or sight.</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Multiattack</name>
            <text>The scout makes two weapon attacks.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Blaster Rifle</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, ranged 100/400 ft., one target. Hit: 6 (1d8 + 2) energy damage.
            </text>
            <attack>|4|1d8+2</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Techblade</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 5 (1d6 + 2) kinetic damage.</text>
            <attack>|4|1d6+2</attack>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Opee Sea Killer</name>
        <size>G</size>
        <type>Beast</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>17 (natural armor)</ac>
        <hp>139 (9d20+45)</hp>
        <speed>20 ft., swim 60 ft.</speed>
        <str>19</str>
        <dex>10</dex>
        <con>20</con>
        <int>3</int>
        <wis>10</wis>
        <cha>6</cha>
        <skill>Stealth +6</skill>
        <senses>Darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
        <passive>10</passive>
        <languages>–</languages>
        <cr>5</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Kidnapper</name>
            <text>The sea killer may move at full speed while grappling a creature.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Tongue</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +7 to hit, range 30 ft., one target. Hit: The target creature is grappled
                (escape DC 15), and if it is a Large or smaller creature it must immediately make a DC 15 Strength
                saving throw, or be pulled up to 30 feet straight toward the sea killer. While a creature is grappled by
                the tongue, the sea killer can&#39;t use its tongue attack on another creature.
            </text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Bite</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +7 to hit, reach 5ft., one target. Hit: 30 (4d12+4) kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <environment>Underwater</environment>
        <description>The opee sea killer, sometimes referred to as simply an opee, is a large meat-eating crustaceous
            sea creature of approximately 60 feet in length. A hybrid of crustacean and fish, the opee sea killer is
            indigenous to the watery planet core of Naboo.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Adult Dewback</name>
        <size>L</size>
        <type>Beast</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>12 (natural armor)</ac>
        <hp>42 (5d10+15)</hp>
        <speed>40 ft., swim 30 ft.</speed>
        <str>20</str>
        <dex>10</dex>
        <con>16</con>
        <int>2</int>
        <wis>13</wis>
        <cha>7</cha>
        <skill>Perception +3</skill>
        <passive>13</passive>
        <languages>–</languages>
        <cr>1</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Keen Smell</name>
            <text>The dewback has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on smell.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Multiattack</name>
            <text>The dewback makes two attacks: one with its bite and one with its claws.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Bite</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 9 (1d8+5) kinetic damage.</text>
            <attack>|7|1d8+5</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Claw</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 12 (2d6+5) kinetic damage.</text>
            <attack>|7|2d6+5</attack>
        </action>
        <environment>Desert</environment>
        <description>Dewbacks are large, four-legged, omnivorous, cold-blooded reptiles native to the Dune Sea of
            Tatooine. As such, they are well-adapted to the harsh desert climate. This and the fact that they could be
            easily domesticated made them commonly employed as beasts of burden by both the inhabitants of the desert
            planet and the off-worlders wandering its dunes. Due to their numerous useful traits and versatility, they
            are quite possibly the most respected of all the creatures native to Tatooine.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Auto-Turret</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Construct</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>14 (armor plating)</ac>
        <hp>19 (3d8+6)</hp>
        <speed>0 ft.</speed>
        <str>12</str>
        <dex>2</dex>
        <con>15</con>
        <int>14</int>
        <wis>11</wis>
        <cha>4</cha>
        <skill>Perception +2</skill>
        <vulnerable>Ion</vulnerable>
        <resist>Necrotic, Poison, Psychic</resist>
        <conditionImmune>poison, disease</conditionImmune>
        <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
        <passive>12</passive>
        <cr>1/2</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Circuitry</name>
            <text>The construct has disadvantage on saving throws against effects that would deal ion or lightning
                damage.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Targeting Systems</name>
            <text>The turret uses its Intelligence modifier for attack, damage, and intitiative rolls.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Multiattack</name>
            <text>The turret makes two repeating blaster attacks.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Repeating Blaster</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, range 40/160 ft., one target. Hit 5 (1d6+2) energy damage.</text>
            <attack>|4|1d6+2</attack>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>A turret is a mount for a weapon that enabled it to turn and pivot, allowing it to fire in many
            different directions. They are mounted on many vehicles, starfighters, and starships. Weapons mounted on
            turrets included laser cannons and other types of projectile cannons.

            Other turrets are mounted on the ground, and can be both manned and un-manned.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Imperial Prison Guard</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Humanoid</type>
        <alignment>lawful neutral</alignment>
        <ac>12 (Heavy Combat Suit)</ac>
        <hp>18 (4d8)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>12</str>
        <dex>11</dex>
        <con>11</con>
        <int>10</int>
        <wis>10</wis>
        <cha>10</cha>
        <passive>12</passive>
        <languages>Galactic Basic</languages>
        <cr>1/8</cr>
        <action>
            <name>Blaster Rifle</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +2 to hit, range 100/400 ft., one target. Hit 4 (1d8) energy damage. Reload
                12.
            </text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Suppress</name>
            <text>The guard sprays a 10-footcube area within normal range of its rifle with shots. A creature in the
                area takes the weapon&#39;s normal damage, or half damage on a successful DC 10 Dexterity saving throw.
                This action consumes 6 ammunition.
            </text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Stock Strike</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, reach 5ft., one target. Hit: 3 (1d4+1) kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Frag Grenade</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: DC 12 Dexterity save, range 35 ft., 10 ft. radius. Hit: 7 (2d6) kinetic damage,
                half on save.
            </text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>AT-ST</name>
        <size>H</size>
        <type>Construct</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>17 (armor plating)</ac>
        <hp>168 (16d12+64)</hp>
        <speed>40 ft.</speed>
        <str>23</str>
        <dex>16</dex>
        <con>19</con>
        <int>10</int>
        <wis>14</wis>
        <cha>7</cha>
        <save>Strength +10</save>
        <save>Constitution +8</save>
        <vulnerable>Ion</vulnerable>
        <resist>Psychic</resist>
        <immune>Poison, Necrotic</immune>
        <conditionImmune>Poisoned, Frightened, Petrified, Restrained, Incapacitated, Stunned, Prone, Blinded, Charmed,
            disease
        </conditionImmune>
        <senses>–</senses>
        <passive>0</passive>
        <languages>–</languages>
        <cr>11</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Circuitry</name>
            <text>The construct has disadvantage on saving throws against effects that would deal ion or lightning
                damage.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Piloted</name>
            <text>The construct requires an active pilot to take any actions, and if the pilot is subjected to any
                conditions that the construct is not immune to, the construct is also subjected to those conditions. The
                pilot may take their own action or one of the actions granted by the construct.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Towering</name>
            <text>Creatures of Medium size or smaller can stand in the AT-ST&#39;s space.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Vulnerable Interior</name>
            <text>The AT-ST&#39;s interior is vulnerable to damage done by grenades, mines and charges, unless it is
                immune to that damage. It also automatically fails all Dexterity saving throws from such effects that
                occur in its interior.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Multiattack</name>
            <text>The AT-ST can use its Frightful Presence. It then makes two attacks with its medium repeating blasters
                or takes the Stomp action.
            </text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Medium Repeating Blasters</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +7 to hit, range 120/240 ft., one target. Hit: 25 (4d10+3) energy damage.</text>
            <attack>|5|4d10+3</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Stomp</name>
            <text>All creatures standing within the AT-ST&#39;s space or within 5 feet of it must make a DC 18 Dexterity
                saving throw, taking 39 (6d12) kinetic damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful
                one.
            </text>
            <attack>|5|2d6+3</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Frightful Presence</name>
            <text>Each creature of the AT-ST&#39;s choice that is within 80 feet of the AT-ST and aware of it must
                succeed on a DC 15 Wisdom saving throw or become frightened for 1 minute. A creature can repeat the
                saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. If a creature&#39;s
                saving throw is successful or the effect ends for it, the creature is immune to the AT-ST&#39;s
                Frightful Presence for the next 24 hours.
            </text>
            <attack>||4d6</attack>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Mynock</name>
        <size>S</size>
        <type>Beast</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>14 (natural armor)</ac>
        <hp>6 (1d12)</hp>
        <speed>5 ft., fly 40 ft.</speed>
        <str>4</str>
        <dex>16</dex>
        <con>11</con>
        <int>2</int>
        <wis>8</wis>
        <cha>6</cha>
        <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
        <passive>9</passive>
        <languages>–</languages>
        <cr>1/8</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Atmosphere Agnostic</name>
            <text>The mynock can survive in any type of atmosphere or vacuum.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Battery Drainer</name>
            <text>If the mynock attaches itself to a piece of equipment that needs energy to function, that piece will
                stop working until the Mynock is removed.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Pack Tactics</name>
            <text>The mynock has advantage on an attack roll against a creature if at least one ally of the mynock is
                within 5 feet of the creature and the ally isn&#39;t incapacitated.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Energy Drain</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one creature. Hit: 5 (1d4 + 3) kinetic damage, and the
                mynock attaches to the target. If attached to a droid or construct, at the start of each of the mynock&#39;s
                turns, the target loses 5 (1d4 + 3) hit points due to energy being drained. The mynock can detach itself
                by spending 5 feet of its Movement. It does so after it drains 10 Hit Points of energy from the target
                or the target dies. A creature, including the target, can use its action to detach the Mynock.
            </text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>Mynocks are a species of silicon-based bat-like parasites that chew on the power cables and energy
            conductors of starships, and can drain a ship&#39;s entire power supply. They reproduce by splitting in two
            and growing new creatures from each half. Mynocks are capable of surviving in the atmospheres of planets and
            the vacuum of space, though only a few varieties lived on planets. They are also known to inhabit asteroid
            fields and the gullets of exogorths, where they share in its meals.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>B1 Battle Droid</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Droid</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>14 (armor plating)</ac>
        <hp>7 (2d8-2)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>9</str>
        <dex>14</dex>
        <con>9</con>
        <int>13</int>
        <wis>10</wis>
        <cha>7</cha>
        <vulnerable>Ion</vulnerable>
        <resist>Necrotic, Poison, Psychic</resist>
        <conditionImmune>poison, disease</conditionImmune>
        <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
        <passive>10</passive>
        <languages>Binary, Galactic Basic</languages>
        <cr>1/8</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Battle Droid Swarm</name>
            <text>When an ally of the battle droid hits a hostile creature that it can see with a weapon attack, the
                battle droid can use its reaction to make one weapon attack against that creature.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Circuitry</name>
            <text>The droid has disadvantage on saving throws against effects that would deal ion or lightning damage.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Blaster Rifle</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, range 100/400 ft., one target. Hit: 6 (1d8+2) energy damage.</text>
            <attack>|4|1d8+2</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Stock Strike</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +1 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 1 (1d4-1) kinetic damage.</text>
            <attack>|1|1d4-1</attack>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>B1 battle droids, also referred to as standard battle droids, are the most widely-used battle
            droids manufactured by Baktoid Combat Automata and Baktoid Armor Workshop. The B1 battle droid sees
            extensive service as the mainlines soldiers due to their cheap, mass produced nature.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Swamp Wampa</name>
        <size>L</size>
        <type>Beast</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>13 (natural armor)</ac>
        <hp>76 (8d10+32)</hp>
        <speed>40 ft.</speed>
        <str>19</str>
        <dex>11</dex>
        <con>18</con>
        <int>5</int>
        <wis>10</wis>
        <cha>11</cha>
        <skill>Perception +2</skill>
        <skill>Stealth +2</skill>
        <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
        <passive>12</passive>
        <languages>–</languages>
        <cr>4</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Putrid Smell</name>
            <text>The wampa has disadvantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks. At the start of each wampas turns, each
                creature within 5 feet of it must succeed on a DC 14 Constitution saving throw or take 10 (4d4) poison
                damage.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Multiattack</name>
            <text>The wampa makes two attacks, one with its claw and one with its bite.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Claw</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 7 (2d6+4) kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Bite</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one creature. Hit: 7 (1d10+4) kinetic damage. The target
                is grappled (escape DC 14). Until this grapple ends, the target is restrained, and the wampa can&#39;t
                bite another target.
            </text>
        </action>
        <environment>Swamp</environment>
        <description>Wampas are semi-sentient predators with humanoid proportions that stand up to 12 feet tall. While
            they all share characteristics in common, there are three variations of wampa that are distinct based on
            their native planet.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>RX-13, Aka &#34;Crash&#34;</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Droid</type>
        <alignment>chaotic good</alignment>
        <ac>12 (Combat Armor)</ac>
        <hp>16 (3d8+3)</hp>
        <speed>25 ft.</speed>
        <str>10</str>
        <dex>14</dex>
        <con>12</con>
        <int>18</int>
        <wis>14</wis>
        <cha>8</cha>
        <save>Constitution +3</save>
        <save>Intelligence +5</save>
        <save>Constitution +3</save>
        <save>Intelligence +5</save>
        <skill>Investigation +6</skill>
        <skill>Acrobatics +6</skill>
        <skill>Medicine +4</skill>
        <skill>Nature +6</skill>
        <skill>Acrobatics +6</skill>
        <skill>Perception +4</skill>
        <skill>Acrobatics +6</skill>
        <skill>Acrobatics +6</skill>
        <skill>Acrobatics +0</skill>
        <resist>Necrotic, psychic</resist>
        <conditionImmune>Poison, disease</conditionImmune>
        <senses>Darkvision 30 ft.</senses>
        <passive>14</passive>
        <languages>Binary, Galactic Basic (Understand), Huttese (Understand)</languages>
        <cr>2</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Rapid Reconstruction</name>
            <text>As a bonus action, Crash can choose to spend one of his hit dice to recover hit points.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Potent Aptitude</name>
            <text>Crash may use a bonus action on your turn to choose one creature other than himself within 60 feet of
                him who can hear him. That creature gains one Potent Aptitude die, a d6. Once within the next 10
                minutes, the creature can roll the die and add the number rolled to one ability check, attack roll, or
                saving throw it makes. The creature can wait until after it rolls The D20 before deciding to use the
                Potent Aptitude die, but must decide before the DM says whether the roll succeeds or fails. Once the
                Potent Aptitude die is rolled, it is lost. A creature can have only one Potent Aptitude die at a time.
                Crash can use this feature a number of times equal to his Intelligence modifier. He regains any expended
                uses when he finishes a long rest.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Infuse Item</name>
            <text>At the end of a long rest, Crash can touch one unenhanced object that is a suit of armor or a simple
                or martial weapon. Until the end of his next long rest or until he dies, the object becomes an enhanced
                item, granting a +1 bonus to AC if it’s armor or a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls if it’s a weapon.
                Once he&#39;s used this feature, he can’t use it again until he finishes a long rest
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Tool Understanding</name>
            <text>Crash has advantage on any ability check he makes that uses tinker&#39;s tools or astrotech tools.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Alarm Protocol</name>
            <text>Crash gains a +5 bonus to initiative and cannot be surprised while conscious.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Sensor Augmentation</name>
            <text>Crash has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) and Intelligence (Investigation) checks made to detect the
                presence of secret doors. He has advantage on saving throws made to avoid or resist traps. He has has
                resistance to the damage dealt by traps. He can search for traps while traveling at a normal pace,
                instead of only at a slow pace.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Techcasting (6/Rest)</name>
            <text>Crash is a 3rd-level techcaster. His techcasting ability is Intelligence (power save DC 14, +6 to hit
                with power attacks).
                At-will: Electroshock, Encrypted Message, Light, Mending
                1st level: Detect Enhancement, Energy Shield, Repair Droid
                2nd level: Detect Traps, Smuggle
            </text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Blaster carbine</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, range 60/240 ft., one target. Hit 5 (1d6+2) energy damage. Reload
                16.
            </text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Vibrodagger</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5ft., one target. Hit: 4 (1d4+2) kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Orbalisk</name>
        <size>T</size>
        <type>Beast</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>14 (natural armor)</ac>
        <hp>15 (6d4)</hp>
        <speed>5 ft.</speed>
        <str>18</str>
        <dex>8</dex>
        <con>18</con>
        <int>1</int>
        <wis>4</wis>
        <cha>3</cha>
        <vulnerable>Lightning</vulnerable>
        <immune>All except lightning</immune>
        <passive>7</passive>
        <cr>1</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Detect Dark Side</name>
            <text>The orbalisk can sense the presence and location of any dark side aligned creature within 300 feet.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Attach</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one creature. Hit: 7 (1d8 + 3) kinetic damage, and the
                orbalisk attaches to the target. Once attached to a target, every day that passes the orbalisk will
                reproduce through fragmentation, so their numbers will be multiplied by 2. As the orbalisk covers the
                host&#39;s body, the following effects will take place (percentages relative to HP):
                0-25%: Host&#39;s max HP is reduced by the number of orbalisk.
                25-50%: Host&#39;s max HP is reduced by the number of orbalisk. The host gains a +2 bonus to AC, and
                Wisdom is decreased by 1.
                50-70%: Host&#39;s max HP is reduced by the number of orbalisk. The host gains a +3 bonus to AC, Wisdom
                is decreased by 2, and max force points are reduced by one-third (rounded down).
                70-90%: Host&#39;s max HP is reduced by the number of orbalisk. The host gains a +4 bonus to AC, Wisdom
                is decreased by 3, and max force points are reduced by two-thirds (rounded up).
                90-99%: Host&#39;s max HP is reduced by the number of orbalisk. The host gains a +5 bonus to AC, Wisdom
                is decreased by 4, and max force points are reduced to 0.
                100%: Host dies.
            </text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>Orbalisks are parasitic creatures native to Dxun. They lay inactive in caves or other dark places,
            until they find a suitable host creature on whose skin they can attach themselves to in order to feed.
            Orbalisks, once attached to a host, rapidly multiply, eventually enveloping and suffocating their victim.
            However, the holocron of Freedon Nadd contains the knowledge to make armament to prevent the orbalisks from
            covering the face, hands, and feet of the host, allowing them to keep this armor hidden.

            Perhaps by nature or as a result of residing on Dxun (which was itself a great focus of dark side power),
            orbalisks are able to feed on the Force-sensitivity of dark side wielders. It is said that the orbalisk
            armor&#39;s durability was such that lightsabers have a hard time penetrating it, making a wearer
            effectively immune to lightsaber attacks. The only weaknesses to this armor are the exposed joints at the
            neck and wrists, but these gaps are so small a lightsaber can only barely slice through. However, orbalisk
            armor is unable to protect the wearer from electricity. Orbalisks cause the wearer to feel pain, fueling the
            wearers dark side power; if they are removed or killed, they release a highly potent toxin into the host&#39;s
            body.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Seer</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Force-wielder</type>
        <alignment>any light</alignment>
        <ac>12 (15 with battle precognition)</ac>
        <hp>27 (6d8)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>10</str>
        <dex>14</dex>
        <con>11</con>
        <int>11</int>
        <wis>18</wis>
        <cha>13</cha>
        <save>Wisdom +6</save>
        <passive>14</passive>
        <languages>Galactic Basic, two others</languages>
        <cr>3</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Skills</name>
            <text>Lore +3, medicine +6, persuasion +3</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Preserve Life</name>
            <text>As an action, the seer can channel the Force and evoke healing energy that can restore 30 hit points
                to any number of creatures within 30 feet of it, and divide those hit points among them. This feature
                can restore a creature to no more than half of its hit point maximum. This feature has no effect on
                droids or constructs.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Spellcasting (Forcecasting)</name>
            <text>The sage is a 6th-level forcecaster. Its forcecasting ability is Wisdom (power save DC 14, +6 to hit
                with force attacks) and it has 24 force points. The sage knows the following force powers:
                At-will: give life (light force), guidance (light force), spare the dying (universal force), turbulence
                (light force)
                1st-level: battle precognition (universal force), burst of speed (universal force), heal (light force),
                project (light force)
                2nd-level: force barrier (light force), force enlightenment (light force), stun (light force)
                3rd-level: knight speed (universal force), share life (light force)
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Shotosaber</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 5 (1d6+2) energy damage.</text>
            <attack>|4|1d6+2</attack>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Tusken Brute</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Humanoid</type>
        <alignment>chaotic dark</alignment>
        <ac>13 (heavy combat suit)</ac>
        <hp>68 (8d8+32)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>16</str>
        <dex>12</dex>
        <con>18</con>
        <int>10</int>
        <wis>13</wis>
        <cha>9</cha>
        <skill>Survival +3</skill>
        <passive>11</passive>
        <languages>Tusken</languages>
        <cr>2</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Agressive</name>
            <text>As a bonus action, the tusken can move up to its speed toward a hostile creature that it can see.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Multiattack</name>
            <text>The tusken makes two gaffi stick attacks.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Gaffi Stick</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5ft., one target. Hit 8 (1d10 + 3) Kinetic damage.</text>
            <attack>|5|1d10+3</attack>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>R2 Series Astromech Droid</name>
        <size>S</size>
        <type>Droid</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>12 (armor plating)</ac>
        <hp>7 (2d6)</hp>
        <speed>25 ft.</speed>
        <str>6</str>
        <dex>13</dex>
        <con>11</con>
        <int>17</int>
        <wis>12</wis>
        <cha>7</cha>
        <skill>Perception +3</skill>
        <vulnerable>Ion</vulnerable>
        <resist>Necrotic, Poison, Psychic</resist>
        <conditionImmune>poison, disease</conditionImmune>
        <senses>Darkvision 60 Ft.</senses>
        <passive>13</passive>
        <languages>Speaks binary, understands Galactic Basic</languages>
        <cr>1/8</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Skills</name>
            <text>Perception +3, Technology +5, Piloting +5</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Circuitry</name>
            <text>The droid has disadvantage on saving throws against effects that would deal ion or lightning damage.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Keen Hearing and Sight.</name>
            <text>The astromech droid has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on hearing or sight.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Shockprod</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 3 (1d4+1) lightning damage.</text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>The R2 series is one of the most popular models of astromechs. Created by a company called
            Industrial Automaton, the R2 unit&#39;s excellent design, high quality marketing, and lucky timing made this
            the standard by which other astromech droids are measured.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Dark Apprentice</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Force-wielder (any)</type>
        <alignment>any dark</alignment>
        <ac>13 (combat suit)</ac>
        <hp>33 (6d8+6)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>11</str>
        <dex>14</dex>
        <con>12</con>
        <int>10</int>
        <wis>13</wis>
        <cha>14</cha>
        <skill>Deception +4</skill>
        <skill>Persuasion +4</skill>
        <passive>11</passive>
        <languages>Galactic Basic and one other</languages>
        <cr>2</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Skills</name>
            <text>Deception +4, Persuasion +4, Lore +2</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Devotion</name>
            <text>The apprentice has advantage on saving throws against being charmed or frightened.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Spellcasting (Forcecasting)</name>
            <text>The apprentice is a 4th-level forcecaster. Its forcecasting ability is Wisdom (power save DC 11, +3 to
                hit with force attacks) and it has 12 force points. The apprentice knows the following force powers:
                At-will: denounce (dark force), lightning charge (dark force), saber reflect (universal force), saber
                ward (universal force)
                1st-level: curse (dark force), sap vitality (dark force)
                2nd-level: drain vitality (dark force), force camouflage (universal force)
            </text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Multiattack</name>
            <text>The apprentice makes two melee weapon attacks.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Doublesaber</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 6 (1d8+2) energy damage.</text>
            <attack>|4|1d8+2</attack>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Gladiator (SW5e)</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>humanoid</type>
        <alignment>any alignment</alignment>
        <ac>16 (combat suit, heavy shield)</ac>
        <hp>112 (15d8+45)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>18</str>
        <dex>15</dex>
        <con>16</con>
        <int>10</int>
        <wis>12</wis>
        <cha>15</cha>
        <save>Strength +7</save>
        <save>Dexterity +5</save>
        <save>Constitution +6</save>
        <skill>Athletics +10</skill>
        <skill>Intimidation +5</skill>
        <passive>11</passive>
        <languages>Galactic Basic, one other</languages>
        <cr>5</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Brave</name>
            <text>The gladiator has advantage on saving throws against being frightened.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Brute</name>
            <text>A melee weapon deals one extra die of its damage when the gladiator hits with it (included in the
                attack).
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>Star Wars 5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Multiattack</name>
            <text>The gladiator makes two vibroblade attacks and one shield bash.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Vibroblade</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +7 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 13 (2d8+4) kinetic damage.</text>
            <attack>|7|2d8+4</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Shield Bash</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +7 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 9 (2d4+4) kinetic damage. If the target
                is a Medium or smaller creature, it must succeed on a DC 15 Strength saving throw or be knocked prone.
            </text>
            <attack>|7|2d4+4</attack>
        </action>
        <reaction>
            <name>Parry</name>
            <text>The gladiator adds 3 to its AC against one melee attack that would hit it. To do so, the gladiator
                must see the attacker and be wielding a melee weapon.
            </text>
        </reaction>
        <environment>Urban</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Adult Rancor</name>
        <size>H</size>
        <type>Beast</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>15 (natural armor)</ac>
        <hp>250 (20d12+120)</hp>
        <speed>40 ft.</speed>
        <str>23</str>
        <dex>11</dex>
        <con>23</con>
        <int>6</int>
        <wis>11</wis>
        <cha>6</cha>
        <save>Strength +10</save>
        <save>Dexterity +4</save>
        <save>Constitution +10</save>
        <save>Wisdom +4</save>
        <senses>darkvision 120 ft.</senses>
        <passive>14</passive>
        <languages>–</languages>
        <cr>12</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Siege Monster</name>
            <text>The rancor deals double damage to objects and structures.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Multiattack</name>
            <text>The rancor makes three attacks: two with its claws, and one with its bite.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Claw</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +10 to hit, reach 5ft., one target. Hit 15 (2d8+6) kinetic damage.</text>
            <attack>|10|2d8+6</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Bite</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +10 to hit, reach 5ft., one target. Hit 19 (2d12+6) kinetic damage. If the target
                is a creature, it is grappled (escape DC 15). Until this grapple ends, the target is restrained, and the
                rancor can&#39;t bite another target.
            </text>
            <attack>|10|2d12+6</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Throw Boulder</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +10 to hit, reach 60/240 ft., one target. Hit 25 (3d12 + 6) kinetic damage.
            </text>
            <attack>|10|3d12+6</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Swallow</name>
            <text>The rancor makes one bite attack against a Medium or smaller creature it is grappling. If the attack
                hits, the target takes the bite&#39;s damage, the target is swallowed, and the grapple ends. While
                swallowed, the creature is blinded and restrained, it has total cover against attacks and other effects
                outside the rancor, and it takes 21 (6d6) acid damage at the start of each of the rancor&#39;s turns. If
                the rancor takes 25 damage or more on a single turn from a creature inside it, the Rancor must succeed
                on a DC 20 Constitution saving throw at the end of that turn or regurgitate all swallowed creatures,
                which fall prone in a space within 10 feet of the Rancor. If the Rancor dies, a swallowed creature is no
                longer restrained by it and can escape from the corpse by using 10 feet of movement, exiting prone.
            </text>
            <attack>||6d6</attack>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>Rancors are large carnivorous reptomammals native to the planet of Dathomir. They are commonly kept
            as pets by affluent, less-than-reputable types.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Gamorrean Guard Thug</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>humanoid (gamorrean)</type>
        <alignment>any alignment</alignment>
        <ac>12 (heavy combat suit)</ac>
        <hp>11 (2d8+2)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>13</str>
        <dex>12</dex>
        <con>13</con>
        <int>9</int>
        <wis>9</wis>
        <cha>8</cha>
        <passive>10</passive>
        <languages>Galactic Basic and one other</languages>
        <cr>1/8</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Gamorrean Toughness</name>
            <text>You have advantage on Constitution saving throws.</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Slugthrower</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, range 30/120 ft., one target. Hit: 7 (2d4+1) kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Vibroaxe</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +2 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 5 (1d12+1) kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Burst</name>
            <text>The thug sprays a 10-foot-cube area within normal range of its slugthrower with shots. Each creature
                in the area must make a DC 11 Dexterity saving throw, taking normal weapon damage on a failed save.
            </text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>2-1B Medical Droid</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Droid</type>
        <alignment>neutral</alignment>
        <ac>10</ac>
        <hp>9 (2d8)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>8</str>
        <dex>11</dex>
        <con>10</con>
        <int>14</int>
        <wis>15</wis>
        <cha>9</cha>
        <vulnerable>Ion</vulnerable>
        <resist>Necrotic, Psychic</resist>
        <conditionImmune>Poison, Disease</conditionImmune>
        <passive>14</passive>
        <languages>Galactic Basic, Binary and two others</languages>
        <cr>1/8</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Circuitry</name>
            <text>The droid has disadvantage on saving throws against effects that would deal ion or lightning damage.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>Dawn of Defiance</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Scalpel</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +2 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit 1 (1d3-1) kinetic damage.</text>
            <attack>|2|1n3-1</attack>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>IG-86 Assassin Droid</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Droid</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>16 (armor plating)</ac>
        <hp>58 (9d8+18)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>14</str>
        <dex>17</dex>
        <con>15</con>
        <int>14</int>
        <wis>13</wis>
        <cha>7</cha>
        <skill>Perception +3</skill>
        <skill>Stealth +5</skill>
        <skill>Survival +3</skill>
        <vulnerable>Ion</vulnerable>
        <resist>Necrotic, Poison, Psychic</resist>
        <conditionImmune>poison, disease</conditionImmune>
        <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
        <passive>13</passive>
        <languages>Binary, Galactic Basic</languages>
        <cr>3</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Circuitry</name>
            <text>The droid has disadvantage on saving throws against effects that would deal ion or lightning damage.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Sneak Attack</name>
            <text>(1/Turn). The assassin droid deals an extra 14 (4d6) damage when it hits a target with a weapon attack
                and has advantage on the attack roll, or when the target is within 5 feet of an ally of the assassin
                droid that isn&#39;t incapacitated and the assassin doesn&#39;t have disadvantage on the roll.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5E Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Sniper Rifle</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, range 150/600 ft., one target. Hit: 9 (1d12+3) energy damage.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Stock Strike</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +2 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 4 (1d4+2) kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>The IG series is a series of droids manufactured by Holowan Laboratories. They are often used as
            both bodyguards and assassins.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Adult Reek</name>
        <size>H</size>
        <type>Beast</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>13 (natural armor)</ac>
        <hp>114 (12d12+36)</hp>
        <speed>50 ft.</speed>
        <str>23</str>
        <dex>8</dex>
        <con>17</con>
        <int>2</int>
        <wis>12</wis>
        <cha>6</cha>
        <passive>11</passive>
        <languages>–</languages>
        <cr>7</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Charge</name>
            <text>If the reek moves at least 20 feet straight toward a target and then hits it with a gore attack on the
                same turn, the target takes an extra 18 (4d8) kinetic damage. If the target is a Large or smaller, it
                must succeed on a DC 15 Strength saving throw or be knocked prone.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Gore</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +9 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 24 (4d8+6) kinetic damage.</text>
            <attack>|9|4d8+6</attack>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>Reeks are large, muscular quadrupeds native to the planet Ylesia. Though naturally herbivores, a
            starved reek can become a ravenous meat-eater. They sport two large cheek horns that can be used for
            head-locking in combat with another Reek as a sign of dominance.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Hidden Turret</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Construct</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>13 (armor plating)</ac>
        <hp>11 (2d8+2)</hp>
        <speed>0 ft.</speed>
        <str>1</str>
        <dex>2</dex>
        <con>13</con>
        <int>14</int>
        <wis>11</wis>
        <cha>4</cha>
        <skill>Perception +2</skill>
        <vulnerable>Ion</vulnerable>
        <resist>Necrotic, Poison, Psychic</resist>
        <conditionImmune>poison, disease</conditionImmune>
        <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
        <passive>12</passive>
        <cr>1/4</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Circuitry</name>
            <text>The construct has disadvantage on saving throws against effects that would deal ion or lightning
                damage.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>False Appearance</name>
            <text>While the turret is inactive, it is indistinguishable from an ordinary section of floor, wall, or
                ceiling.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Targeting Systems</name>
            <text>The turret uses its Intelligence modifier for attack, damage, and intitiative rolls.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Blaster Cannon</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, range 80/320 ft., one target. Hit 7 (1d10+2) energy damage.</text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>A turret is a mount for a weapon that enabled it to turn and pivot, allowing it to fire in many
            different directions. They are mounted on many vehicles, starfighters, and starships. Weapons mounted on
            turrets included laser cannons and other types of projectile cannons.

            Other turrets are mounted on the ground, and can be both manned and un-manned.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Thug (SW5E)</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>humanoid (any)</type>
        <alignment>any alignment</alignment>
        <ac>12 (heavy combat suit)</ac>
        <hp>11 (2d8+2)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>11</str>
        <dex>12</dex>
        <con>12</con>
        <int>10</int>
        <wis>10</wis>
        <cha>8</cha>
        <passive>10</passive>
        <languages>Galactic Basic and one other</languages>
        <cr>1/8</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Slugthrower</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, range 30/120 ft., one target. Hit: 7 (2d4+1) kinetic damage.</text>
            <attack>|3|2d4+1</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Vibromace</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +2 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 5 (1d6+1) kinetic damage.</text>
            <attack>|2|1d10+1</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Burst</name>
            <text>The thug sprays a 10-foot-cube area within normal range of its slugthrower with shots. Each creature
                in the area must make a DC 11 Dexterity saving throw, taking normal weapon damage on a failed save.
            </text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Flame Trooper</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Humanoid</type>
        <alignment>any alignment</alignment>
        <ac>16 (durasteel armor)</ac>
        <hp>45 (6d10 + 15)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>15</str>
        <dex>16</dex>
        <con>16</con>
        <int>9</int>
        <wis>10</wis>
        <cha>11</cha>
        <skill>Athletics +4</skill>
        <passive>10</passive>
        <languages>Galactic Basic, one other</languages>
        <cr>2</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Flamethrower</name>
            <text>Each creature in a 30-foot cone must make a DC 13 Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes 13 (3d8)
                fire damage on a failed save, or half as much on a successful one. The fire ignites any flammable
                objects in the area that aren&#39;t being worn or carried.
            </text>
            <attack>||3d8</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Blaster Pistol</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, range 40/160 ft., one target. Hit: 6 (1d6+3) energy damage.</text>
            <attack>|5|1d6+3</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Bash</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 4 (1d4+2) kinetic damage.</text>
            <attack>|4|1d4+2</attack>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Kargrek And Hagark</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Humanoid</type>
        <alignment>neutral</alignment>
        <ac>13</ac>
        <hp>57 (6d8+30)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>22</str>
        <dex>13</dex>
        <con>20</con>
        <int>8</int>
        <wis>11</wis>
        <cha>8</cha>
        <skill>Stealth +4</skill>
        <passive>13</passive>
        <languages>None</languages>
        <cr>1/2</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Amphibious</name>
            <text>Felucians breathe air and water.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Mask of the Wild</name>
            <text>Felucians may attempt to hide even when they are only lightly obscured by foliage, heavy rain, falling
                snow, mist, and other natural phenomena.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Fused blade</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +9 to hit, reach 5ft., one target. Hit 11 (1d10+6) kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Mighty Swing</name>
            <text>The Felucian can spend their bonus action to add an additional damage dice to their melee attack. This
                dice is doubled on a critical hit.
            </text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Burst</name>
            <text>The Felucian causes the earth to burst from beneath their feet. Each creature within 5 ft., other than
                them, must succeed on a DC 10 Dexterity saving throw or take 1d6 kinetic damage.
            </text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Warden Droid (SW5e)</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Droid</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>13 (Armor)</ac>
        <hp>27 (6d8)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>14</str>
        <dex>13</dex>
        <con>10</con>
        <int>10</int>
        <wis>11</wis>
        <cha>7</cha>
        <vulnerable>Ion, Lightning</vulnerable>
        <resist>Necrotic, Psychic</resist>
        <conditionImmune>poison, disease</conditionImmune>
        <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
        <passive>13</passive>
        <languages>Binary, Galactic Basic</languages>
        <cr>1/4</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Stun claws</name>
            <text>The warden droid may make a second claw attack as a bonus action.</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Stun Claws</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit 5 (1d6+2) subdual (non-lethal) damage.
            </text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Maya (Normal)</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>humanoid (any), SW5E monster manual</type>
        <alignment>chaotic good</alignment>
        <ac>14 (Combat Suit)</ac>
        <hp>5 (1d8+1)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>10</str>
        <dex>16</dex>
        <con>12</con>
        <int>14</int>
        <wis>10</wis>
        <cha>14</cha>
        <save>Dexterity +5</save>
        <save>Intelligence +4</save>
        <save>Dexterity +5</save>
        <save>Intelligence +4</save>
        <passive>12</passive>
        <languages>Galactic Basic , Huttese</languages>
        <cr>1/2</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Sneak Attack (1/Turn)</name>
            <text>The spy deals an extra 3 (1d6) damage when it hits a target with a weapon attack and has advantage on
                the attack roll, or when the target is within 5 ft. of an ally of the spy that isn&#39;t incapacitated
                and the spy doesn&#39;t have disadvantage on the attack roll.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Vibrodagger</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +2 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 2 (1d4) kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Blaster Pistol</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, range 40/160 ft., one target. Hit: 5 (1d6+3) energy damage. Reload
                12.
            </text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Dark Lord</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Force-wielder</type>
        <alignment>any dark</alignment>
        <ac>12 (15 with *battle precognition*)</ac>
        <hp>99 (18d8+18)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>10</str>
        <dex>14</dex>
        <con>12</con>
        <int>15</int>
        <wis>20</wis>
        <cha>16</cha>
        <save>Intelligence +6</save>
        <save>Wisdom +9</save>
        <save>Charisma +7</save>
        <resist>damage from force powers</resist>
        <passive>10</passive>
        <languages>Galactic Basic, one other</languages>
        <cr>12</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Skills</name>
            <text>Lore +6, Insight +13</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Force Resistance</name>
            <text>The dark lord has advantage on saving throws against force powers.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Spellcasting (Forcecasting)</name>
            <text>The dark lord is an 18st-level forcecaster. Its forcecasting ability is Wisdom (power save DC 17, +9
                to hit with force attacks) and it has 72 force points. The dark lord knows the following force powers:
                At-will: affect mind (universal force), denounce (dark force), force push/pull (universal force), mind
                trick (universal force), saber reflect (universal force), saber ward (universal force), shock (dark
                force)
                1st-level: battle precognition (universal force), force body (universal force), hex (dark force)
                2nd-level: battle meditation (universal force), darkness (dark force), phasewalk (universal force)
                3rd-level: force lightning (dark force), force suppression (universal force), sever force (universal
                force)
                4th-level: dominate beast (dark force), force immunity (universal force), shocking shield (dark force)
                5th-level: improved battle meditation (universal force), improved phasewalk (universal force),
                telekinesis (universal force)
                6th-level: force chain lightning (dark force), improved force immunity (universal force)
                7th-level: force lightning cone (dark force)
                8th-level: master force immunity (universal force)
                9th-level: force storm (dark force)
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Lightfoil</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 6 (1d8+2) energy damage.</text>
            <attack>|6|1d8+2</attack>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Detention Warden</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Humanoid</type>
        <alignment>lawful neutral</alignment>
        <ac>12 (Combat Suit)</ac>
        <hp>18 (4d8)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>11</str>
        <dex>13</dex>
        <con>11</con>
        <int>10</int>
        <wis>10</wis>
        <cha>10</cha>
        <passive>12</passive>
        <languages>Galactic Basic</languages>
        <cr>1/4</cr>
        <action>
            <name>Blaster Pistol</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, range 40/160 ft., one target. Hit 4 (1d6+1) energy damage. Reload
                12.
            </text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Stun Baton</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, reach 5ft., one target. Hit: 4 (1d6+1) subdual damage.</text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Lieutenant Aden</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Humanoid</type>
        <alignment>lawful evil</alignment>
        <ac>10 (Combat Suit)</ac>
        <hp>22 (5d8)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>10</str>
        <dex>8</dex>
        <con>10</con>
        <int>12</int>
        <wis>11</wis>
        <cha>13</cha>
        <passive>13</passive>
        <languages>Galactic Basic, High Galactic</languages>
        <cr>1/4</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Brave</name>
            <text>Lieutenant Aden has advantage on saving throws against being frightened.</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Blaster Pistol</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +2 to hit, range 40/160 ft., one target. Hit 2 (1d6-1) energy damage. Reload
                12.
            </text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Vibrodagger</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, reach 5ft., one target. Hit: 2 (1d4) kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <reaction>
            <name>Leadership (Recharges after a Short or Long Rest)</name>
            <text>Lieutenant Aden can utter a special command or warning whenever a nonhostile creature that it can see
                within 30 feet of it makes an attack roll or a saving throw. The creature can add a d4 to its roll
                provided it can hear and understand the Lieutenant. A creature can benefit from only one Leadership die
                at a time.
            </text>
        </reaction>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Adult Bantha</name>
        <size>H</size>
        <type>Beast</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>13 (natural armor)</ac>
        <hp>126 (11d12+55)</hp>
        <speed>40 ft.</speed>
        <str>24</str>
        <dex>9</dex>
        <con>21</con>
        <int>3</int>
        <wis>11</wis>
        <cha>6</cha>
        <passive>10</passive>
        <languages>–</languages>
        <cr>6</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Trampling Charge</name>
            <text>If the bantha moves at least 20 feet straight toward a creature and then hits it with a gore attack on
                the same turn, that target must succeed on a DC 18 Strength saving throw or be knocked prone. If the
                target is prone, the bantha can make one stomp attack against it as a bonus action.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Gore</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +10 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 25 (4d8+7) kinetic damage.</text>
            <attack>|10|4d8+7</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Stomp</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +10 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 29 (4d10+7) kinetic damage.</text>
            <attack>|10|4d10+7</attack>
        </action>
        <environment>Desert</environment>
        <description>Banthas are a species of large, hairy mammals with sharp,
            spiraling horns. They are native to the desert planet Tatooine, though they are bred on many worlds
            throughout the galaxy. They are social herd animals, and are often domesticated, and used prominently, by
            Tusken Raiders as mounts and companions.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>AT-AT</name>
        <size>G</size>
        <type>Construct</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>20 (armor plating)</ac>
        <hp>330 (20d20+120)</hp>
        <speed>40 ft.</speed>
        <str>27</str>
        <dex>10</dex>
        <con>23</con>
        <int>10</int>
        <wis>10</wis>
        <cha>7</cha>
        <save>Strength +14</save>
        <save>Constitution +12</save>
        <vulnerable>Ion</vulnerable>
        <resist>Psychic</resist>
        <immune>Poison, Necrotic</immune>
        <conditionImmune>Poisoned, Frightened, Petrified, Restrained, Incapacitated, Stunned, Prone, Blinded, Charmed,
            disease
        </conditionImmune>
        <senses>–</senses>
        <passive>0</passive>
        <languages>–</languages>
        <cr>19</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Circuitry</name>
            <text>The construct has disadvantage on saving throws against effects that would deal ion or lightning
                damage.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Heavy Durasteel Armor</name>
            <text>The outer layer of the AT-AT is covered in heavy armor, making it difficult for smaller arms to damage
                it. Unless the damage from a single attack or effect exceeds 30 points, the AT-AT takes no damage from
                that attack. If the AT-AT takes an amount of damage from a single attack or effect equal to or greater
                than its damage threshold, it takes damage as normal.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Piloted</name>
            <text>The construct requires an active pilot to take any actions, and if the pilot is subjected to any
                conditions that the construct is not immune to, the construct is also subjected to those conditions. The
                pilot may take their own action or one of the actions granted by the construct.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Towering</name>
            <text>Creatures of Large size or smaller can stand in the AT-AT&#39;s space.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Troop Transport</name>
            <text>The AT-AT can transport a maximum of 40 stormtroopers and five speeder bikes, which it can deploy
                using its Deploy Troops legendary action, or which can be fought by creatures inside of the AT-AT
                itself.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Vulnerable Interior</name>
            <text>The AT-AT&#39;s interior is vulnerable to damage done by grenades, mines and charges, unless it is
                immune to that damage. It also automatically fails all Dexterity saving throws from such effects that
                occur in its interior.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Multiattack</name>
            <text>The AT-AT can use its Frightful Presence. It then makes three attacks: one with its laser cannon
                volley and two with its medium repeating blasters.
            </text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Laser Cannon Volley</name>
            <text>The AT-AT chooses a point within 320 ft and lets loose a blast from each of its heavy laser cannons
                that explodes in a 15ft cube around that point. Each creature within the cube must succeed on a DC 18
                Dexterity saving throw, taking 54 (12d8) energy damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a
                successful one.
            </text>
            <attack>||12d8</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Medium Repeating Blasters</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +8 to hit, range 240/360 ft., one target. Hit: 22 (4d10) energy damage.</text>
            <attack>|8|4d10</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Stomp</name>
            <text>All creatures standing within the AT-AT&#39;s space or within 5ft of it must make a DC 20 Dexterity
                saving throw, taking 78 (12d12) kinetic damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful
                one.
            </text>
            <attack>||12d12</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Frightful Presence</name>
            <text>Each creature of the AT-AT&#39;s choice that is within 240 feet of the AT-AT and aware of it must
                succeed on a DC 16 Wisdom saving throw or become Frightened for 1 minute. A creature can repeat the
                saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. If a creature&#39;s
                saving throw is successful or the effect ends for it, the creature is immune to the AT-AT&#39;s
                Frightful Presence for the next 24 hours.
            </text>
        </action>
        <legendary>
            <name>Legendary Actions</name>
            <text>The AT-AT can take 3 legendary actions, choosing from the options below. Only one legendary action
                option can be used at a time and only at the end of another creature&#39;s turn. The AT-AT regains spent
                legendary actions at the start of their turn.
            </text>
        </legendary>
        <legendary>
            <name>Stomp</name>
            <text>The AT-AT makes a stomp attack.</text>
        </legendary>
        <legendary>
            <name>Repeating Blasters</name>
            <text>The AT-AT makes a single attack with its medium repeating blasters.</text>
        </legendary>
        <legendary>
            <name>Deploy Troops (Costs 2 Actions)</name>
            <text>The AT-AT mobilizes some of the soldiers traveling within it. It deploys 1d4+2 Troopers and 1 74-Z
                speeder bike. These troops appear in any unoccupied spaces within 10 ft. of the AT-AT.
            </text>
        </legendary>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>The All-Terrain Armored Transport (or AT-AT) is a behemoth of a war machine, standing at a height
            of 60 feet. Designed for the dual purpose of crushing and demoralizing enemy forces, and also serving as a
            transport for troops and light vehicles, the AT-AT is among the most astonishing vehicles ever constructed.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Maya (Wounded)</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>humanoid (any), SW5E monster manual</type>
        <alignment>chaotic good</alignment>
        <ac>14 (Combat Suit)</ac>
        <hp>2 (1d8)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>10</str>
        <dex>16</dex>
        <con>12</con>
        <int>14</int>
        <wis>10</wis>
        <cha>14</cha>
        <save>Dexterity +5</save>
        <save>Intelligence +4</save>
        <save>Dexterity +5</save>
        <save>Intelligence +4</save>
        <passive>12</passive>
        <languages>Galactic Basic , Huttese</languages>
        <cr>1/8</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Sneak Attack (1/Turn)</name>
            <text>The spy deals an extra 3 (1d6) damage when it hits a target with a weapon attack and has advantage on
                the attack roll, or when the target is within 5 ft. of an ally of the spy that isn&#39;t incapacitated
                and the spy doesn&#39;t have disadvantage on the attack roll.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Vibrodagger</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +2 to hit (disadvantage), reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 2 (1d4) kinetic damage.
            </text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Blaster Pistol</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +5 to hit (disadvantage), range 40/160 ft., one target. Hit: 5 (1d6+3) energy
                damage. Reload 12.
            </text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Twi&#39;lek Thug (SW5E)</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>humanoid (Twi’lek)</type>
        <alignment>lawful evil</alignment>
        <ac>12 (heavy combat suit)</ac>
        <hp>11 (2d8+2)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>11</str>
        <dex>13</dex>
        <con>12</con>
        <int>10</int>
        <wis>10</wis>
        <cha>10</cha>
        <skill>Performance +2</skill>
        <conditionImmune>Advantage on saving throws against poison and disease</conditionImmune>
        <senses>Darkvision</senses>
        <passive>10</passive>
        <languages>Galactic Basic and Twi’lek</languages>
        <cr>1/8</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>Dawn of Defiance: A Wretched Hive, /u/stuartcmackey</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Slugthrower</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, range 30/120 ft., one target. Hit: 7 (2d4+1) kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Vibromace</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +2 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 5 (1d6+1) kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Burst</name>
            <text>The thug sprays a 10-foot-cube area within normal range of its slugthrower with shots. Each creature
                in the area must make a DC 11 Dexterity saving throw, taking normal weapon damage on a failed save.
            </text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Adolescent Rancor</name>
        <size>L</size>
        <type>Beast</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>14 (natural armor)</ac>
        <hp>157 (15d10+75)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>20</str>
        <dex>11</dex>
        <con>21</con>
        <int>4</int>
        <wis>9</wis>
        <cha>6</cha>
        <senses>darkvision 120 ft.</senses>
        <passive>9</passive>
        <languages>-</languages>
        <cr>8</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Siege Monster</name>
            <text>The rancor deals double damage to objects and structures.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Multiattack</name>
            <text>The rancor makes three attacks: two with its claws, and one with its bite.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Claw</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +8 to hit, reach 5ft., one target. Hit 12 (2d6+5) kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Bite</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +8 to hit, reach 5ft., one target. Hit 16 (2d10+5) kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Throw Boulder</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +8 to hit, reach 60/240 ft., one target. Hit 21 (3d10 + 5) kinetic damage.
            </text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>Rancors are large carnivorous reptomammals native to the planet of Dathomir. They are commonly kept
            as pets by affluent, less-than-reputable types.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Imperial Informant (SW5E)</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>humanoid (any), (SW5E)</type>
        <alignment>any alignment</alignment>
        <ac>10</ac>
        <hp>9 (2d8)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>12</str>
        <dex>10</dex>
        <con>10</con>
        <int>11</int>
        <wis>13</wis>
        <cha>11</cha>
        <passive>13</passive>
        <languages>Galactic Basic and one other</languages>
        <cr>1/8</cr>
        <action>
            <name>Hold Out Blaster</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +2 to hit, range 30/120 ft., one target. Hit: 2 (1d4) energy damage. Reload 6.
            </text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Vibrodagger</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 3 (1d4+1) kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>Carries: comlink, personal items</description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Adolescent Varactyl</name>
        <size>L</size>
        <type>Beast</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>10</ac>
        <hp>13 (2d10+2)</hp>
        <speed>50 ft., climb 30 ft.</speed>
        <str>16</str>
        <dex>10</dex>
        <con>12</con>
        <int>2</int>
        <wis>11</wis>
        <cha>7</cha>
        <passive>10</passive>
        <languages>–</languages>
        <cr>1/4</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Trampling Charge</name>
            <text>If the varactyl moves at least 20 feet straight toward a creature and then hits it with a bite attack
                on the same turn, that target must succeed on a DC 14 Strength saving throw or be knocked prone. If the
                target is prone, the varactyl can make another attack with its bite against it as a bonus action.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Bite</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 8 (2d4+3) kinetic damage.</text>
            <attack>|5|2d4+3</attack>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>Varactyls are a species of majestic, giant reptavian herbivores native to the world of Utapau. They
            typically have blue and green feather manes and feather ridges along their back. They are incredibly loyal
            and obedient mounts, that had strong long strides to navigate the uneven and vertical surfaces of their
            homeworld.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Heavy Trooper</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Humanoid</type>
        <alignment>any alignment</alignment>
        <ac>17 (powered durasteel armor)</ac>
        <hp>42 (5d10 + 15)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>15</str>
        <dex>16</dex>
        <con>17</con>
        <int>9</int>
        <wis>10</wis>
        <cha>10</cha>
        <skill>Athletics +4</skill>
        <passive>10</passive>
        <languages>Galatic Basic, one other</languages>
        <cr>3</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Multiattack</name>
            <text>The trooper makes two attacks with its assault cannon or uses its assault cannon&#39;s burst.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Assault Cannon</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, range 80/320 ft., one target. Hit: 8 (1d10+3) energy damage.</text>
            <attack>|5|1d10+3</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Burst</name>
            <text>The trooper sprays a 10-foot-cube area within normal range with shots. Each creature in the area must
                make a DC 13 Dexterity saving throw, taking 8 (1d10+3) energy damage on a failed save, or half as much
                on a successful one.
            </text>
            <attack>||1d10+3</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Bash</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 4 (1d4+2) kinetic damage.</text>
            <attack>||1d4+2</attack>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Ysalamir</name>
        <size>S</size>
        <type>Beast</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>10 (natural armor)</ac>
        <hp>3 (1d6)</hp>
        <speed>15 ft., climb 30 ft.</speed>
        <str>2</str>
        <dex>11</dex>
        <con>10</con>
        <int>1</int>
        <wis>8</wis>
        <cha>3</cha>
        <senses>darkvision 30 ft.</senses>
        <passive>9</passive>
        <languages>–</languages>
        <cr>0</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Force Nulify</name>
            <text>The Ysalamir create a 10ft radius bubble that neutralizes the presence of the force. The bubble
                doubles in radius for each Ysalamir standing inside it.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Bite</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +2 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 1 kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>Ysalamiri are furry, lizard-like tree-dwellers about 2 feet long native to the planet Myrkr, most
            known for their ability to repel the Force by creating a Force-neutral bubble. This ability evolved in
            response to predation by the Force-sensitive vornskrs. Many ysalamiri grouped together can expand their
            Force-neutral bubble by varying distances – sometimes by miles.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Swarm Of Porgs</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Swarm of Tiny Beasts</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>12</ac>
        <hp>24 (7d8-7)</hp>
        <speed>10 ft. , Fly 50 ft.</speed>
        <str>6</str>
        <dex>14</dex>
        <con>8</con>
        <int>3</int>
        <wis>12</wis>
        <cha>6</cha>
        <skill>Perception +5</skill>
        <resist>Energy, Kinetic</resist>
        <conditionImmune>Charmed, Frightened, Paralyzed, Petrified, Prone, Restrained, Stunned</conditionImmune>
        <passive>15</passive>
        <languages>–</languages>
        <cr>1/4</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Keen Smell</name>
            <text>The porg has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on smell.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Swarm</name>
            <text>The swarm can occupy another creature&#39;s space and vice versa, and the swarm can move through any
                opening large enough for a Tiny porg. The swarm can&#39;t regain hit points or gain temporary hit
                points.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Bite</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target in the swarm&#39;s space. Hit: 7 (2d6) kinetic
                damage, or 3 (1d6) kinetic damage if the swarm has half of its hit points or fewer.
            </text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>Porgs are a species of non-sentient birds. They are stocky in nature, with two short wings, flat,
            beak-less faces, and two webbed feet. Porgs are sexually dimorphic; males are slightly larger than females,
            and males also have orange plumage around the eyes. Porgs of both sexes are covered in dense feathers, with
            white coloration on the body and face, and gray to brown on the wings and back. They are much lighter than
            they looked, thanks to a thick outer layer of waterproof feathers with a fluffy underlayer for warmth. They
            can fly short distances but not far enough to leave their native island. They can also run quite swiftly on
            the ground and are good at maneuvering into small spaces. The birds have stereoscopic vision, colored with
            brown irises and black pupils. Porgs favor cold environments.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Rakghoul</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Humanoid</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>12 (natural armor)</ac>
        <hp>27 (5d8+5)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>14</str>
        <dex>15</dex>
        <con>12</con>
        <int>4</int>
        <wis>10</wis>
        <cha>6</cha>
        <skill>Perception +2</skill>
        <passive>12</passive>
        <languages>–</languages>
        <cr>1</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Rakghoul Plague</name>
            <text>Creatures that come in contact with the rakghoul may become afflicted with rakghoul plague, a virulent
                disease that transforms the creature into a rakghoul over the next 24 (7d6) hours. The plague is only
                effective against humanoids.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Savage Leap</name>
            <text>If the rakghoul moves at least 20 feet toward a creature and then hits it with a claw attack on the
                same turn, the target must succeed on a DC 13 Strength saving throw or be knocked prone. If the target
                is prone, the rakghoul can make one bite attack against it as a bonus action.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Bite</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5ft., one target. Hit 9 (2d6+2) Kinetic damage. If the target is
                a humanoid creature, it must succeed on a DC 12 Constitution saving throw or become infected with the
                Rakghoul Plague.
            </text>
            <attack>|4|2d6+2</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Claws</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 7 (2d4+2) Kinetic damage. If the target
                is a humanoid creature, it must succeed on a DC 12 Constitution saving throw or become infected with the
                Rakghoul Plague.
            </text>
            <attack>|4|2d4+2</attack>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>Rakghouls are a living plague–the manifestation of a highly communicable disease capable of swiftly
            transforming its victims into twisted, degenerate monsters with predatory instincts. The rakghoul virus can
            infect hundreds of known species and is most often delivered through a rakghoul’s bite; a person attacked by
            a rakghoul and “lucky” enough to survive typically becomes a rakghoul him- or herself. Some victims resist
            the virus for days, succumbing to rakghoul instincts while retaining their original bodies.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Juvenile Rancor</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Beast</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>13 (natural armor)</ac>
        <hp>75 (10d8+30)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>18</str>
        <dex>11</dex>
        <con>16</con>
        <int>4</int>
        <wis>9</wis>
        <cha>6</cha>
        <senses>darkvision 120 ft.</senses>
        <passive>9</passive>
        <languages>–</languages>
        <cr>2</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Multiattack</name>
            <text>The rancor makes two attacks: one with its claws, and one with its bite.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Claw</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +8 to hit, reach 5ft., one target. Hit 7 (1d6+4) kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Bite</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +8 to hit, reach 5ft., one target. Hit 9 (1d10+4) kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>Rancors are large carnivorous reptomammals native to the planet of Dathomir. They are commonly kept
            as pets by affluent, less-than-reputable types.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>B2-HA Series Super Battle Droid</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Droid</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>17 (armor plating)</ac>
        <hp>84 (14d8+28)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>15</str>
        <dex>16</dex>
        <con>14</con>
        <int>14</int>
        <wis>15</wis>
        <cha>11</cha>
        <skill>Perception +4</skill>
        <vulnerable>Ion</vulnerable>
        <resist>Necrotic, Poison, Psychic</resist>
        <conditionImmune>poison, disease</conditionImmune>
        <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
        <passive>14</passive>
        <languages>Binary, Galactic Basic</languages>
        <cr>4</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Circuitry</name>
            <text>The droid has disadvantage on saving throws against effects that would deal ion or lightning damage.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Multiattack</name>
            <text>The super battle droid makes two weapon attacks with its strike or wrist blaster.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Strike</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 3 (1d4+2) kinetic damage.</text>
            <attack>|4|1d6+3</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Wrist Blaster</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, range 60/240 ft., one target. Hit: 6 (1d6+3) energy damage.</text>
            <attack>|5|1d6+3</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Wrist Blaster Volley</name>
            <text>(Recharge 5-6). The super battle droid sprays a 10-foot-cube area within normal range with shots. Each
                creature in the area must make a DC 13 Dexterity saving throw, taking normal weapon damage on a failed
                save.
            </text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Rocket Launcher (1/Day)</name>
            <text>Each creature in a 20-foot- radius sphere centered on a point that you can see within 150 feet must
                make a Dexterity saving throw. A target takes 8d6 fire damage on a failed save, or half as much damage
                on a successful one.
            </text>
            <attack>||8d6</attack>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>The B2 super battle droid is an upgraded version of the B1 battle droid, with superior armament and
            armor. It features dual integrated wrist blasters.

            The B2-HA model was equipped with an integrated rocket launcher.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Viper Probe Droid</name>
        <size>L</size>
        <type>Droid</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>14 (armor plating)</ac>
        <hp>37 (5d10+10)</hp>
        <speed>5 ft., fly 40 ft.</speed>
        <str>11</str>
        <dex>15</dex>
        <con>12</con>
        <int>17</int>
        <wis>14</wis>
        <cha>7</cha>
        <skill>Investigation +5</skill>
        <skill>Perception +4</skill>
        <vulnerable>Ion</vulnerable>
        <immune>necrotic, poison, disease</immune>
        <conditionImmune>poison, disease</conditionImmune>
        <senses>Darkvision 120 Ft.</senses>
        <passive>14</passive>
        <languages>–</languages>
        <cr>1</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Circuitry</name>
            <text>The droid has disadvantage on saving throws against effects that would deal ion or lightning damage.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Keen Hearing and Sight</name>
            <text>The probe droid has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on hearing or sight.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Blaster Cannon</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, range 60/240 ft., one target. Hit: 7 (1d10+2) energy damage.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Self-Destruct</name>
            <text>When the probe droid is reduced to half of its hit point maximum, it attempts to self-destruct. Each
                creature within 20 feet of it must make a DC 13 Dexterity saving throw, taking 6d6 fire damage on a
                failed save, or half as much on a successful one.
            </text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>The Viper Probe Droid is a deep-space exploration and reconnaissance probe droid produced by Arakyd
            Industries. The probe droid is equipped with a blaster cannon and a selfdestruct mechanism.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Imperial Soldier</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Humanoid</type>
        <alignment>lawful neutral</alignment>
        <ac>12 (Heavy Combat Suit)</ac>
        <hp>9 (2d8)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>12</str>
        <dex>11</dex>
        <con>11</con>
        <int>10</int>
        <wis>10</wis>
        <cha>10</cha>
        <passive>12</passive>
        <languages>Galactic Basic</languages>
        <cr>1/8</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>Other</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Blaster Carbine</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +2 to hit, range 60/240 ft., one target. Hit 3 (1d6) energy damage. Reload 16.
            </text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Suppress</name>
            <text>The security officer sprays a 10-footcube area within normal range of its carbine with shots. A
                creature in the area takes the weapon&#39;s normal damage, or half damage on a successful DC 10
                Dexterity saving throw. This action consumes 8 ammunition.
            </text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Stock Strike</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, reach 5ft., one target. Hit: 3 (1d4+1) kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Security Officer</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Humanoid</type>
        <alignment>lawful neutral</alignment>
        <ac>12 (Heavy Combat Suit)</ac>
        <hp>9 (2d8)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>12</str>
        <dex>11</dex>
        <con>11</con>
        <int>10</int>
        <wis>10</wis>
        <cha>10</cha>
        <passive>12</passive>
        <languages>Galactic Basic</languages>
        <cr>1/8</cr>
        <action>
            <name>Blaster Carbine</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack. +2 to hit, range 60/240 ft., one target. Hit 3 (1d6) energy damage. Reload 16.
            </text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Suppress</name>
            <text>The security officer sprays a 10-ft-cube area within normal range of its carbine with shots. A
                creature in the area takes the weapon’s normal damage, or half damage on a successful DC 10 Dexterity
                saving throw. This action consumes 8 ammunition.
            </text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Stock Strike</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, reach 5ft., one target. Hit 3 (1d4+1) kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>DRK-1 Tracker Droid</name>
        <size>T</size>
        <type>Droid</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>11 (armor plating)</ac>
        <hp>1 (1d4-1)</hp>
        <speed>5 ft., fly 60 ft.</speed>
        <str>3</str>
        <dex>13</dex>
        <con>8</con>
        <int>2</int>
        <wis>12</wis>
        <cha>7</cha>
        <skill>Perception +3</skill>
        <skill>Stealth +3</skill>
        <vulnerable>Ion</vulnerable>
        <resist>Necrotic, Poison, Psychic</resist>
        <conditionImmune>poison, disease</conditionImmune>
        <senses>Darkvision 120 Ft.</senses>
        <passive>13</passive>
        <cr>0</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Circuitry</name>
            <text>The droid has disadvantage on saving throws against effects that would deal ion or lightning damage.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Flyby</name>
            <text>The tracker droid doesn&#39;t provoke opportunity attacks when it flies out of an enemy&#39;s reach.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Keen Hearing and Sight</name>
            <text>The tracker droid has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on hearing or sight.</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Shockprod</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 1 lightning damage.</text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>The DRK-1 Tracker Droid is one of the most commonly used trackers. Originally created by Arakyd
            Industries on Mechis III, they are small and unobtrusive, can have great utility.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Captain (SW5E)</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>humanoid (any)</type>
        <alignment>any alignment</alignment>
        <ac>20 (powered durasteel armor, heavy shield)</ac>
        <hp>97 (6d8+12)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>16</str>
        <dex>14</dex>
        <con>16</con>
        <int>15</int>
        <wis>11</wis>
        <cha>15</cha>
        <save>Intelligence +5</save>
        <save>Wisdom +3</save>
        <save>Charisma +5</save>
        <skill>Athletics +5</skill>
        <skill>Persuasion +5</skill>
        <passive>10</passive>
        <languages>Galactic Basic and one other</languages>
        <cr>6</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Martial Advantage</name>
            <text>Once per turn, the captain can deal an extra 14 (4d6) damage to a creature it hits with a weapon
                attack if that creature is within 5 ft. of an ally of the captain that isn&#39;t incapacitated.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5E monster manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Multiattack</name>
            <text>The captain makes three weapon attacks</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Hold-out</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, range 30/120 ft., one target. Hit: 4 (1d4+2) energy damage.</text>
            <attack>|5|1d4+2</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Techblade</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft.,
                one target. Hit: 6 (1d6+3) kinetic damage
            </text>
            <attack>|6|1d6+3</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Leadership (Recharges after a Short or Long Rest)</name>
            <text>For 1 minute, the captain can utter a special command or warning whenever a nonhostile creature that
                it can see within 30 ft. of it makes an attack roll or a saving throw. The creature can add a d4 to its
                roll provided it can hear and understand the captain. A creature can benefit from only one Leadership
                die at a time. This effect ends if the captain is incapacitated.
            </text>
        </action>
        <reaction>
            <name>Parry</name>
            <text>The captain adds 3 to its AC against one melee attack that would hit it. To do so, the captain must
                see the attacker and be wielding a melee weapon.
            </text>
        </reaction>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Prisoner</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Humanoid</type>
        <alignment>lawful neutral</alignment>
        <ac>11</ac>
        <hp>16 (3d8)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>11</str>
        <dex>13</dex>
        <con>12</con>
        <int>8</int>
        <wis>9</wis>
        <cha>10</cha>
        <passive>11</passive>
        <languages>Galactic Basic</languages>
        <cr>1/8</cr>
        <action>
            <name>Unarmed</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, reach 5ft., one target. Hit: 3 (1d4+1) kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Assassin (SW5e)</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>humanoid (any race)</type>
        <alignment>any non-good alignment</alignment>
        <ac>15 (heavy combat suit)</ac>
        <hp>78 (12d8+24)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>11</str>
        <dex>16</dex>
        <con>14</con>
        <int>13</int>
        <wis>11</wis>
        <cha>10</cha>
        <save>Dexterity +7</save>
        <save>Intelligence +4</save>
        <skill>Acrobatics +7</skill>
        <skill>Deception +4</skill>
        <skill>Perception +4</skill>
        <skill>Stealth +11</skill>
        <resist>poison</resist>
        <passive>14</passive>
        <languages>Galactic Basic, one other</languages>
        <cr>8</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Assassinate</name>
            <text>During its first turn, the assassin has advantage on attack rolls against any creature that hasn&#39;t
                taken a turn. Any hit the assassin scores against a surprised creature is a critical hit.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Evasion</name>
            <text>If the assassin is subjected to an effect that allows it to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only
                half damage, the assassin instead takes no damage if it succeeds on the saving throw, and only half
                damage if it fails.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Sneak Attack (1/Turn)</name>
            <text>The assassin deals an extra 13 (4d6) damage when it hits a target with a weapon attack and has
                advantage on the attack roll, or when the target is within 5 ft. of an ally of the assassin that isn&#39;t
                incapacitated and the assassin doesn&#39;t have disadvantage on the attack roll.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>Star Wars 5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Multiattack</name>
            <text>The assassin makes two weapon attacks.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Hidden blade</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +7 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 5 (1d6+3) kinetic damage.</text>
            <attack>Normal|7|1d6+3</attack>
            <attack>With Sneak Attack Damage|7|1d6+3+4d6</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Hold-out</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +7 to hit, range 30/120 ft., one target. Hit: 5 (1d4+3) energy damage.</text>
            <attack>Normal|7|1d4+3</attack>
            <attack>With Sneak Attack Damage|7|1d4+3+4d6</attack>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Jetpack Trooper</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Humanoid (any)</type>
        <alignment>any alignment</alignment>
        <ac>15 (light battle armor)</ac>
        <hp>32 (5d8+10)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft., fly 30 ft.</speed>
        <str>13</str>
        <dex>16</dex>
        <con>14</con>
        <int>11</int>
        <wis>13</wis>
        <cha>10</cha>
        <passive>11</passive>
        <languages>Galactic Basic and one other</languages>
        <cr>2</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Jetpack</name>
            <text>Activating or deactivating the jetpack requires a bonus action and, while active, the trooper has a
                flying speed of 30 feet. The jetpack lasts for a maximum of 10 minutes.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Multiattack</name>
            <text>The trooper makes two attacks, one with its blaster pistol and one with its wrist launcher.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Blaster Pistol</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, range 40/160 ft., one target. Hit: 6 (1d6+3) energy damage.</text>
            <attack>|5|1d6+3</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Wrist Launcher</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, range 30/120 ft., one target. Hit: 6 (1d6+3) kinetic damage, and each
                creature within 5 feet must make a DC 13 Dexterity saving throw, taking 3 (1d6) kinetic damage on a
                failed save, or half on a successful save.
            </text>
            <attack>||1d6</attack>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>IG-88 Assassin Droid</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Droid</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>17 (armor plating)</ac>
        <hp>112 (15d8+45)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>14</str>
        <dex>19</dex>
        <con>16</con>
        <int>14</int>
        <wis>15</wis>
        <cha>7</cha>
        <save>Dexterity +7</save>
        <save>Intelligence +5</save>
        <save>Wisdom +5</save>
        <skill>Insight +5</skill>
        <skill>Perception +5</skill>
        <skill>Stealth +7</skill>
        <skill>Survival +5</skill>
        <vulnerable>Ion</vulnerable>
        <resist>Necrotic, Poison, Psychic</resist>
        <conditionImmune>poison, disease</conditionImmune>
        <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
        <passive>13</passive>
        <languages>Binary, Galactic Basic</languages>
        <cr>6</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Circuitry</name>
            <text>The droid has disadvantage on saving throws against effects that would deal ion or lightning damage.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Sneak Attack</name>
            <text>(1/Turn). The assassin droid deals an extra 14 (4d6) damage when it hits a target with a weapon attack
                and has advantage on the attack roll, or when the target is within 5 feet of an ally of the assassin
                droid that isn&#39;t incapacitated and the assassin doesn&#39;t have disadvantage on the roll.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5E Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Multiattack</name>
            <text>The assassin droid makes two weapon attacks.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Sniper Rifle</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +7 to hit, range 150/600 ft., one target. Hit: 10 (1d12+4) energy damage.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Stock Strike</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +2 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 4 (1d4+2) kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Padawan</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Force-wielder</type>
        <alignment>any light</alignment>
        <ac>11 (14 with battle precognition)</ac>
        <hp>27 (5d8+5)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>10</str>
        <dex>12</dex>
        <con>13</con>
        <int>12</int>
        <wis>15</wis>
        <cha>11</cha>
        <passive>14</passive>
        <languages>Galactic Basic, two others</languages>
        <cr>2</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Skills</name>
            <text>Lore +3, Medicine +3, Perception +4</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Spellcasting (Forcecasting)</name>
            <text>The padawan is a 4th-level forcecaster. Its forcecasting ability is Wisdom (power save DC 12, +4 to
                hit with force attacks) and it has 16 force points. The padawan knows the following force powers:
                At-will: give life (light force), guidance (light force), spare the dying (light force), turbulence
                (light force)
                1st-level: cloud mind (light force), heal (light force), project (light force), valor (light force)
                2nd-level: calm emotions (light force), force barrier (light force)
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Shotosaber</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 4 (1d6+1) energy damage.</text>
            <attack>|3|1d6+1</attack>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Adult Acklay</name>
        <size>H</size>
        <type>Beast</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>14 (natural armor)</ac>
        <hp>149 (13d12+65)</hp>
        <speed>40 ft.</speed>
        <str>25</str>
        <dex>10</dex>
        <con>20</con>
        <int>3</int>
        <wis>11</wis>
        <cha>5</cha>
        <passive>10</passive>
        <languages>–</languages>
        <cr>8</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Trampling Charge</name>
            <text>If the acklay moves at least 20 feet straight toward a creature and then hits it with a bite attack on
                the same turn, that target must succeed on a DC 19 Strength saving throw or be knocked prone. If the
                target is prone, the acklay can make one claw attack against it as a bonus action.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Bite</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +9 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 25 (4d8+7) kinetic damage.</text>
            <attack>|11|4d8+7</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Claw</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +11 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 29 (4d10+7) kinetic damage.</text>
            <attack>|11|4d10+7</attack>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>Acklays are amphibious reptillian crustaceans with six deadly claws and razor-sharp teeth native to
            the planet Vendaxa. They are often used as execution beasts or fodder for gladiatorial arenas.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Swarm Of Monkey-Lizards</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Medium swarm of Tiny beasts</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>12 (natural armor)</ac>
        <hp>24 (7d8-7)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft., climb 30 ft.</speed>
        <str>6</str>
        <dex>14</dex>
        <con>8</con>
        <int>3</int>
        <wis>12</wis>
        <cha>6</cha>
        <skill>Perception +5</skill>
        <resist>Energy, Kinetic</resist>
        <conditionImmune>Charmed, Frightened, Paralyzed, Petrified, Prone, Restrained, Stunned</conditionImmune>
        <passive>15</passive>
        <languages>–</languages>
        <cr>1/2</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Pack Tactics</name>
            <text>The monkey-lizard has advantage on attack rolls against a creature if at least one of the
                monkey-lizard&#39;s allies is within 5 feet of the creature and the ally isn&#39;t incapacitated.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Swarm</name>
            <text>The swarm can occupy another creature&#39;s space and vice versa, and the swarm can move through any
                opening large enough for a Tiny porg. The swarm can&#39;t regain hit points or gain temporary hit
                points.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Bite</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target in the swarm&#39;s space. Hit: 7 (2d6) kinetic
                damage, or 3 (1d6) kinetic damage if the swarm has half of its hit points or fewer.
            </text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>Kowakian monkey-lizards are a bipedal reptilian species native to a jungle-like Outer Rim planet
            called Kowak. Although have had no established culture, Kowakian monkeylizards were quite intelligent, and
            despite their silly, cruel nature, they are considered sentient by many sentientologists in the galaxy,
            although there was much debate over that designation. They are often kept as pets due to their mischievous
            nature.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Repulsor Sled (SW5e)</name>
        <size>L</size>
        <type>Construct</type>
        <alignment>neutral</alignment>
        <ac>14 (Armor Plating)</ac>
        <hp>32 (5d10+5)</hp>
        <speed>0 ft., fly 60 ft.</speed>
        <str>16</str>
        <dex>16</dex>
        <con>13</con>
        <int>10</int>
        <wis>10</wis>
        <cha>10</cha>
        <save>Dexterity +5</save>
        <save>Constitution +3</save>
        <save>Dexterity +5</save>
        <save>Constitution +3</save>
        <vulnerable>Ion, lightning</vulnerable>
        <resist>Necrotic, psychic</resist>
        <conditionImmune>Poison, disease</conditionImmune>
        <passive>12</passive>
        <languages>Galactic Basic</languages>
        <cr>1</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Piloted</name>
            <text>The construct requires an active pilot to take any actions, and if the pilot is subjected to any
                conditions that the construct is not immune to, the construct is also subjected to those conditions. The
                pilot may take their own action or one of the actions granted by the construct.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Multiattack</name>
            <text>The construct makes two attacks.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Medium Blaster Cannon</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, range 60/240 ft., one target. Hit 7 (1d10+2) energy damage.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Shock-Net</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, range 60/240 ft., 10 ft. square. Hit 8 (2d4+3) lightning damage and
                restrained. DC 13 str check to break free.
            </text>
        </action>
        <reaction>
            <name>Redirect</name>
            <text>If the construct&#39;s pilot takes damage from a source the pilot is aware of and can see, the
                construct can use its reaction to instead take that damage.
            </text>
        </reaction>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Adolescent Bantha</name>
        <size>H</size>
        <type>Beast</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>12 (natural armor)</ac>
        <hp>76 (8d12+24)</hp>
        <speed>40 ft.</speed>
        <str>22</str>
        <dex>9</dex>
        <con>17</con>
        <int>3</int>
        <wis>11</wis>
        <cha>6</cha>
        <passive>10</passive>
        <languages>–</languages>
        <cr>4</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Trampling Charge</name>
            <text>If the bantha moves at least 20 feet straight toward a creature and then hits it with a gore attack on
                the same turn, that target must succeed on a DC 14 Strength saving throw or be knocked prone. If the
                target is prone, the bantha can make one stomp attack against it as a bonus action.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Gore</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +8 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 18 (3d8+6) kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Stomp</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +8 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 21 (3d10+6) kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <environment>Desert</environment>
        <description>Banthas are a species of large, hairy mammals with sharp,
            spiraling horns. They are native to the desert planet Tatooine, though they are bred on many worlds
            throughout the galaxy. They are social herd animals, and are often domesticated, and used prominently, by
            Tusken Raiders as mounts and companions.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>STAP</name>
        <size>L</size>
        <type>Construct</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>13 (armor plating)</ac>
        <hp>32 (5d10+5)</hp>
        <speed>0 ft., fly 40 ft.</speed>
        <str>11</str>
        <dex>17</dex>
        <con>13</con>
        <int>10</int>
        <wis>10</wis>
        <cha>7</cha>
        <save>Dexterity +5</save>
        <vulnerable>Ion</vulnerable>
        <resist>Necrotic, Poison, Psychic</resist>
        <conditionImmune>poison, disease</conditionImmune>
        <senses>–</senses>
        <passive>0</passive>
        <languages>–</languages>
        <cr>1</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Circuitry</name>
            <text>The construct has disadvantage on saving throws against effects that would deal ion or lightning
                damage.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Piloted</name>
            <text>The construct requires an active pilot to take any actions, and if the pilot is subjected to any
                conditions that the construct is not immune to, the construct is also subjected to those conditions. The
                pilot may take their own action or one of the actions granted by the construct.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Multiattack</name>
            <text>The construct makes two attacks.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Blaster Cannon</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, range 40/160 ft., one target. Hit: 5 (1d4+3) energy damage.</text>
        </action>
        <reaction>
            <name>Redirect</name>
            <text>If the construct&#39;s pilot takes damage from a source the pilot is aware of and can see, the
                construct can use its reaction to instead take that damage.
            </text>
        </reaction>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>The Single Trooper Aerial Platform (or STAP) is a Baktoid Armor Workshop product inspired by
            civilian airhooks. They re-engineered similar craft for greater performance and reliability. Slim and
            lightweight, the tiny repulsorlift craft is fueled by high-voltage energy cells, which power drive turbines
            providing the STAP with impressive speed and maneuverability. The agile vessels are popular mounts for
            droids, and are typically bolstered by signals from an orbital Droid Control Ship, which skillfully guides
            the STAP&#39;s pilots. However, battle droids are exposed to enemy fire while riding the fragile craft. The
            vehicles are armed with a pair of forward-mounted blaster cannons.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Aqualish Enforcer</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Humanoid</type>
        <alignment>chaotic evil</alignment>
        <ac>16 (durasteel armor)</ac>
        <hp>93 (11d8+44)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>18</str>
        <dex>12</dex>
        <con>18</con>
        <int>11</int>
        <wis>11</wis>
        <cha>16</cha>
        <save>Strength +6</save>
        <save>Constitution +6</save>
        <save>Wisdom +2</save>
        <skill>Intimidation +5</skill>
        <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
        <passive>10</passive>
        <languages>Galactic Basic, Aqualish, one other</languages>
        <cr>4</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Aggressive</name>
            <text>As a bonus action, the aqualish can move up to its speed toward a hostile creature that it can see.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Fury</name>
            <text>The aqualish deals an extra 4 (ld8) damage when it hits with a melee weapon attack (included in the
                attack).
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Multiattack</name>
            <text>The aqualish makes two weapon attacks.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Vibroaxe</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 14 (1d12+4+1d8) kinetic damage.</text>
            <attack>|3|1d12+4+1d8</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Slugthrower</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, range 30/120 ft., one target. Hit: 6 (2d4+1) kinetic damage.</text>
            <attack>|3|2d4+1</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Burst</name>
            <text>The aqualish sprays a 10-foot-cube area within normal range of its slugthrower with shots. Each
                creature in the area must make a DC 11 Dexterity saving throw, taking normal weapon damage on a failed
                save.
            </text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Battle Cry (1/Day)</name>
            <text>Each creature of the aqualish&#39;s choice that is within 30 feet of it, can hear it, and not already
                affected by Battle Cry gain advantage on attack rolls until the start of the aqualish&#39;s next turn.
                The aqualish can then make one attack as a bonus action.
            </text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Berserker (SW5e)</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>humanoid (any species)</type>
        <alignment>any chaotic alignment</alignment>
        <ac>13 (heavy combat suit)</ac>
        <hp>67 (9d8+27)</hp>
        <speed>35 ft.</speed>
        <str>16</str>
        <dex>12</dex>
        <con>17</con>
        <int>9</int>
        <wis>11</wis>
        <cha>9</cha>
        <passive>10</passive>
        <languages>Galactic Basic and one other</languages>
        <cr>2</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Reckless</name>
            <text>At the start of its turn, the berserker can gain advantage on all melee weapon attack rolls during
                that turn, but attack rolls against it have advantage until the start of its next turn.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Vibroaxe</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 9 (1d12 + 3) kinetic damage.</text>
            <attack>|5|1d12+3</attack>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Trooper Captain</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Humanoid</type>
        <alignment>any alignment</alignment>
        <ac>16 (durasteel armor)</ac>
        <hp>90 (10d8+45)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>15</str>
        <dex>18</dex>
        <con>16</con>
        <int>11</int>
        <wis>12</wis>
        <cha>15</cha>
        <save>Strength +4</save>
        <save>Dexterity +6</save>
        <save>Constitution +5</save>
        <skill>Athletics +4</skill>
        <skill>Perception +2</skill>
        <skill>Persuasion +4</skill>
        <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
        <passive>13</passive>
        <languages>Galatic Basic, two others</languages>
        <cr>4</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Brave</name>
            <text>The captain has advantage on saving throws against being frightened.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Multiattack</name>
            <text>The captain makes two blaster rifle attacks and throws a fragmentation grenade, if available.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Blaster Rifle</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, range 100/400 ft., one target. Hit 8 (1d8+4) energy damage.</text>
            <attack>|6|1d8+4</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Frag Grenade</name>
            <text>(3/Day). The captain throws a grenade, choosing a point within 40 ft. Each creature within 10 feet
                must make a DC 12 Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes 2d6 kinetic damage on a failed save, or half
                as much as on a successful one.
            </text>
            <attack>||2d6</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Stock Strike</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5ft., one target. Hit: 4 (1d4+2) kinetic damage.</text>
            <attack>|4|1d4+2</attack>
        </action>
        <reaction>
            <name>Leadership</name>
            <text>(Recharges after a Short or Long Rest). The Trooper Captain can utter a special command or warning
                whenever a nonhostile creature that it can see within 30 feet of it makes an attack roll or a saving
                throw. The creature can add a d4 to its roll provided it can hear and understand the Trooper Captain. A
                creature can benefit from only one Leadership die at a time.
            </text>
        </reaction>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Adolescent Dewback</name>
        <size>L</size>
        <type>Beast</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>11 (natural armor)</ac>
        <hp>34 (4d10+12)</hp>
        <speed>40 ft., swim 30 ft.</speed>
        <str>19</str>
        <dex>10</dex>
        <con>16</con>
        <int>2</int>
        <wis>13</wis>
        <cha>7</cha>
        <skill>Perception +3</skill>
        <passive>13</passive>
        <languages>–</languages>
        <cr>1</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Keen Smell</name>
            <text>The dewback has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on smell.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Multiattack</name>
            <text>The dewback makes two attacks: one with its bite and one with its claws.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Bite</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 8 (1d8+4) kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Claw</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 11 (2d6+4) kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <environment>Desert</environment>
        <description>Dewbacks are large, four-legged, omnivorous, cold-blooded reptiles native to the Dune Sea of
            Tatooine. As such, they are well-adapted to the harsh desert climate. This and the fact that they could be
            easily domesticated made them commonly employed as beasts of burden by both the inhabitants of the desert
            planet and the off-worlders wandering its dunes. Due to their numerous useful traits and versatility, they
            are quite possibly the most respected of all the creatures native to Tatooine.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Tusken Cheiftain</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Humanoid</type>
        <alignment>chaotic dark</alignment>
        <ac>16 (durasteel armor)</ac>
        <hp>93 (11d8+44)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>18</str>
        <dex>12</dex>
        <con>18</con>
        <int>10</int>
        <wis>13</wis>
        <cha>13</cha>
        <save>Strength +6</save>
        <save>Constitution +6</save>
        <save>Wisdom +3</save>
        <skill>Intimidation +3</skill>
        <skill>Perception +3</skill>
        <skill>Survival +3</skill>
        <passive>13</passive>
        <languages>Tusken</languages>
        <cr>4</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Agressive</name>
            <text>As a bonus action, the tusken can move up to its speed toward a hostile creature that it can see.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Multiattack</name>
            <text>The tusken makes two gaffi stick attacks.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Gaffi Stick</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5ft., one target. Hit 9 (1d10+4) kinetic damage.</text>
            <attack>|6|1d10+4</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Cycler Rifle</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack +3 to hit, reach 150/600 ft., one target. Hit 6 (1d10+1) kinetic damage.</text>
            <attack>|3|1d10+1</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Battle Cry</name>
            <text>(1/Day). Each creature of the chieftain&#39;s choice that is within 30 feet of it, can hear it, and
                not already affected by Battle Cry gain advantage on attack rolls until the start of the chieftain&#39;s
                next turn. The chieftain can then make one attack as a bonus action.
            </text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Shyrack</name>
        <size>S</size>
        <type>Beast</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>12 (natural armor)</ac>
        <hp>2 (1d6-1)</hp>
        <speed>0 ft., Fly 20 ft.</speed>
        <str>4</str>
        <dex>16</dex>
        <con>9</con>
        <int>3</int>
        <wis>12</wis>
        <cha>4</cha>
        <senses>blindsight 60ft</senses>
        <passive>11</passive>
        <cr>0</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Keen Hearing</name>
            <text>The Shyrack has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on hearing.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Bite</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one creature. Hit: 1 kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>Shyracks are cave-dwelling terrors that are fiercely territorial and attack any intruder with
            aggression and fervor. While typically cave bound, every sixty-three years the shyracks of Korriban spill
            from their cave habitats for an entire summer. These periods saw them fill the sky where they blotted out
            the sun and moon where they rained their bluish droppings onto everything below. Prior to the return of the
            Sith Empire, biologists from across the galaxy arrived on the planet in order to witness every sixty-third
            summer where they observed the purpling of the red Korriban terrain.

            While ungainly and slow-moving with no eyes, shyracks are potentially dangerous pests, especially when they
            converge as a swarm on an intruder. They are native to the Shyrack cave of Korriban and are natural rivals
            to the feared Tuk&#39;ata.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Sirona O&#39;Keefe</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Humanoid</type>
        <alignment>chaotic good</alignment>
        <ac>14 (Combat Suit)</ac>
        <hp>27 (6d8)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>8</str>
        <dex>16</dex>
        <con>10</con>
        <int>19</int>
        <wis>12</wis>
        <cha>14</cha>
        <save>Dexterity +6</save>
        <save>Intelligence +7</save>
        <save>Dexterity +6</save>
        <save>Intelligence +7</save>
        <skill>Deception +5</skill>
        <skill>Insight +4</skill>
        <skill>Acrobatics +0</skill>
        <skill>Perception +4</skill>
        <skill>Persuasion +5</skill>
        <skill>Acrobatics +0</skill>
        <skill>Acrobatics +0</skill>
        <skill>Sleight of Hand +6</skill>
        <skill>Acrobatics +0</skill>
        <skill>Acrobatics +0</skill>
        <passive>14</passive>
        <languages>Galactic Basic, Huttese, Binary</languages>
        <cr>5</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Bad Feeling</name>
            <text>When Captain O&#39;Keefe rolls for initiative, she can move up to her speed. This movement happens
                before the initiative order is determined. Once she has used this feature, she can’t use it again until
                she finishes a long rest.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Cunning Action</name>
            <text>Captain O&#39;Keefe can take a bonus action on each of her turns in combat. This action can be used
                only to take the Dash, Disengage, or Hide action.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Defiant</name>
            <text>Captain O&#39;Keefe can add a d4 to a skill check or saving throw, after rolling but before the
                outcome is known. She must then finish a short or long rest before she can use this feature again.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Sneak Attack</name>
            <text>Once per turn, Captain O&#39;Keefe can deal an extra 3d6 damage to one creature she hits with an
                attack if she has advantage on the attack roll. The attack must use a finesse or a ranged weapon. She
                does not need advantage on the attack roll if another enemy of the target is within 5 feet of it, that
                enemy isn’t incapacitated, and she does not have disadvantage on the attack roll
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Techcasting (3/Rest)</name>
            <text>Captain O&#39;Keefe is a 6th-level techcaster. Her techcasting ability is Intelligence (power save DC
                15, +7 to hit with power attacks).
                At-will: Encrypted Message, Mending
                1st level: Detect Enhancement, Repair Droid, Tracker Droid Interface
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Uncanny Dodge</name>
            <text>When an attacker that Captain O&#39;Keefe can see hits her with an attack, she can use her reaction to
                halve the attack’s damage against her.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Blaster Pistol</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack. +6 to hit, range 40/160 ft., one target. Hit 6 (1d6+3) energy damage. Reload
                12.
            </text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Vibrodagger</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5ft., one target. Hit: 3 (1d4+3) kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Hidden blade</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5ft., one target. Hit: 5 (1d4+3) kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Snow Wampa</name>
        <size>L</size>
        <type>Beast</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>12 (natural armor)</ac>
        <hp>51 (6d10 + 18)</hp>
        <speed>40 ft.</speed>
        <str>19</str>
        <dex>13</dex>
        <con>16</con>
        <int>5</int>
        <wis>12</wis>
        <cha>11</cha>
        <skill>Perception +3</skill>
        <skill>Stealth +3</skill>
        <immune>Cold</immune>
        <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
        <passive>13</passive>
        <languages>–</languages>
        <cr>3</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Fear of Fire</name>
            <text>If the wampa takes fire damage, it has disadvantage on attack rolls and ability checks until the end
                of its next turn.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Keen Smell</name>
            <text>The wampa has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on smell.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Snow Camouflage</name>
            <text>The wampa has advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks made to hide in snowy terrain.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Multiattack</name>
            <text>The wampa makes two attacks, one with its claw and one with its bite.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Claw</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 12 (2d6+5) kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Bite</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one creature. Hit: 7 (1d10+2) kinetic damage. The target
                is grappled (escape DC 14) Until this grapple ends, the target is restrained, and the Snow Wampa can&#39;t
                bite another target.
            </text>
        </action>
        <environment>Arctic, Mountain</environment>
        <description>Wampas are semi-sentient predators with humanoid proportions that stand up to 12 feet tall. While
            they all share characteristics in common, there are three variations of wampa that are distinct based on
            their native planet.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Hulking Rakghoul</name>
        <size>L</size>
        <type>Humanoid</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>15 (natural armor)</ac>
        <hp>120 (16d10+16)</hp>
        <speed>40 ft.</speed>
        <str>17</str>
        <dex>19</dex>
        <con>14</con>
        <int>4</int>
        <wis>10</wis>
        <cha>6</cha>
        <skill>Athletics +6</skill>
        <skill>Perception +3</skill>
        <passive>12</passive>
        <languages>–</languages>
        <cr>5</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Rakghoul Plague</name>
            <text>Creatures that come in contact with the rakghoul may become afflicted with rakghoul plague, a virulent
                disease that transforms the creature into a rakghoul over the next 24 (7d6) hours. The plague is only
                effective against humanoids.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Savage Leap</name>
            <text>If the rakghoul moves at least 20 feet toward a creature and then hits it with a claw attack on the
                same turn, the target must succeed on a DC 13 Strength saving throw or be knocked prone. If the target
                is prone, the rakghoul can make one bite attack against it as a bonus action.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Multiattack</name>
            <text>The rakghoul makes two claw attacks.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Bite</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5ft., one target. Hit 12 (2d8+3) Kinetic damage. If the target
                is a humanoid creature, it must succeed on a DC 13 Constitution saving throw or become infected with the
                Rakghoul Plague.
            </text>
            <attack>|4|2d8+3</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Claws</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 10 (2d6+3) Kinetic damage. If the target
                is a humanoid creature, it must succeed on a DC 13 Constitution saving throw or become infected with the
                Rakghoul Plague.
            </text>
            <attack>|4|2d6+3</attack>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>Rakghouls are a living plague–the manifestation of a highly communicable disease capable of swiftly
            transforming its victims into twisted, degenerate monsters with predatory instincts. The rakghoul virus can
            infect hundreds of known species and is most often delivered through a rakghoul’s bite; a person attacked by
            a rakghoul and “lucky” enough to survive typically becomes a rakghoul him- or herself. Some victims resist
            the virus for days, succumbing to rakghoul instincts while retaining their original bodies.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Sergeant</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>humanoid (any)</type>
        <alignment>any alignment</alignment>
        <ac>16 (durasteel armor)</ac>
        <hp>39 (6d8+12)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>13</str>
        <dex>15</dex>
        <con>14</con>
        <int>10</int>
        <wis>13</wis>
        <cha>12</cha>
        <skill>Athletics +3</skill>
        <skill>Persuasion +3</skill>
        <passive>11</passive>
        <languages>Galactic Basic and one other</languages>
        <cr>3</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Martial Advantage</name>
            <text>Once per turn, the sergeant can deal an extra 10 (3d6) damage to a creature it hits with a weapon
                attack if that creature is within 5 feet of an ally of the sergeant that isn&#39;t incapacitated.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Multiattack</name>
            <text>The sergeant makes two weapon attacks.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Blaster Rifle</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, range 100/400 ft., one target. Hit: 6 (1d8+2) energy damage.</text>
            <attack>|4|1d8+2</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Vibrosword</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 7 (1d12+1) kinetic damage.</text>
            <attack>|3|1d12+1</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Leadership (Recharges after a Short or Long Rest)</name>
            <text>For 1 minute, the sergeant can utter a special command or warning whenever a nonhostile creature that
                it can see within 30 feet of it makes an attack roll or a saving throw. The creature can add a d4 to its
                roll provided it can hear and understand the sergeant. A creature can benefit from only one Leadership
                die at a time. This effect ends if the sergeant is incapacitated.
            </text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Spy (SW5E)</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>humanoid (any)</type>
        <alignment>any alignment</alignment>
        <ac>12 (unarmored)</ac>
        <hp>27 (6d8)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>10</str>
        <dex>15</dex>
        <con>10</con>
        <int>12</int>
        <wis>14</wis>
        <cha>16</cha>
        <skill>Deception +5</skill>
        <skill>Insight +4</skill>
        <skill>Investigation +5</skill>
        <skill>Perception +6</skill>
        <skill>Persuasion +5</skill>
        <skill>Sleight of Hand +4</skill>
        <skill>Stealth +4</skill>
        <passive>16</passive>
        <languages>Galactic Basic and one other</languages>
        <cr>1</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Cunning Action</name>
            <text>On each of its turns, the spy can use a bonus action to take the Dash, Disengage, or Hide action.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Sneak Attack (1/Turn)</name>
            <text>The spy deals an extra 7 (2d6) damage when it hits a target with a weapon attack and has advantage on
                the attack roll, or when the target is within 5 ft. of an ally of the spy that isn&#39;t incapacitated
                and the spy doesn&#39;t have disadvantage on the attack roll.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Multiattack</name>
            <text>The spy makes two weapon attacks.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Hold-out</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, range 30/120 ft., one target. Hit: 4 (1d4+2) energy damage.</text>
            <attack>|4|1d4+2</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Techblade</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 5 (1d6+2) kinetic damage.</text>
            <attack>|4|1d6+2</attack>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Switch</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Droid</type>
        <alignment>lawful evil</alignment>
        <ac>10 (Integrated Armor)</ac>
        <hp>13 (3d8)</hp>
        <speed>30 feet</speed>
        <str>8</str>
        <dex>9</dex>
        <con>10</con>
        <int>13</int>
        <wis>13</wis>
        <cha>14</cha>
        <save>Dexterity +1</save>
        <save>Intelligence +3</save>
        <save>Dexterity +1</save>
        <save>Intelligence +3</save>
        <vulnerable>Ion</vulnerable>
        <resist>Necrotic, psychic</resist>
        <conditionImmune>Poison, disease</conditionImmune>
        <passive>13</passive>
        <languages>All Registered</languages>
        <cr>1/8</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Droid Systems</name>
            <text>Droids do not need to eat or drink.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Rapid Reconstruction</name>
            <text>As a bonus action, Switch can spend one hit dice to recover hit points.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Intimidating Presence</name>
            <text>Switch has advantage on Intimidation.</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Hold-out Blaster</name>
            <text>Rangers weapon attack. +1 to hit, range 30/120, one target. Hit: 1 (1d4-1). Reload 6.</text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>Possessions: hold-out blaster, audio recorder, comlink, data pad, R5-88 astromech droid
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Captain Vischera</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Humanoid</type>
        <alignment>lawful evil</alignment>
        <ac>13 (Heavy Combat Suit)</ac>
        <hp>22 (5d8)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>10</str>
        <dex>12</dex>
        <con>10</con>
        <int>14</int>
        <wis>11</wis>
        <cha>13</cha>
        <passive>13</passive>
        <languages>Galactic Basic, Bocce, Durese, High Galactic</languages>
        <cr>1/4</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Brave</name>
            <text>Captain Vischera has advantage on saving throws against being frightened.</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Blaster Pistol</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, range 40/160 ft., one target. Hit 4 (1d6+1) energy damage. Reload
                12.
            </text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Vibrodagger</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5ft., one target. Hit: 3 (1d4+1) kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <reaction>
            <name>Leadership (Recharges after a Short or Long Rest)</name>
            <text>Captain Vischera can utter a special command or warning whenever a nonhostile creature that it can see
                within 30 feet of it makes an attack roll or a saving throw. The creature can add a d4 to its roll
                provided it can hear and understand the Lieutenant. A creature can benefit from only one Leadership die
                at a time.
            </text>
        </reaction>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>74-Z Speeder Bike</name>
        <size>L</size>
        <type>Construct</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>14 (armor plating)</ac>
        <hp>39 (6d10+6)</hp>
        <speed>0 ft., fly 50 ft.</speed>
        <str>11</str>
        <dex>17</dex>
        <con>13</con>
        <int>10</int>
        <wis>10</wis>
        <cha>7</cha>
        <save>Dexterity +5</save>
        <vulnerable>ion</vulnerable>
        <resist>necrotic, poison, psychic</resist>
        <conditionImmune>poison, disease</conditionImmune>
        <passive>0</passive>
        <languages>–</languages>
        <cr>2</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Comm Jammers</name>
            <text>The construct suppresses all electronic communications devices within 60 feet of it.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Circuitry</name>
            <text>The construct has disadvantage on saving throws against effects that would deal ion or lightning
                damage.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Piloted</name>
            <text>The construct requires an active pilot to take any actions, and if the pilot is subjected to any
                conditions that the construct is not immune to, the construct is also subjected to those conditions. The
                pilot may take their own action or one of the actions granted by the construct.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Multiattack</name>
            <text>The construct makes two attacks.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Blaster Cannon</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, range 60/240 ft., one target. Hit: 6 (1d6+3) energy damage.</text>
            <attack>||1d6+3</attack>
        </action>
        <reaction>
            <name>Redirect</name>
            <text>If the construct&#39;s pilot takes damage from a source the pilot is aware of and can see, the
                construct can use its reaction to instead take that damage.
            </text>
        </reaction>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>The 74-z speeder bike is a model of speeder bike manufactured by the Aratech Repulsor Company. It
            is commonly used for reconnaissance missions. They are equipped with a blaster cannon and comm jammers.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Trooper Recruit</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Humanoid (any), (SW5E)</type>
        <alignment>any alignment</alignment>
        <ac>11 (light battle armor)</ac>
        <hp>6 (1d8+1)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>12</str>
        <dex>11</dex>
        <con>11</con>
        <int>10</int>
        <wis>10</wis>
        <cha>10</cha>
        <senses>Dark vision 60 ft.</senses>
        <passive>8</passive>
        <cr>1/4</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Blaster Rifle</name>
            <text>Ranged weapon attack. +2 to hit, range 100/400 ft., one target. Hit: 7 (1d8+2) energy damage.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Stock Strike</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +1 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 3 (1d4+1) kinetic damage.</text>
        </trait>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>Carries: utility belt with one medpac</description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>BX-5C Series Supercommando Droid</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>droid</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>16 (armor plating)</ac>
        <hp>96 (15d8+30)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>13</str>
        <dex>19</dex>
        <con>14</con>
        <int>15</int>
        <wis>13</wis>
        <cha>7</cha>
        <save>Dexterity +7</save>
        <skill>Perception +4</skill>
        <skill>Stealth +7</skill>
        <vulnerable>Ion</vulnerable>
        <resist>Necrotic, Poison, Psychic</resist>
        <conditionImmune>poison, disease</conditionImmune>
        <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
        <passive>12</passive>
        <languages>Binary, Galactic Basic</languages>
        <cr>5</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Circuitry</name>
            <text>The droid has disadvantage on saving throws against effects that would deal ion or lightning damage.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Droid Synergy</name>
            <text>Once per turn, the commando droid can deal an extra 3 (1d6) damage to a creature it hits with a weapon
                attack if that creature is within 5 feet of an ally of the commando droid that isn&#39;t incapacitated.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Stealth Field Generator</name>
            <text>The commando droid has advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks that rely on sight.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Multiattack</name>
            <text>The supercommando droid makes two weapon attacks.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Blaster Carbine</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +7 to hit, range 60/240 ft., one target. Hit: 6 (1d6+3) energy damage.</text>
            <attack>|7|1d6+3</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Techblade</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +7 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 6 (1d6+3) kinetic damage.</text>
            <attack>|7|1d6+3</attack>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>The BX series commando droid is an elite battle droid model made for stealth assignments. Equipped
            with a stealth field generator, they are perfectly designed for espionage.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Soldier</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Humanoid</type>
        <alignment>any alignment</alignment>
        <ac>15 (light battle armor, light shield generator)</ac>
        <hp>11 (2d8+2)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>12</str>
        <dex>13</dex>
        <con>12</con>
        <int>10</int>
        <wis>11</wis>
        <cha>8</cha>
        <skill>Athletics +3</skill>
        <passive>10</passive>
        <languages>Galactic Basic, one other</languages>
        <cr>1/2</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Martial Advantage</name>
            <text>Once per turn, the soldier can deal an extra 7 (2d6) damage to a creature it hits with a weapon attack
                if that creature is within 5 feet of an ally of the soldier that isn&#39;t incapacitated.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Blaster Carbine</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, range 60/240 ft., one target. Hit: 4 (1d6+1) energy damage</text>
            <attack>|3|1d6+1</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Vibroblade</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 5 (1d8+1) kinetic damage, or 6 (1d10+1)
                kinetic damage if used with two hands.
            </text>
            <attack>One-handed|3|1d8+1</attack>
            <attack>Two-handed|3|1d10+1</attack>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Felucian Chief</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Humanoid</type>
        <alignment>neutral</alignment>
        <ac>11</ac>
        <hp>85 (9d8+9)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>8</str>
        <dex>12</dex>
        <con>12</con>
        <int>13</int>
        <wis>20</wis>
        <cha>14</cha>
        <skill>Stealth +3</skill>
        <passive>19</passive>
        <languages>Felucianese</languages>
        <cr>1/2</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Amphibious</name>
            <text>Felucians breathe air and water.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Mask of the Wild</name>
            <text>Felucians may attempt to hide even when they are only lightly obscured by foliage, heavy rain, falling
                snow, mist, and other natural phenomena.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Forcecasting</name>
            <text>The Chief knows the following Force Powers: Affect Mind, Force Push/Pull, Give Life, Mind Trick, Spare
                the Dying, Disperse Force, Heal, Sense Emotion, Sense Force, Calm Emotions, Coerce Mind, Dissuade Mind,
                Sever Force, Share Life, Telekinesis
            </text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Burst</name>
            <text>The Felucian causes the earth to burst from beneath their feet. Each creature within 5 ft., other than
                them, must succeed on a DC 17 Dexterity saving throw or take 1d6 kinetic damage.
            </text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Beast Trick (1/Rest)</name>
            <text>This power lets the Chief distract a beast. Choose a beast that he can see within range. If the
                beast’s Intelligence is 4 or higher, the power fails. Otherwise, the beast must succeed on a DC 17
                Wisdom saving throw or be charmed by the Chief for 24 hours. If the Chief or one of his companions harms
                the target, the power ends.
            </text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Plant Surge (1/Rest)</name>
            <text>If the Chief casts this power using 1 action, all normal plants in a 100-foot radius centered on a
                point become overgrown. Moving through the area spends 4 feet of movement for every 1 foot moved. He can
                exclude areas of any size within the power&#39;s area from being affected. If he casts this power over 8
                hours, all plants in a halfmile radius centered on a point yield twice the normal amount of food when
                harvested for 1 year.
            </text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Felucian</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Humanoid</type>
        <alignment>neutral</alignment>
        <ac>11</ac>
        <hp>22 (4d8+4)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>14</str>
        <dex>13</dex>
        <con>14</con>
        <int>8</int>
        <wis>15</wis>
        <cha>8</cha>
        <skill>Stealth +3</skill>
        <passive>14</passive>
        <languages>Felucianese</languages>
        <cr>1/8</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Amphibious</name>
            <text>Felucians breathe air and water.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Mask of the Wild</name>
            <text>Felucians may attempt to hide even when they are only lightly obscured by foliage, heavy rain, falling
                snow, mist, and other natural phenomena.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Skullblade</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5ft., one target. Hit 6 (1d8+2) kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Mighty Swing</name>
            <text>The Felucian can spend their bonus action to add an additional damage dice to their melee attack. This
                dice is doubled on a critical hit.
            </text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Burst</name>
            <text>The Felucian causes the earth to burst from beneath their feet. Each creature within 5 ft., other than
                them, must succeed on a DC 12 Dexterity saving throw or take 1d6 kinetic damage.
            </text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Admiral Nathan Gilder Varth</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Humanoid</type>
        <alignment>lawful evil</alignment>
        <ac>11</ac>
        <hp>54 (12d8)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>8</str>
        <dex>12</dex>
        <con>10</con>
        <int>20</int>
        <wis>16</wis>
        <cha>16</cha>
        <save>Dexterity +6</save>
        <save>Intelligence +9</save>
        <save>Wisdom +7</save>
        <skill>Acrobatics +9</skill>
        <skill>Deception +0</skill>
        <skill>Insight +0</skill>
        <skill>Investigation +0</skill>
        <skill>Perception +0</skill>
        <skill>Persuasion +7</skill>
        <passive>26</passive>
        <languages>Galactic Basic, High Galactic</languages>
        <cr>9</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Defiant</name>
            <text>Admiral Gilder can add a d4 to a skill check or saving throw, after rolling but before the outcome is
                known. He must then finish a short or long rest before he can use this feature again.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Inspiring Leader</name>
            <text>Admiral Gilder can spend 10 minutes inspiring his companions, shoring up their resolve to fight. When
                he does so, choose up to six friendly creatures (which can include him) within 30 feet of him who can
                see or hear him and who can understand him. Each creature can gain temporary hit points equal to 15. A
                creature can’t gain temporary hit points from this feat again until it has finished a short or long
                rest.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Academic Superiority</name>
            <text>Admiral Gilder knows how to apply his studies in practical ways known as maneuvers. His maneuvers are
                fueled by special dice called superiority dice. He has 6 superiority dice, which are d10s. A superiority
                die is expended when he uses it. He regains all of his expended superiority dice when he finishes a
                short or long rest. Some of his maneuvers require his target to make a saving throw to resist the
                maneuver’s effects. The saving throw DC is 17.

                Admiral Gilder knows the following maneuvers from the SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook:

                Commander&#39;s Strike, Deliberate Movement, Heads Up, Measured Action, One Step Ahead, Riposte, Scholar&#39;s
                Parry, Targeted Strike
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Critical Analysis</name>
            <text>Admiral Gilder is able to analyze a target, develop a plan on how to best overcome any potential
                obstacle, and execute that plan with ruthless efficiency. As a bonus action on his turn, he can analyze
                a target he can see within 120 feet of him. For the next minute, or until he analyzes another target, he
                gain the following benefits:

                When he analyzes a hostile creature, attack and damage rolls made with vibroweapons wielded in onehand
                or blaster weapons against that target may use his Intelligence modifier instead of Strength or
                Dexterity.

                When he analyzes a friendly creature, the target may use its reaction and end your Critical Analysis to
                add 5 to 1 attack roll, ability check, or saving throw.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Discovery</name>
            <text>Admiral Gilder&#39;s studies have helped him discover new practices he can apply to his skills. He
                knows the following scholar discoveries from the SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook:

                Contingency Plan, Firing Command, Observant Leader, Running on Fumes, Tactical Retreat, Unbound
                Commander
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Fire as One</name>
            <text>Admiral Gilder can focus his target down with the help with an ally. Whenever the creature that is the
                target of his Critical Analysis feature is attacked by someone other than him, he can use his reaction
                to make one weapon attack against them.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Battlefield Survey</name>
            <text>When Admiral Gilder spends 10 minutes observing an area that is within 120 feet of him, or by using a
                detailed map, select 5 creatures. He and those selected allies ignore any known difficult terrain, and
                have advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks in that area.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>Dawn of Defiance</text>
        </trait>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>HK-47 Assassin Droid</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Droid</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>18 (armor plating)</ac>
        <hp>214 (10d8+20)</hp>
        <speed>40 ft.</speed>
        <str>14</str>
        <dex>20</dex>
        <con>17</con>
        <int>15</int>
        <wis>16</wis>
        <cha>15</cha>
        <skill>Athletics +6</skill>
        <skill>Acrobatics +9</skill>
        <skill>Insight +7</skill>
        <skill>Perception +7</skill>
        <skill>Survival +7</skill>
        <vulnerable>Ion</vulnerable>
        <resist>Necrotic, Poison, Psychic</resist>
        <conditionImmune>poison, disease</conditionImmune>
        <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
        <passive>17</passive>
        <languages>Binary, Galactic Basic</languages>
        <cr>9</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Droid Synergy</name>
            <text>Once per turn, the droid can deal an extra 14 (4d6) damage to a creature it hits with a weapon attack
                if that creature is within 5 feet of an ally of droid that isn&#39;t incapacitated.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Legendary Resistance (3/day)</name>
            <text>If the Assassin fails a saving throw, it can choose to succeed instead.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Multiattack</name>
            <text>The assassin droid makes two weapon attacks.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Blaster Rifle</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +9 to hit, range 100/400 ft., one target. Hit: 9 (1d8+5) energy damage.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Stock Strike</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +2 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 4 (1d4+2) kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <reaction>
            <name>Reactive Shield</name>
            <text>(1/day). Until the start of its next turn, the assassin droid has a +5 bonus to AC. This includes the
                triggering attack.
            </text>
        </reaction>
        <legendary>
            <name>Legendary Actions</name>
            <text>The Assassin Droid can take 3 legendary actions, choosing from the options below. Only one legendary
                action option can be used at a time and only at the end of another creature&#39;s turn. The Assassin
                Droid regains spent legendary actions at the start of their turn.
            </text>
        </legendary>
        <legendary>
            <name>Attack</name>
            <text>The assassin droid makes one weapon attack.</text>
        </legendary>
        <legendary>
            <name>Detect</name>
            <text>The assassin droid makes a Wisdom (Perception) check.</text>
        </legendary>
        <legendary>
            <name>Rocket Boost</name>
            <text>The assassin droid leaps up to 40 feet in any direction. This movement does not provoke opportunity
                attacks.
            </text>
        </legendary>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>The HK series assassin droid, also known as the HK series protocol droid, is a combination of an
            assassin droid and protocol droid. The series designation stands for &#34;Hunter Killer,&#34; befitting
            their primary functions as assassins. They are manufactured by Czerka Corporation. Their ability to perform
            the functions of a protocol droid became a major reason for their unmatched lethality, as they could and
            would often act as normal (if quite sinister looking) protocol droids, thus concealing their true function
            and allowing them to get closer to intended targets. HK series assassin droids are equipped with an
            integrated emergency shield and jet pack.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>B1-X Battle Droid</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Droid</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>15 (armor plating)</ac>
        <hp>16 (3d8+3)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>11</str>
        <dex>16</dex>
        <con>12</con>
        <int>14</int>
        <wis>10</wis>
        <cha>9</cha>
        <skill>Perception +2</skill>
        <vulnerable>Ion</vulnerable>
        <resist>Necrotic, Poison, Psychic</resist>
        <conditionImmune>poison, disease</conditionImmune>
        <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
        <passive>12</passive>
        <languages>Binary, Galactic Basic</languages>
        <cr>1/2</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Battle Droid Swarm</name>
            <text>When an ally of the battle droid hits a hostile creature that it can see with a weapon attack, the
                battle droid can use its reaction to make one weapon attack against that creature.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Circuitry</name>
            <text>The droid has disadvantage on saving throws against effects that would deal ion or lightning damage.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Blaster Pistol</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, range 40/160 ft., one target. Hit: 6 (1d6+3) energy damage.</text>
            <attack>|5|1d6+3</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Stock Strike</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +2 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 2 (1d4) kinetic damage.</text>
            <attack>|2|1d4</attack>
        </action>
        <reaction>
            <name>Redirect Attack</name>
            <text>When a creature the battle droid can see targets it with an attack, the battle droid chooses another
                battle droid within 5 feet of it. The two battle droids swap places, and the chosen battle droid becomes
                the target instead.
            </text>
        </reaction>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>B1 battle droids, also referred to as standard battle droids, are the most widely-used battle
            droids manufactured by Baktoid Combat Automata and Baktoid Armor Workshop. The B1 battle droid sees
            extensive service as the mainlines soldiers due to their cheap, mass produced nature.

            The B1-X model was created to serve as an officer unit.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Headhunter Trooper</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Humanoid</type>
        <alignment>any alignment</alignment>
        <ac>14 (combat suit)</ac>
        <hp>23 (5d8)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>11</str>
        <dex>16</dex>
        <con>10</con>
        <int>12</int>
        <wis>15</wis>
        <cha>10</cha>
        <save>Dexterity +5</save>
        <skill>Stealth +7</skill>
        <skill>Perception +4</skill>
        <skill>Acrobatics +5</skill>
        <passive>14</passive>
        <languages>Galactic Basic, one other</languages>
        <cr>2</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Cunning Action</name>
            <text>On each of its turns, the trooper can use a bonus action to take the Dash, Disengage, or Hide
                action.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Sneak Attack</name>
            <text>(1/Turn). The trooper deals an extra 7 (2d6) damage when it hits a target with a weapon attack and has
                advantage on the attack roll, or when the target is within 5 ft. of an ally of the trooper that isn&#39;t
                incapacitated and the trooper doesn&#39;t have disadvantage on the attack roll.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Sniper Rifle</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, range 150/600 ft., one target. Hit: 9 (1d12+3) energy damage.</text>
            <attack>|5|1d12+3</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Vibrodagger</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 5 (1d4+3) kinetic damage.</text>
            <attack>|5|1d4+3</attack>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>The Banshee</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Starship</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>15 (lightweight armor)</ac>
        <hp>60 (6d8+6)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>11</str>
        <dex>14</dex>
        <con>12</con>
        <int>19</int>
        <wis>14</wis>
        <cha>14</cha>
        <skill>Perception +4</skill>
        <skill>Acrobatics +10</skill>
        <passive>14</passive>
        <languages>Galactic Basic, Huttese, Binary</languages>
        <cr>6</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Starship Traits</name>
            <text>
                Shield Regeneration Rate: 5
                Shield Points: 30 (quick-charge shield)
                Hyperdrive: Class 2 (Backup Class 7) Crew 2
                Passengers: 8
                Cargo: 35 tons
                Consumables: 1 month
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Armaments</name>
            <text>Double Light Laser Cannon (Pilot)
                Capacitor (Co-Pilot)
                Interdiction Drive (Co-Pilot)
                Quad Laser Cannon (Port Gunner)
                Quad Laser Cannon (Starboard Gunner)
            </text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Capacitor (Recharge 6)</name>
            <text>The freighter routes power between the shields, engines, and weapons. While balanced, each feature
                functions normally. While power is shifted to one of the features, the efficacy of that feature is
                doubled (shields take half damage and regenerate at double their speed, engines generate twice the
                speed, weapons deal double damage) while the other two are halved (shields take double damage and
                regenerate at half speed, engines generate half the speed, weapons deal half damage). These effects last
                until the capacitor is toggled again.
            </text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Light Laser Cannon</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, range 30/60 ft., one target. Hit: 7 (2d4+2) energy damage. Two
                attacks.
            </text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Quad Laser Cannon</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, range 45/90 ft., one target. Hit: 9 (2d6+2) energy damage. Two
                attacks.
            </text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Bonus Action: Interdiction Drive (Recharge 6)</name>
            <text>As a bonus action, the freighter can engage the interdiction drive. All ships within 30 feet of your
                starting point must make a DC 14 Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, their speed is halved
                until the beginning of the freighter&#39;s next turn. The freighter then launches forward 30 feet.
            </text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Ganga Lor</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Humanoid</type>
        <alignment>chaotic neutral</alignment>
        <ac>13 (Heavy Combat Suit)</ac>
        <hp>11 (2d8+2)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>13</str>
        <dex>11</dex>
        <con>12</con>
        <int>8</int>
        <wis>9</wis>
        <cha>10</cha>
        <passive>11</passive>
        <languages>Galactic Basic, Chevin, Huttese, Rhodes’s, Shriiwook</languages>
        <cr>1/2</cr>
        <action>
            <name>Blaster Pistol</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack. +1 to hit, range 40/160 ft., one target. Hit 2 (1d6-1) energy damage. Reload
                12.
            </text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Thick Skull.</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack. +2 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit 3 (1d6) kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Cliff Wampa</name>
        <size>L</size>
        <type>Beast</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>13 (natural armor)</ac>
        <hp>96 (12d10+24)</hp>
        <speed>40ft., climb 40 ft.</speed>
        <str>21</str>
        <dex>11</dex>
        <con>18</con>
        <int>5</int>
        <wis>13</wis>
        <cha>12</cha>
        <skill>Athletics +8</skill>
        <skill>Perception +4</skill>
        <skill>Stealth +3</skill>
        <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
        <passive>14</passive>
        <languages>–</languages>
        <cr>5</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Keen Smell</name>
            <text>The wampa has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on smell.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Rocky Camouflage</name>
            <text>The wampa has advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks made to hide in rocky terrain.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Multiattack</name>
            <text>The wampa makes two attacks, one with its claw and one with its bite.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Claw</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +8 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 7 (2d6+5) kinetic damage.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Bite</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +8 to hit, reach 5 ft., one creature. Hit: 7 (1d10+5) kinetic damage. The target
                is grappled (escape DC 16) Until this grapple ends, the target is restrained, and the wampa can&#39;t
                bite another target.
            </text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Throw Boulder</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +8 to hit, reach 5 ft., range 25/50 ft., one target. Hit: 8 (1d8+5) kinetic
                damage. If the target is a creature, it must succeed a DC 15 Strength saving throw or be knocked prone.
            </text>
        </action>
        <environment>Forest, Hill, Mountain</environment>
        <description>Wampas are semi-sentient predators with humanoid proportions that stand up to 12 feet tall. While
            they all share characteristics in common, there are three variations of wampa that are distinct based on
            their native planet.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Tusken Raider</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Humanoid</type>
        <alignment>chaotic dark</alignment>
        <ac>12 (combat suit)</ac>
        <hp>15 (2d8+6)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>15</str>
        <dex>12</dex>
        <con>16</con>
        <int>10</int>
        <wis>11</wis>
        <cha>9</cha>
        <skill>Survival +2</skill>
        <passive>10</passive>
        <languages>Tusken</languages>
        <cr>1/2</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Agressive</name>
            <text>As a bonus action, the tusken can move up to its speed toward a hostile creature that it can see.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Gaffi Stick</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5ft., one target. Hit 7 (1d10+2) kinetic damage.</text>
            <attack>|4|1d10+2</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Cycler Rifle</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack +3 to hit, reach 150/600 ft., one target. Hit 6 (1d10+1) kinetic damage.</text>
            <attack>|3|1d10+1</attack>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>B2 Super Battle Droid</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Droid</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>16 (armor plating)</ac>
        <hp>26 (4d8+8)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>13</str>
        <dex>16</dex>
        <con>14</con>
        <int>14</int>
        <wis>12</wis>
        <cha>11</cha>
        <vulnerable>Ion</vulnerable>
        <resist>Necrotic, Poison, Psychic</resist>
        <conditionImmune>poison, disease</conditionImmune>
        <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
        <passive>11</passive>
        <languages>Binary, Galactic Basic</languages>
        <cr>1</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Circuitry</name>
            <text>The droid has disadvantage on saving throws against effects that would deal ion or lightning damage.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Multiattack</name>
            <text>The super battle droid makes two weapon attacks with its strike or wrist blaster.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Strike</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 3 (1d4+1) kinetic damage.</text>
            <attack>|3|1d4+1</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Wrist Blaster</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, range 60/240 ft., one target. Hit: 6 (1d6+3) energy damage.</text>
            <attack>|5|1d6+3</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Wrist Blaster Volley</name>
            <text>(Recharge 6). The super battle droid sprays a 10-foot-cube area within normal range with shots. Each
                creature in the area must make a DC 13 Dexterity saving throw, taking normal weapon damage on a failed
                save.
            </text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>The B2 super battle droid is an upgraded version of the B1 battle droid, with superior armament and
            armor. It features dual integrated wrist blasters.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>3PO Series Protocol Droid</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Droid</type>
        <alignment>neutral</alignment>
        <ac>10 (armor plating)</ac>
        <hp>4 (1d8)</hp>
        <speed>20 ft.</speed>
        <str>10</str>
        <dex>10</dex>
        <con>11</con>
        <int>13</int>
        <wis>12</wis>
        <cha>7</cha>
        <vulnerable>Ion</vulnerable>
        <resist>Necrotic, Poison, Psychic</resist>
        <conditionImmune>poison, disease</conditionImmune>
        <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
        <passive>11</passive>
        <languages>All Registered Languages</languages>
        <cr>0</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Skills</name>
            <text>Lore +2</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Circuitry</name>
            <text>The droid has disadvantage on saving throws against effects that would deal ion or lightning damage.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Strike</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +2 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 1 kinetic damage.</text>
            <attack>|2|1</attack>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
        <description>The 3PO series is a Human-cyborg relations protocol droid produced by Cybot Galactica. The primary
            function of this droid is to assist sentient species in relations with one another. Protocol droids are
            programmed mostly for etiquette and translation. They are programmed with knowledge about numerous culture,
            both to advise their owners and ensure their own diplomatic and cultural sensitivity.
        </description>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Sage</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>force-wielder</type>
        <alignment>any universal</alignment>
        <ac>12 ((15 with battle precognition))</ac>
        <hp>40 (9d8)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>9</str>
        <dex>14</dex>
        <con>11</con>
        <int>12</int>
        <wis>19</wis>
        <cha>11</cha>
        <save>Intelligence +4</save>
        <save>Wisdom +7</save>
        <passive>13</passive>
        <cr>6</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Skills</name>
            <text>Lore +4, Medicine +7</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Spellcasting (Forcecasting)</name>
            <text>The sage is a 9th-level forcecaster. Its forcecasting ability is Wisdom (power save DC 15, +7 to hit
                with force attacks) and it has 36 force points. The sage knows the following force powers:
                At-will: mind trick, saber ward, saber reflect, turbulence
                1st-level: breath control (universal force), battle precognition (universal force), force jump
                (universal force)
                2nd-level: battle meditation (universal force), force confusion (universal force), phasewalk (universal
                force)
                3rd-level: force suppression (universal force), sever force (universal force), telekinetic storm
                (universal force)
                4th-level: force immunity (universal force), freedom of movement (universal force)
                5th-level: improved battle meditation (universal force)
            </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Shotosaber</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 5 (1d6 +2) energy damage.</text>
            <attack>|5|1d6+2</attack>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Scout Trooper</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Humanoid (any)</type>
        <alignment>any alignment</alignment>
        <ac>13 (combat suit)</ac>
        <hp>13 (2d8+4)</hp>
        <speed>30 ft.</speed>
        <str>11</str>
        <dex>15</dex>
        <con>12</con>
        <int>14</int>
        <wis>13</wis>
        <cha>9</cha>
        <skill>Acrobatics +0</skill>
        <senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
        <passive>15</passive>
        <languages>Galactic Basic and one other</languages>
        <cr>1/2</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Skills</name>
            <text>Nature +4, Perception +5, Stealth +6, Survival +5, Piloting +4</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Keen Hearing and Sight</name>
            <text>The scout trooper has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on hearing or sight.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Source</name>
            <text>SW5e Monster Manual</text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Multiattack</name>
            <text>The scout trooper makes two weapon attacks.</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Hold-out Blaster</name>
            <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, range 30/120, one target. Hit: 4 (1d4+2)</text>
            <attack>|5|1d6+3</attack>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Vibrodagger</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5ft., one target. Hit: 4 (1d4+2)</text>
            <attack>||1d6</attack>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
    <monster>
        <name>Kybuck</name>
        <size>M</size>
        <type>Beast</type>
        <alignment>unaligned</alignment>
        <ac>14</ac>
        <hp>7 (2d8-2)</hp>
        <speed>60 ft.</speed>
        <str>12</str>
        <dex>16</dex>
        <con>8</con>
        <int>2</int>
        <wis>13</wis>
        <cha>12</cha>
        <skill>Athletics +3</skill>
        <passive>13</passive>
        <cr>1/8</cr>
        <trait>
            <name>Dash</name>
            <text>Unlike many other beasts, kybucks can move at incredibly high speeds overland. They have a maximum
                velocity of 60 mph.
            </text>
        </trait>
        <action>
            <name>Bite</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, reach 5ft., one target. Hit 5 (1d4+3)</text>
        </action>
        <action>
            <name>Kick</name>
            <text>Melee Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, reach 5ft., one target. Hit 4 (1d3+3)</text>
        </action>
        <environment>Any</environment>
    </monster>
</compendium>