<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
    <spell>
        <name>Mass Coerce Mind (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>6</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <duration>24 hours</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Coerce Mind

            You suggest a course of activity (limited to a sentence or two) and influence with the Force up to twelve
            creatures of your choice that you can see within range and that can hear and understand you. Creatures that
            can’t be charmed are immune to this effect. The suggestion must be worded in such a manner as to make the
            course of action sound reasonable. Asking the creature to harm itself automatically negates the effect of
            the power.

            Each target must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, it pursues the course of action you described
            to the best of its ability. The suggested course of action can continue for the entire duration. If the
            suggested activity can be completed in a shorter time, the power ends when the subject finishes what it was
            asked to do.

            You can also specify conditions that will trigger a special activity during the duration. For example, you
            might suggest that a group of soldiers give all their money to the first beggar they meet. If the condition
            isn’t met before the power ends, the activity isn’t performed. If you or any of your companions damage a
            creature affected by this power, the power ends for that creature. This power has no effect on droids or
            constructs.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a 7th-level force slot, the duration is 10 days. When you use
            an 8th-level force slot, the duration is 30 days. When you use a 9th-level force slot, the duration is a
            year and a day.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Necrotic Charge (Dark Force)</name>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Varies</range>
        <duration>1 round</duration>
        <text>As part of the action used to cast this power, you must make a melee attack with a weapon against one
            creature within your weapon’s reach, otherwise the power fails. On a hit, the target suffers the attack’s
            normal effects, and you can choose to deal up to 1d8 of necrotic damage, which you suffer as well. This
            damage can’t be reduced or negated in any way.

            This power’s damage increases when you reach higher levels. At 5th level, the melee attack deals an extra
            1d8 necrotic damage to the target, and you can increase the secondary damage to 2d8. Both damage rolls
            increase by 1d8 at 11th level and 17th level.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>1d8</roll>
        <roll>2d8</roll>
        <roll>3d8</roll>
        <roll>4d8</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Drain Vitality (Dark Force)</name>
        <level>2</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Sap Vitality

            You draw the willpower from a creature you can see within range. Make a ranged force attack against the
            target. On a hit, the target takes 2d6 necrotic damage and it deals only half damage with weapon attacks
            that use Strength until the power ends.

            At the end of each of the target’s turns, it can make a Constitution saving throw against the power. On a
            success, the power ends.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force slot of 3rd level or higher, the damage increases by
            1d6 for each slot level above 2nd.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>2d6</roll>
        <roll>3d6</roll>
        <roll>4d6</roll>
        <roll>5d6</roll>
        <roll>6d6</roll>
        <roll>7d6</roll>
        <roll>8d6</roll>
        <roll>9d6</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Greater Heal (Light Force)</name>
        <level>6</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Improved Heal

            Choose a creature that you can see within range. A surge of positive energy washes through the creature,
            causing it to regain 70 hit points. This power also ends blindness, deafness, and any diseases affecting the
            target. This power has no effect on droids or constructs.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force slot of 7th level or higher, the healing increases by
            10 for each slot level above 6th.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Force Camouflage (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>2</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>You become invisible until the power ends. Anything you are wearing or carrying is invisible as long as it
            is on your person. The power ends if you attack or cast a power.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Project (Light Force)</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>120 feet</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>You lift three piles of debris or small objects from the ground and hurl them. Each pile hits a creature
            of your choice that you can see within range. The pile deals 1d4+1 force damage to its target. The piles all
            strike simultaneously and you can direct them to hit one creature or several.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force slot of 2nd level or higher, you lift and throw an
            additional pile of debris for each slot level above 1st.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>1d4+1</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Slow Descent (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 reaction*</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <duration>1 minute</duration>
        <text>* which you take when you or a creature within 60 feet of you falls.

            Choose up to five falling creatures within range. A falling creature’s rate of descent slows to 60 feet per
            round until the power ends. If the creature lands before the power ends, it takes no falling damage and can
            land on its feet, and the power ends for that creature.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Stun Droid (Light Force)</name>
        <level>2</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Choose a droid that you can see within range. The target must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or be
            paralyzed for the duration. At the beginning of each of its turns, the droid takes energy damage equal to
            your forcecasting ability modifier. At the end of each of its turns, the target can make another Wisdom
            saving throw. On a success, the power ends on the target.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Cloud Mind (Light Force)</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>90 feet</range>
        <duration>1 minute</duration>
        <text>Roll 5d8; the total is how many hit points of creatures this power can affect. Creatures within 20 feet of
            a point you choose are affected in order of their current hit points.

            Starting with the creature that has the lowest current hit points, each creature affected by this power
            falls unconscious. If the power ends, the sleeper takes damage, or someone uses an action wake the sleeper,
            they will be awoken.

            Subtract each creature’s hit points from the total before moving on to the creature with the next lowest hit
            points. A creature’s hit points must be equal to or less than the remaining total for that creature to be
            affected.

            This power has no effect on droids or constructs.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force slot of 2nd level or higher, you can roll an
            additional 2d8 for each slot level above 1st.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>5d8</roll>
        <roll>7d8</roll>
        <roll>9d8</roll>
        <roll>11d8</roll>
        <roll>13d8</roll>
        <roll>15d8</roll>
        <roll>17d8</roll>
        <roll>19d8</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>True Sight (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>6</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <duration>1 hour</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Force Sight

            You shift your vision to see through use of the Force, giving you the ability to see things as they actually
            are. For the duration, you have truesight and notice secret doors hidden by powers, all out to a range of
            120 feet.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Valor (Light Force)</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Guidance

            You bless up to three creatures of your choice within range. Whenever a target makes an attack roll or a
            saving throw before the power ends, the target can roll a d4 and add the number rolled to the attack roll or
            saving throw.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force slot of 2nd level or higher, you can target one
            additional creature for each slot level above 1st.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Drain Life (Dark Force)</name>
        <level>4</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Drain Vitality

            You draw the life force from a creature you can see within range. The target must make a Constitution saving
            throw. The target takes 8d8 necrotic damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. If
            you reduce a hostile creature to 0, you gain temporary hit points equal to half the damage dealt. This power
            has no effect on droids or constructs.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force slot of 5th level or higher, the damage increases by
            1d8 for each slot level above 4th.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>8d8</roll>
        <roll>9d8</roll>
        <roll>10d8</roll>
        <roll>11d8</roll>
        <roll>12d8</roll>
        <roll>13d8</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Maddening Darkness (Dark Force)</name>
        <level>8</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>150 feet</range>
        <duration>Up to 10 minutes, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Shroud of Darkness

            Terrifying darkness spreads from a point you choose within range to fill a 60-foot-radius sphere until the
            power ends. The darkness spreads around corners. A creature with darkvision can’t see through this darkness.
            Unenhanced light, as well as light created by powers of 8th level or lower, can’t illuminate the area.

            Shrieks, gibbering, and mad laughter can be heard within the sphere. Whenever a creature starts its turn in
            the sphere, it must make a Wisdom saving throw, taking 8d8 psychic damage on a failed save, or half as much
            damage on a successful one.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>8d8</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Rescue (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>2</level>
        <time>1 bonus action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>You pull one willing ally you can see within 30 feet of you to an unoccupied space within 5 feet of you.
            The target must use their reaction to accept the pull.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Master Force Immunity (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>8</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self (10-foot-radius sphere)</range>
        <duration>Up to 1 hour, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Improved Force Immunity

            A 10-foot-radius faintly shimmering barrier surrounds you. Within the sphere, powers can’t be cast and
            enhanced items become mundane. Until the power ends, the sphere moves with you, centered on you.

            Powers and other enhanced effects are suppressed in the sphere and can’t protrude into it. A slot expended
            to cast a suppressed power is consumed. While an effect is suppressed, it doesn’t function, but the time it
            spends suppressed counts against its duration.

            Targeted Effects: Powers and other enhanced effects that target a creature or an object in the sphere have
            no effect on that target.

            Enhanced Areas: The area of another power or enhanced effect, such as force storm, can’t extend into the
            sphere. If the sphere overlaps an enhanced area, the part of the area that is covered by the sphere is
            suppressed.

            Powers: Any active power or other enhanced effect on a creature or an object in the sphere is suppressed
            while the creature or object is in it.

            Enhanced Items: The properties and powers of enhanced items are suppressed in the sphere. For example, a +1
            vibrosword in the sphere functions as an unenhanced vibrosword.

            An enhanced weapon’s properties and powers are suppressed if it is used against a target in the sphere or
            wielded by an attacker in the sphere. If an enhanced weapon or a piece of enhanced ammunition fully leaves
            the sphere (for example, if you fire an enhanced shot or throw an enhanced saberspear at a target outside
            the sphere), the enhancement of the item ceases to be suppressed as soon as it exits.

            Enhanced Travel: Teleportation fails to work in the sphere, whether the sphere is the destination or the
            departure point for such enhanced travel. A portal to another location temporarily closes while in the
            sphere.

            Creatures and Objects: A creature or object summoned or created by powers temporarily winks out of existence
            in the sphere. Such a creature instantly reappears once the space the creature occupied is no longer within
            the sphere.

            Tech Override/Sever Force: Powers and enhanced effects such as sever force have no effect on the sphere.
            Likewise, the spheres created by different scrambling field powers don’t nullify each other.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Insanity (Dark Force)</name>
        <level>5</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self (30-foot sphere)</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Horror

            This power assaults and twists creatures’ minds, spawning delusions and provoking uncontrolled action. Each
            creature in a 30-foot-radius sphere centered on you must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw when you cast this
            power or be affected by it.

            An affected target can’t take reactions and must roll a d8 at the start of each of its turns to determine
            its behavior for that turn. This power has no effect on constructs or droids.

            D8 | Behavior
            1 | The creature uses all its movement to move in a random direction. To determine the direction, roll a d8
            and assign a direction to each die face. The creature doesn’t take an action this turn.
            2-6 | The creature doesn’t move or take actions this turn.
            7-8 | The creature uses its action to make a melee attack against a randomly determined creature within its
            reach. If there is no creature within its reach, the creature does nothing this turn.

            At the end of each of its turns, an affected target can make a Wisdom saving throw. If it succeeds, this
            effect ends for that target.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a power slot of 6th level or higher, the radius of the sphere
            increases by 5 feet for each force slot level above 5th.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>1d8</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Plague (Dark Force)</name>
        <level>3</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Affliction

            Choose up to six creatures of your choice in a 40-foot cube within range. Each target must succeed on a
            Constitution saving throw or be affected by this power for the duration.

            An affected target’s speed is halved, it takes a -2 penalty to AC and Dexterity saving throws, and it can’t
            use reactions. On its turn, it can use either an action or a bonus action, not both. Regardless of the
            creature’s abilities or items, it can’t make more than one melee or ranged attack during its turn.

            If the creature attempts to cast a power with a casting time of 1 action, roll a d20. On an 11 or higher,
            the power doesn’t take effect until the creature’s next turn, and the creature must use its action on that
            turn to complete the power. If it can’t, the power is wasted.

            A creature affected by this power makes another Wisdom saving throw at the end of its turn. On a successful
            save, the effect ends for it.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Enfeeble (Dark Force)</name>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <duration>minute</duration>
        <text>Dark energy courses from your hand at a creature within range. The target must succeed on a Wisdom saving
            throw. If it’s is missing any hit points, it takes 1d12 necrotic damage. Otherwise, it takes 1d8.

            The power’s damage increases by one die when you reach 5th, 11th, and 17th level.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>1d12</roll>
        <roll>2d12</roll>
        <roll>3d12</roll>
        <roll>4d12</roll>
        <roll>1d8</roll>
        <roll>2d8</roll>
        <roll>3d8</roll>
        <roll>4d8</roll>
        <classes>Sorcerer, Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Heroism (Light Force)</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <duration>Up to 1 minute, concentration</duration>
        <text>A willing creature you touch is imbued with bravery. Until the power ends, the creature is immune to being
            frightened and gains temporary hit points equal to your forcecasting ability modifier at the start of each
            of its turns. When the power ends, the target loses any remaining temporary hit points from this power.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force slot of 2nd level or higher, you can target one
            additional creature for each slot level above 1st.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Hallucination (Dark Force)</name>
        <level>2</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>You craft a dangerous illusion in the mind of a creature that you can see within range. The target must
            make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, you create a phantasmal object, creature, or other visible
            phenomenon of your choice that is no larger than a 10-foot cube and that is perceivable only to the target
            for the duration. This power has no effect on droids or constructs.

            The hallucination includes sound, temperature, and other stimuli, also evident only to the creature.

            The target can use its action to examine the hallucination with an Intelligence (Investigation) check
            against your force power save DC. If the check succeeds, the target realizes that the hallucination is an
            illusion, and the power ends.

            While a target is affected by the power, the target treats the hallucination as if it were real. The target
            rationalizes any illogical outcomes from interacting with the hallucination. For example, a target
            attempting to walk across a phantasmal bridge that spans a chasm falls once it steps onto the bridge. If the
            target survives the fall, it still believes that the bridge exists and comes up with some other explanation
            for its fall - it was pushed, it slipped, or a strong wind might have knocked it off.

            An affected target is so convinced of the hallucination’s reality that it can even take damage from the
            illusion. A hallucination created to appear as a creature can attack the target. Similarly, a hallucination
            created to appear as fire, a pool of acid, or lava can burn the target. Each round on your turn, the
            hallucination can deal 1d6 psychic damage to the target if it is in the hallucination’s area or within 5
            feet of the hallucination, provided that the illusion is of a creature or hazard that could logically deal
            damage, such as by attacking. The target perceives the damage as a type appropriate to the illusion.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force power slot of 3rd level or higher, the range increases
            by 20 feet, the image dimensions increase by 5 feet, and you can target one additional creature for every
            two slot levels above 2nd.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Tremor (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>10 feet</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Burst

            You cause a tremor in the ground within range. Each creature other than you in a 5-foot-radius sphere
            centered on that point must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 1d6 kinetic
            damage and is knocked prone. If the ground in that area is loose earth or stone, it becomes difficult
            terrain until cleared, with each 5-foot-diameter portion requiring at least 1 minute to clear by hand.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by
            1d6 for each slot level above 1st.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>1d6</roll>
        <roll>2d6</roll>
        <roll>3d6</roll>
        <roll>4d6</roll>
        <roll>5d6</roll>
        <roll>6d6</roll>
        <roll>7d6</roll>
        <roll>8d6</roll>
        <roll>9d6</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Force Scream (Dark Force)</name>
        <level>3</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self (15-foot radius)u</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>You emit a scream imbued with the power of the Force. Each creature you choose within 15 feet of you must
            succeed on a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, a creature take 4d6 psychic damage, 4d6 sonic
            damage, and is deafened until the end of its next turn. On a successful save, it takes half as much damage
            and isn’t deafened.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>4d6</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Knight Speed (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>3</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Burst of Speed

            Choose a willing creature that you can see within range. Until the power ends, the target’s speed is
            doubled, it gains a +2 bonus to AC, it has advantage on Dexterity saving throws, and it gains an additional
            action on each of its turns. That action can be used only to take the Attack (one weapon attack only), Dash,
            Disengage, Hide, or Use an Object action.

            When the power ends, the target can’t move or take actions until after its next turn, as a wave of lethargy
            sweeps over it.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Force Mend (Light Force)</name>
        <level>7</level>
        <time>1 minute</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <duration>1 hour</duration>
        <text>You touch a creature and stimulate its natural healing ability. The target regains 4d8+15 hit points. For
            the duration of the power, the target regains 1 hit point at the start of each of its turns (10 hit points
            each minute).

            If the creature has a severed part you hold it to the stump, the power instantaneously causes the limb to
            knit to the stump.

            This power has no effect on droids or constructs.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Force Jump (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>Using the force to augment the strength in your legs, you leap up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space you
            can see.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force slot of 2nd level or higher, your jump distance
            increases by 5 feet for each slot level above 1st.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Wrack (Dark Force)</name>
        <level>6</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>You wrack the body of a creature that you can see with a virulent, disease-like condition. The target must
            make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, it takes 14d6 necrotic damage, or half as much damage on
            a successful save. The damage can’t reduce the target’s hit points below 1. If the target fails the saving
            throw, its hit point maximum is reduced for 1 hour by an amount equal to the necrotic damage it took. Any
            effect that removes a disease allows a creature’s hit point maximum to return to normal before that time
            passes.

            Force Potency: If you cast this power using a force slot of 7th level or higher, the power deals an extra
            2d6 damage for each slot level above 6th.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>14d6</roll>
        <roll>16d6</roll>
        <roll>18d6</roll>
        <roll>20d6</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Improved Force Immunity (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>6</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self (15-foot radius)</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Force Immunity

            An immobile, faintly shimmering barrier springs into existence in a 15-foot radius around you and remains
            for the duration. The barrier moves with you.

            Any force power of 5th level or lower cast from outside the barrier can’t affect creatures or objects within
            it, even if the power is cast using a higher level force slot. Such a power can target creatures and objects
            within the barrier, but the power has no effect on them. Similarly, the area within the barrier is excluded
            from the areas affected by such powers.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force slot of 7th level or higher, the barrier blocks powers
            of one level higher for each slot level above 6th.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Heal (Light Force)</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>A creature you touch regains a number of hit points equal to 1d8 + your forcecasting ability modifier.
            This power has no effect on droids or constructs.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force slot of 2nd level or higher, the healing increases by
            1d8 for each slot level above 1st.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>1d8+%5</roll>
        <roll>2d8+%5</roll>
        <roll>3d8+%5</roll>
        <roll>4d8+%5</roll>
        <roll>5d8+%5</roll>
        <roll>6d8+%5</roll>
        <roll>7d8+%5</roll>
        <roll>8d8+%5</roll>
        <roll>9d8+%5</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Greater Feedback (Dark Force)</name>
        <level>5</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>120 feet</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Improved Feedback

            You choose a point within range and cause psychic energy to explode there. Each creature in a 20-foot-radius
            sphere centered on that point must make an Intelligence saving throw. A creature with an Intelligence score
            of 2 or lower can’t be affected by this power. A target takes 8d6 psychic damage on a failed save, or half
            as much damage on a successful one.

            After a failed save, a target has muddled thoughts for 1 minute. During that time, it rolls a d6 and
            subtracts the number rolled from all its attack rolls and ability checks, as well as its Constitution saving
            throws to maintain concentration. The target can make a Wisdom saving throw at the end of each of its turns,
            ending the effect on itself on a success.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>8d6</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Beast Trick (Light Force)</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <duration>24 hours</duration>
        <text>This power lets you distract a beast. Choose a beast that you can see within range. If the beast’s
            Intelligence is 4 or higher, the power fails. Otherwise, the beast must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or
            be charmed by you for the power’s duration. If you or one of your companions harms the target, the power
            ends.

            Force Potency - When you cast this power using a force slot of 2nd level or higher, you can affect one
            additional beast for each slot level above 1st.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Mind Trap (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>4</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Force Confusion

            You attempt to trap the mind of your target in a psychic cage. The target must make a Charisma saving throw.
            On a failed save, the creature’s mind is trapped. It can think, but it can’t have any contact with or
            perceive the outside world. If the creature takes damage, it makes another Charisma save. On a success, the
            power ends. This power has no effect on droids or constructs.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force slot of 6th level or higher, after 1 minute of
            concentration the power’s duration becomes 24 hours and it no longer requires your concentration.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Whirlwind (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>7</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>300 feet</range>
        <duration>Up to 1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>A whirlwind howls down to a point that you can see on the ground within range. The whirlwind is a
            10-foot-radius, 30-foot-high cylinder centered on that point. Until the power ends, you can use your action
            to move the whirlwind up to 30 feet in any direction along the ground. The whirlwind sucks up any Medium or
            smaller objects that aren’t secured to anything and that aren’t worn or carried by anyone.

            A creature must make a Dexterity saving throw the first time on a turn that it enters the whirlwind or that
            the whirlwind enters its space, including when the whirlwind first appears. A creature takes 10d6 kinetic
            damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. In addition, a Large or smaller
            creature that fails the save must succeed on a Strength saving throw or become restrained in the whirlwind
            until the power ends. When a creature starts its turn restrained by the whirlwind, the creature is pulled 5
            feet higher inside it, unless the creature is at the top. A restrained creature moves with the whirlwind and
            falls when the power ends, unless the creature has some means to stay aloft.

            A restrained creature can use an action to make a Strength or Dexterity check against your force save DC. If
            successful, the creature is no longer restrained by the whirlwind and is hurled 3d6x10 feet away from it in
            a random direction.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Shocking Shield (Dark Force)</name>
        <level>4</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <duration>10 minutes</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Shock

            Lightning courses in a sphere surrounding your body, shedding bright light in a 10-foot radius and dim light
            for an additional 10 feet. You can use your action to end the power early.

            Whenever a creature within 5 feet of you hits you with a melee attack, it takes 2d8 lightning damage.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>2d8</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Mind Spike (Dark Force)</name>
        <level>2</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <duration>Up tp 1 hour, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Choose one creature you can see. The target must make a Wisdom saving throw. A creature takes 3d8 psychic
            damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. Additionally, on a failed save, you
            always know the target’s location, but only while the two of you are on the same planet. The target can’t
            become hidden from you, and if it’s invisible, it gains no benefits from this condition against you. This
            power has no effect on droids or constructs.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Restoration (Light Force)</name>
        <level>2</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>You touch a creature and end either one disease or one condition afflicting it. The condition can be
            blinded, deafened, paralyzed, or poisoned.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Sense Emotion (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <duration>Up to 10 minutes, Concentration</duration>
        <text>You attune your senses to pick up the emotions of others for the duration. When you cast the power, and as
            your action on each turn until the power ends, you can focus your senses on one humanoid you can see within
            30 feet of you. You instantly learn the target’s prevailing emotion, whether it’s love, anger, pain, fear,
            calm, or something else. If the target isn’t actually humanoid or it is immune to being charmed, you sense
            that it is calm.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Force Repulse (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>3</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self (20-foot radius)</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>You release an omnidirectional telekinetic burst. Each creature within 20 feet must make a Dexterity
            saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 8d6 force damage and is pushed back 5 feet. On a successful
            save, a creature takes half damage and isn’t pushed.

            All small objects that are not worn or carried are also pushed 5 feet back.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by
            1d6 for each slot level above 3rd.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>8d6</roll>
        <roll>9d6</roll>
        <roll>10d6</roll>
        <roll>11d6</roll>
        <roll>12d6</roll>
        <roll>13d6</roll>
        <roll>14d6</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Telekinetic Storm (Light Force)</name>
        <level>3</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self (15-foot radius)</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Turbulence

            You stir the force around you, creating a turbulent field of telekinetic energy that buffets enemies around
            you. The field extends out to a distance of 15 feet around you for the duration.

            When you cast this power, you can designate any number of creatures you can see to be unaffected by it. An
            affected creature’s speed is halved in the area, and when the creature enters the area for the first time on
            a turn or starts its turn there, it must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, the creature
            takes 3d8 force damage. On a successful save, the creature takes half as much damage.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force power slot of 4th level or higher, the damage
            increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 3rd.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>3d8</roll>
        <roll>4d8</roll>
        <roll>5d8</roll>
        <roll>6d8</roll>
        <roll>7d8</roll>
        <roll>8d8</roll>
        <roll>9d8</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Aura of Vigor (Light Force)</name>
        <level>3</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self (30-foot radius)</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Valor

            Envigorating energy radiates from you in a 30-foot radius. Until the power ends, the aura moves with you,
            centered on you. Each nonhostile creature in the aura (including you) deals an extra 1d4 damage with weapon
            attacks.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Horror (Dark Force)</name>
        <level>3</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self (30-foot cone)</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Fear

            You project a phantasmal image of a creature’s worst fears. Each creature in a 30-foot cone must succeed on
            a Wisdom saving throw or drop whatever it is holding and become frightened for the duration. This power has
            no effect on constructs or droids.

            While frightened by this power, a creature must take the Dash action and move away from you by the safest
            available route on each of its turns, unless there is nowhere to move. If the creature ends its turn in a
            location where it doesn’t have line of sight to you, the creature can make a Wisdom saving throw. On a
            successful save, the power ends for that creature.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Skill Empowerment (Light Force)</name>
        <level>5</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <duration>Up to 1 hour, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Your power with the Force deepens a creature’s understanding of its own talent. You touch one willing
            creature and give it expertise in one skill of your choice; until the power ends, the creature doubles its
            proficiency bonus for ability checks it makes that use the chosen skill.

            You must choose a skill in which the target is proficient and that isn’t already benefiting from an effect,
            such as Expertise, that doubles its proficiency bonus.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Force Project (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>7</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <duration>Up to one day, concentration</duration>
        <text>You create an illusory copy of yourself that lasts for the duration. The copy can appear at any location
            that you have seen before, regardless of intervening obstacles. The illusion looks and sounds like you but
            is intangible. If the illusion takes any damage, it disappears, and the power ends.

            You can use your action to move this illusion up to twice your speed, and make it gesture, speak, and behave
            in whatever way you choose. It mimics your mannerisms perfectly.

            You can see through its eyes and hear through its ears as if you were in its space. On your turn as a bonus
            action, you can switch from using its senses to using your own, or back again. While you are using its
            senses, you are blinded and deafened in regard to your own surroundings.

            Physical interaction with the image reveals it to be an illusion, because things can pass through it. A
            creature that uses its action to examine the image can determine that it is an illusion with a successful
            Intelligence (Investigation) check against your force save DC. If a creature discerns the illusion for what
            it is, the creature can see through the image, and any noise it makes sounds hollow to the creature.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Mind Trick (Universal Force)</name>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Choose a target within range that isn’t hostile toward you. The target must make a Wisdom saving throw. On
            a failed save, the target has disadvantage on Wisdom (Perception) and Intelligence (Investigation) checks.

            On a successful save, the creature realizes that you tried to use the Force to influence its awareness and
            becomes hostile toward you. A creature prone to violence might attack you. Another creature might seek
            retribution in other ways (at the GM’s discretion), depending on the nature of your interaction with it.
            This power has no effect on droids or constructs.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Remove Curse (Light Force)</name>
        <level>3</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>At your touch, all curses affecting one creature or object end. If the object is a cursed enhanced item,
            its curse remains, but the power breaks its owner’s attunement to the object so it can be removed or
            discarded.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Denounce (Dark Force)</name>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <duration>1 minute, concentration</duration>
        <text>A target of your choice within range must make a Charisma saving throw. On a failed save, when the target
            makes their next attack roll or saving throw they must roll a d4 and subtract the number from it. The power
            then ends.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Zzz (Light Force)</name>
        <level>8</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>90 feet</range>
        <duration>Up to 1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite:


            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Saber Ward (Universal Force)</name>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>You take a defensive stance. Until the end of your next turn, you have resistance against kinetic and
            energy damage dealt by weapons.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Force Lightning (Dark Force)</name>
        <level>3</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self (100-foot line)</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Shock

            A stroke of lightning forming a line 100 feet long and 5 feet wide blasts out from you in a direction you
            choose. Each creature in the line must make a Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes 8d6 lightning damage
            on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.

            The lightning ignites flammable objects in the area that aren’t being worn or carried.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by
            1d6 for each slot level above 3rd.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>8d6</roll>
        <roll>9d6</roll>
        <roll>10d6</roll>
        <roll>11d6</roll>
        <roll>12d6</roll>
        <roll>13d6</roll>
        <roll>14d6</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Saber Throw (Universal Force)</name>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>As a part of the action used to cast this power, you must make a ranged force attack with a lightweapon or
            vibroweapon against one target within the power’s range, otherwise the power fails. On a hit, the target
            takes 1d8 damage of the same type as the weapon’s damage. The weapon then immediately returns to your hand.

            This power can hit multiple targets when you reach higher levels: two targets at 5th level, three targets at
            11th level, and four targets at 17th level. Each target must be within 30 feet of the previous target, you
            must make a separate attack roll for each target, and the last target must be no further than 30 feet away
            from you. You can not hit the same target twice in succession.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>1d8</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Scourge (Dark Force)</name>
        <level>6</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Plague

            For the power’s duration, your eyes become an inky void imbued with dread power. One creature of your choice
            within 60 feet of you that you can see must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or be affected by one of
            the following effects of your choice for the duration. On each of your turns until the power ends, you can
            use your action to target another creature but can’t target a creature again if it has succeeded on a saving
            throw against this casting of scourge.

            Asleep: The target falls unconscious. It wakes up if it takes any damage or if another creature uses its
            action to shake the sleeper awake.

            Panicked: The target is frightened of you. On each of its turns, the frightened creature must take the Dash
            action and move away from you by the safest and shortest available route, unless there is nowhere to move.
            If the target moves to a place at least 60 feet away from you where it can no longer see you, this effect
            ends.

            Sickened: The target has disadvantage on attack rolls and ability checks. At the end of each of its turns,
            it can make another Wisdom saving throw. If it succeeds, the effect ends.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Force Disarm (Universal Force)</name>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <duration>minute</duration>
        <text>You select a weapon being worn or carried by a Large or smaller creature within range. The creature must
            make a Strength or Dexterity saving throw (the creature chooses the ability to use). If the item is being
            worn, this save is made with disadvantage. On a failed save, the creature takes 1d4 force damage and the
            item is pulled directly to you. If you have a free hand, you catch the weapon. Otherwise, it lands at your
            feet.

            This power’s damage increases by 1d4 when you reach 5th level (2d4), 11th level (3d4), and 17th level (4d4).

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>1d4</roll>
        <roll>2d4</roll>
        <roll>3d4</roll>
        <roll>4d4</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Improved Dark Side Tendrils (Dark Force)</name>
        <level>3</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>150 feet</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Dark Side Tendrils

            You summon a 20-foot-radius sphere of inky blackness at a point within range. No light, enhanced or
            otherwise, can illuminate the area, creatures fully within the area are blinded, and the area is difficult
            terrain. Any creature that starts its turn in the area takes 2d6 necrotic damage. Any creature that ends its
            turn in the area must succeed on a Strength saving throw or take 2d6 poison damage as tendrils of dark
            energy caress it.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>2d6</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Improved Feedback (Dark Force)</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Feedback

            You unleash a blast of psychic energy at a target within range. If the target can hear you (though it need
            not understand you), it must succeed on an Intelligence saving throw. On a failed save, it takes 3d6 psychic
            damage and must immediately use its reaction, if available, to move as far as its speed allows away from
            you. The creature doesn’t move into obviously dangerous ground, such as a fire or a pit. On a successful
            save, the target takes half as much damage and doesn’t have to move away. A deafened creature automatically
            succeeds on the save.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by
            1d6 for each slot level above 1st.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>3d6</roll>
        <roll>4d6</roll>
        <roll>5d6</roll>
        <roll>6d6</roll>
        <roll>7d6</roll>
        <roll>8d6</roll>
        <roll>9d6</roll>
        <roll>10d6</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Dominate Mind (Dark Force)</name>
        <level>5</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Dominate Beast

            You attempt to beguile a humanoid that you can see within range. It must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or
            be charmed by you for the duration. If you or creatures that are friendly to you are fighting it, it has
            advantage on the saving throw.

            While the target is charmed, you have a telepathic link with it as long as you are within 1 mile of it. You
            can use this telepathic link to issue commands to the creature while you are conscious (no action required),
            which it does its best to obey. You can specify a simple and general course of action, such as “Attack that
            creature,” “Run over there,” or “Fetch that object.” If the creature completes the order and doesn’t receive
            further direction from you, it defends and preserves itself to the best of its ability.

            You can use your action to take total and precise control of the target. Until the end of your next turn,
            the creature takes only the actions you choose, and doesn’t do anything that you don’t allow it to do.
            During this time you can also cause the creature to use a reaction, but this requires you to use your own
            reaction as well.

            Each time the target takes damage, it makes a new Wisdom saving throw against the power. If the saving throw
            succeeds, the power ends. This power has no effect on droids or constructs.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a 6th-level force slot, the duration is 10 minutes. When you
            use a 7th-level force slot, the duration is 1 hour. When you use a force slot of 8th level or higher, the
            duration is 8 hours.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Fear (Dark Force)</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>You awaken the sense of mortality in one creature you can see within range. The target must succeed on a
            Wisdom saving throw or become frightened for the duration. A target with 25 hit points or fewer makes the
            saving throw with disadvantage. This power has no effect on constructs or droids.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Stun (Light Force)</name>
        <level>2</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Choose a creature that you can see within range. The target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be
            paralyzed for the duration. At the end of each of its turns, the target can make another Wisdom saving
            throw. On a success, the power ends on the target.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Dark Shear (Dark Force)</name>
        <level>2</level>
        <time>1 bonus action</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>You create a weapon of imperceptible Force energy that lasts until the power ends. It counts as a simple
            lightweapon with which you are proficient. It deals 2d6 psychic damage, and has the finesse, light, and
            thrown properties (range 20/60). When you attack while within dim light or darkness, you have advantage.

            If you drop the weapon or throw it, it disappears at the end of the turn. While the power lasts, you can use
            a bonus action to make the weapon reappear in your hand.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a 3rd or 4th level force slot, the damage increases by 1d6
            (3d6). At 5th or 6th level, the damage increases by 2d6 (4d6). At 7th level or higher, the damage increases
            by 3d6 (5d6).

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>2d6</roll>
        <roll>3d6</roll>
        <roll>4d6</roll>
        <roll>5d6</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Sonic Charge (Universal Force)</name>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Varies</range>
        <duration>1 round</duration>
        <text>As part of the action used to cast this power, you must make a melee attack with a weapon against one
            creature within your weapon’s reach, otherwise the power fails. On a hit, the target suffers the attack’s
            normal effects, and you begin to emanate a disturbing hum until the start of your next turn. If a hostile
            creature ends its turn within 5 feet of you, it takes 1d4 sonic damage.

            This power’s damage increases when you reach higher levels. At 5th level, the melee attack deals an extra
            1d8 sonic damage to the target, and the secondary damage increases by 1d4. Both damage rolls increase by 1d8
            and 1d4, respectively, at 11th level and 17th level.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>1d4</roll>
        <roll>1d8</roll>
        <roll>2d4</roll>
        <roll>2d8</roll>
        <roll>3d4</roll>
        <roll>3d8</roll>
        <roll>4d4</roll>
        <roll>4d8</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Locate Creature (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>4</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Locate Object

            Describe or name a creature familiar to you. You sense the direction to the creature’s location, as long as
            its within 1000 feet of you. If the creature is in motion, you know the direction of its movement. The power
            can locate a specific creature known to you or the nearest of a specific kind, as long as you have seen it
            while within 30 feet of it. If the creature is in a different form, the power doesn’t work. This power can’t
            locate a creature if running water at least 10 feet wide blocks a direct path between you and the creature.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Force Enlightenment (Light Force)</name>
        <level>2</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <duration>Up to 1 hour, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Guidance

            You touch a creature and enhance it with the Force. Choose one of the following effects; the target gains
            that effect until the power ends.

            Endurance: The target has advantage on Constitution checks. It also gains 2d6 temporary hit points, which
            are lost when the power ends.

            Strength: The target has advantage on Strength checks, and his or her carrying capacity doubles.

            Dexterity: The target has advantage on Dexterity checks. It also doesn’t take damage from falling 20 feet or
            less if it isn’t incapacitated.

            Splendor: The target has advantage on Charisma checks.

            Cunning: The target has advantage on Intelligence checks.

            Wisdom: The target has advantage on Wisdom checks.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force slot of 3rd level or higher, you can target one
            additional creature for each slot level above 2nd.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Feedback (Dark Force)</name>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <duration>minute</duration>
        <text>You unleash a burst of psychic energy at a target within range. If the target can hear you (though it need
            not understand you), it must succeed on an Intelligence saving throw or take 1d4 psychic damage and have
            disadvantage on the next attack roll it makes before the end of its next turn.

            This power’s damage increases by 1d4 when you reach 5th level (2d4), 11th level (3d4), and 17th level (4d4).

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>1d4</roll>
        <roll>2d4</roll>
        <roll>3d4</roll>
        <roll>4d4</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Force Confusion (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>2</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>120 feet</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>One humanoid of your choice that you can see within range must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or become
            charmed by you for the duration. The charmed target must use its action before moving on each of its turns
            to make a melee attack against a creature other than itself that you mentally choose.

            The target can act normally on its turn if you choose no creature or if none are within its reach.

            On your subsequent turns, you must use your action to maintain control over the target, or the power ends.
            Also, the target can make a Wisdom saving throw at the end of each of its turns. On a success, the power
            ends.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Hex (Dark Force)</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 bonus action</time>
        <range>90 feet</range>
        <duration>Up to one hour, concentration</duration>
        <text>You curse an opponent within range. Until the power ends, you deal an extra 1d6 necrotic damage to the
            target whenever you hit it with an attack. Also, choose one ability when you cast the power. The target has
            disadvantage on ability checks made with the chosen ability.

            If the target drops to 0 hit points before this power ends, you can use a bonus action on a subsequent turn
            of yours to curse a new creature.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force slot of 3rd or 4th level, you can maintain your
            concentration on the power for up to 8 hours. When you use a force slot of 5th level or higher, you can
            maintain your concentration on the power for up to 24 hours.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>1d6</roll>
        <classes>Sorcerer, Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Guidance (Light Force)</name>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>You touch one willing creature. Once before the power ends, the target can roll a d4 and add the number
            rolled to one ability check of its choice. It can roll the die before or after making the ability check. The
            power then ends.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Battle Meditation (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>2</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self (5-foot raduis)</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>You exude an aura out to 5 feet that boosts the morale and overall battle prowess you and your allies
            while simultaneously reducing the opposition’s combat-effectiveness by eroding their will to fight.

            Whenever you or a friendly creature within your meditation makes an attack roll or a saving throw, they can
            roll a d4 and add the number rolled to the attack roll or saving throw.

            Whenever a hostile creature starts enters your meditation or starts its turn there, it must make a Charisma
            saving throw. On a failed save, it must roll a d4 and subtract the number rolled from each attack roll or
            saving throw it makes before the end of your next turn. On a successful save, it is immune to this power for
            1 day.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Phasestrike (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 bonus action</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Until the power ends, your movement doesn’t provoke opportunity attacks.

            Once before the power ends, you can give yourself advantage on one weapon attack roll on your turn. That
            attack deals an extra 1d8 force damage on a hit. Whether you hit or miss, your walking speed increases by 30
            feet until the end of that turn.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>1d8</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Force Lightning Cone (Dark Force)</name>
        <level>7</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self (60-foot cone)</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Force Chain Lightning

            Lightning arcs from your hands. Each creature in a 60-foot cone must make a Dexterity saving throw. A
            creatures takes 12d6 lightning damage on a failed save, or half as much on a successful one.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force slot of 8th level or higher, the damage increases by
            2d6 for each slot level above 7th.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>12d6</roll>
        <roll>14d6</roll>
        <roll>16d6</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Dominate Monster (Dark Force)</name>
        <level>8</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <duration>Up to 1 hour, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Dominate Mind

            You attempt to beguile a creature that you can see within range. It must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or
            be charmed by you for the duration. If you or creatures that are friendly to you are fighting it, it has
            advantage on the saving throw.

            While the creature is charmed, you have a telepathic link with it as long as you are within 1 mile of it.
            You can use this telepathic link to issue commands to the creature while you are conscious (no action
            required), which it does its best to obey. You can specify a simple and general course of action, such as
            “Attack that creature,” “Run over there,” or “Fetch that object.” If the creature completes the order and
            doesn’t receive further direction from you, it defends and preserves itself to the best of its ability.

            You can use your action to take total and precise control of the target. Until the end of your next turn,
            the creature takes only the actions you choose, and doesn’t do anything that you don’t allow it to do.
            During this time, you can also cause the creature to use a reaction, but this requires you to use your own
            reaction as well.

            Each time the target takes damage, it makes a new Wisdom saving throw against the power. If the saving throw
            succeeds, the power ends.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power with a 9th-level force slot, the duration is concentration, up to 8
            hours.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Battle Precognition (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <duration>8 Hours</duration>
        <text>Your attunement to the Force warns you when you are about to enter danger. Until the power ends, your base
            AC becomes 13 + your Dexterity modifier. This power has no effect if you are wearing armor.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>13+%2</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Danger Sense (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>2</level>
        <time>1 bonus action</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>You put your faith in the Force, feeling out the future and seeing whether your actions will lead to
            fortune or ruin. The GM chooses from the following possible omens:

            • Peace, for results which are not dangerous
            • Danger, for results which are dangerous but perhaps still worth the danger
            • Ruin, for results which are certain to end in death or tragedy

            The power doesn’t take into account any possible circumstances that might change the outcome, such as the
            use of additional powers or the loss or gain of a companion.

            If you use this power two or more times before completing your next long rest, there is a cumulative 25
            percent chance for each casting after the first that you get a neutral result regardless of the actual
            outcome.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Psychic Charge (Dark Force)</name>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Varies</range>
        <duration>1 round</duration>
        <text>As part of the action used to cast this power, you must make a melee attack with a weapon against one
            creature within your weapon’s reach, otherwise the power fails. On a hit, the target suffers the attack’s
            normal effects, and its mouth is covered by a violet veil until the start of your next turn. If the target
            willingly speaks before then, it immediately takes 1d8 psychic damage, and the power ends.

            This power’s damage increases when you reach higher levels. At 5th level, the melee attack deals an extra
            1d8 psychic damage to the target, and the damage the target takes for speaking increases to 2d8. Both damage
            rolls increase by 1d8 at 11th level and 17th level.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>1d8</roll>
        <roll>2d8</roll>
        <roll>3d8</roll>
        <roll>4d8</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Calm Emotions (Light Force)</name>
        <level>2</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>You attempt to suppress strong emotions in a group of people. Each humanoid in a 20-foot-radius sphere
            centered on a point you choose within range must make a Charisma saving throw a creature can choose to fail
            this saving throw if it wishes. If a creature fails its saving throw, choose one of the following two
            effects.

            • You can suppress any effect causing a target to be charmed or frightened. When this power ends, any
            suppressed effect resumes, provided that its duration has not expired in the meantime.
            • You can make a target indifferent about creatures of your choice that it is hostile toward. This
            indifference ends if the target is attacked or harmed by a power or if it witnesses any of its friends being
            harmed.

            When the power ends, the creature becomes hostile again, unless the GM rules otherwise.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Hysteria (Dark Force)</name>
        <level>4</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>120 feet</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Hallucination

            You tap into the nightmares of a creature you can see within range and create an illusory manifestation of
            its deepest fears, visible only to that creature. The target becomes frightened for the duration. At the end
            of each of the target’s turns before the power ends, the target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or
            take 4d10 psychic damage. On a successful save, the power ends. This power has no effect on droids or
            constructs.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force power slot of 5th level or higher, the damage
            increases by 1d10 for each slot level above 4th.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>4d10</roll>
        <roll>5d10</roll>
        <roll>6d10</roll>
        <roll>7d10</roll>
        <roll>8d10</roll>
        <roll>9d10</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Force Blind/Deafen (Light Force)</name>
        <level>2</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <duration>1 minute</duration>
        <text>You can blind or deafen a foe. Choose one creature that you can see within range to make a Constitution
            saving throw. If it fails, the target is either blinded or deafened (your choice) for the duration. At the
            end of each of its turns, the target can make a Constitution saving throw. On a success, the power ends.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force slot of 3rd level or higher, you can target one
            additional creature for each slot level above 2nd.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Force Suppression (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>3</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>120 feet</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>Choose one creature, object, or force effect within range. Any force power of 3rd level or lower on the
            target ends. For each force power of 4th level or higher on the target, make an ability check using your
            forcecasting ability. The DC equals 10 + the power’s level. On a success, the power ends.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force slot of 4th level or higher, you automatically end the
            effects of a force power on the target if the power’s level is equal to or less than the level of the force
            slot you used.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Telekinesis (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>5</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>90 feet</range>
        <duration>Up to 10 minutes, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Force Throw

            You gain the ability to move or manipulate creatures and objects with the Force. When you cast this power,
            and as your action each round for the duration, you can exert your will on one creature or object that you
            can see within range, causing the appropriate effect below. You can affect the same target round after
            round, or choose a new one at any time. If you switch targets, the prior target is no longer affected by the
            power.

            Creature: You can try to move a Huge or smaller creature. The target must make a Strength saving throw. On a
            failed save, you move the creature up to 30 feet in any direction, including upward but not beyond the range
            of this power. Until the end of your next turn, the creature is restrained in your telekinetic grip. A
            creature lifted upward is suspended in mid-air.

            On subsequent rounds, you can use your action to attempt to maintain your telekinetic grip on the creature
            by repeating the contest.

            Object: You move an object that isn’t being worn or carried and weighs up to 1,000 lbs up to 30 feet in any
            direction, but not beyond the range of this power.

            You can exert fine control on objects with your telekinetic grip, such as manipulating a simple tool,
            opening a door or a container, stowing or retrieving an item from an open container, or pouring the contents
            from a vial.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Share Life (Light Force)</name>
        <level>3</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>You sacrifice some of your health to mend another creature’s injuries. You take 4d8 necrotic damage, and
            one creature of your choice that you can see within range regains a number of hit points equal to twice the
            necrotic damage you take. This power has no effect on droids or constructs.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by
            1d8 for each slot level above 3rd.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>4d8</roll>
        <roll>5d8</roll>
        <roll>6d8</roll>
        <roll>7d8</roll>
        <roll>8d8</roll>
        <roll>9d8</roll>
        <roll>10d8</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Force Trance (Light Force)</name>
        <level>3</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <duration>10 minutes</duration>
        <text>You make a calming gesture, and up to three willing creatures of your choice that you can see within range
            fall unconscious for the power’s duration. The power ends on a target early if it takes damage or someone
            uses an action to shake or slap it awake. If a target remains unconscious for the full duration, that target
            gains the benefit of a short rest, and it can’t be affected by this power again until it finishes a long
            rest.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force slot of 4th level or higher, you can target one
            additional willing creature for each slot level above 3rd.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Force Throw (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Force Push/Pull

            Choose one or more creatures or objects within 60 feet that weigh up to 15 pounds. The object immediately
            moves 60 feet in a direction of your choice. If the object ends this movement in the air, it immediately
            falls to the ground. If the object collides with anything during its travel, both the object and the target
            take 3d8 kinetic damage. If the target is a creature, it must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed
            save, it takes 3d8 kinetic damage, or half as much on a successful one.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force slot of 2nd level or higher, the maximum weight
            increases by 15 pounds and the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 1st.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>3d8</roll>
        <roll>4d8</roll>
        <roll>5d8</roll>
        <roll>6d8</roll>
        <roll>7d8</roll>
        <roll>8d8</roll>
        <roll>9d8</roll>
        <roll>10d8</roll>
        <roll>11d8</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Rage (Dark Force)</name>
        <level>6</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <duration>Up to 10 minutes, Concentration</duration>
        <text>You endow yourself with endurance and martial prowess fueled by the Force. Until the power ends, you can’t
            cast powers, and you gain the following benefits:

            • You gain 50 temporary hit points. If any of these remain when the power ends, they are lost.
            • You have advantage on attack rolls that you make with lightweapons and vibroweapons.
            • When you hit a target with a weapon attack, that target takes an extra 2d12 force damage.
            • You have proficiency with all armor, lightweapons, and vibroweapons.
            • You have proficiency in Strength and Constitution saving throws.
            • You can attack twice, instead of once, when you take the Attack action on your turn. You ignore this
            benefit if you already have a feature, like Extra Attack, that gives you extra attacks.

            Immediately after the power ends, you must succeed on a DC 15 Constitution saving throw or suffer one level
            of exhaustion.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Revitalize (Light Force)</name>
        <level>5</level>
        <time>1 minute</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Spare the Dying

            You return a dead creature you touch to life, provided that it has been dead no longer than 10 minutes. If
            the creature’s soul is both willing and at liberty to rejoin the body, the creature returns to life with 1
            hit point.

            This power also neutralizes any poisons and cures diseases that affected the creature at the time it died.

            This power closes all mortal wounds, but it doesn’t restore missing body parts. If the creature is lacking
            body parts or organs integral for its survival – its head, for instance – the power automatically fails.

            Coming back from the dead is an ordeal. The target takes a -4 penalty to all attack rolls, saving throws,
            and ability checks. Every time the target finishes a long rest, the penalty is reduced by 1 until it
            disappears.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Slow (Dark Force)</name>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>15 feet</range>
        <duration>1 hour</duration>
        <text>A hostile creature of your choice must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, the target’s
            speed decreases by 10 feet until the power ends.

            The target’s speed decreases by 5 more feet when you reach 5th level (15 feet), 11th level (20 feet), and
            17th level (25 feet).

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Give Life (Light Force)</name>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>Placing your hand on another creature you can transfer your own life force to them. You spend and roll one
            of your hit dice and the creature regains that many hit points. This power has no effect on droids or
            constructs.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Master Speed (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>7</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <duration>Up to 1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Knight Speed

            Choose up to two willing creatures that you can see within range. Until the power ends, each targets’ speed
            is doubled, they gain a +2 bonus to AC, they have advantage on Dexterity saving throws, and they gain an
            additional action on each of their turns. That action can be used only to take the Attack (one weapon attack
            only), Dash, Disengage, Hide, or the Use an Object Action.

            When the power ends, each target can’t move or take actions until after its next turn, as a wave of lethargy
            sweeps over it.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force slot of 8th-level or higher, you can target one
            additional creature for each slot level above 7th.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Dominate Beast (Dark Force)</name>
        <level>4</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>A beast you can see must succeed on a Wisdom save or be charmed. If you or your companions are fighting
            it, it has advantage on this saving throw.

            While it’s charmed, you have a telepathic link to it if you’re on the same planet. You can use this link to
            issue commands while you are conscious, no action required, which it does its best to obey. You can specify
            a simple and general course of action. If it completes the order and doesn’t receive further orders, it
            focuses on defending itself.

            You can use your action to take total control of the target. Until the end of your next turn, the beast
            takes only the actions you decide and nothing you don’t allow it to. You can also have the beast use a
            reaction, but this takes your reaction as well.

            If the beast takes damage, it makes another Wisdom save. On a success, the power ends.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a 5th-level force slot, the duration is up to 10 minutes. At a
            6th-level slot, the duration is up to 1 hour. At a slot of 7th or higher, the duration is up to 8 hours.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Improved Heal (Light Force)</name>
        <level>5</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Heal

            A wave of healing energy washes out from a point of your choice within range. Choose up to six creatures in
            a 30-foot-radius sphere centered on that point. Each target regains hit points equal to 3d8 + your
            forcecasting ability modifier. This power has no effect on droids or constructs.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force slot of 6th level or higher, the healing increases by
            1d8 for each slot level above 5th.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>3d8+%6</roll>
        <roll>4d8+%6</roll>
        <roll>5d8+%6</roll>
        <roll>6d8+%6</roll>
        <roll>7d8+%6</roll>
        <roll>3d8+%5</roll>
        <roll>4d8+%5</roll>
        <roll>5d8+%5</roll>
        <roll>6d8+%5</roll>
        <roll>7d8+%5</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Improved Force Barrier (Light Force)</name>
        <level>5</level>
        <time>10 minutes</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Force Barrier

            This power further bolsters your allies with toughness and resolve. Choose up to twelve creatures within
            range. Each target gains the following benefits:

            • The becomes immune to poison and disease. Any currently existing poison or diseases still exist.
            • The creature becomes immune to being frightened by powers.
            • The creature’s hit point maximum and current hit points increase by 2d10 for the duration.

            These benefits last for 24 hours or until the end of your next long rest, whichever happens first.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>2d10</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Force Mask (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <duration>1 hour</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Mind Trick

            Until the power ends or you use an action to dismiss it, you can disguise yourself through use of the Force
            in many ways. You can appear to be shorter or taller by about a foot and change the appearance of your body
            and weight, but you cannot change the basic structure of your body. This effect can include your clothes,
            weapons, and other belongings on your person.

            This effect is only visual, so any sort of physical contact will only interact with the real size and shape
            of you. A creature that uses its action to examine you can identify this effect with a successful
            Intelligence (Investigation) check against your force save DC. This power has no effect on droids or
            constructs.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Force Link (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>8</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Unlimited</range>
        <duration>24 hours</duration>
        <text>You create a telepathic link between yourself and a willing creature with which you are familiar. Until
            the power ends, you and the target can instantaneously share words, images, sounds, and other sensory
            messages with one another through the link, and the target recognizes you as the creature it is
            communicating with. The power enables a creature with an Intelligence score of at least 1 to understand the
            meaning of your words and take in the scope of any sensory messages you send to it.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Master Force Barrier (Light Force)</name>
        <level>8</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <duration>Up to 1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Improved Force Barrier

            This power massively bolsters your allies with toughness and resolve. Creatures of your choice in a 30-foot
            radius around you when you cast this power gain the following benefits:

            • The creature sheds dim light in a 5-foot radius.
            • The creature has advantage on all saving throws
            • Other creatures have disadvantage on attack rolls against them.
            • When a dark side creature hits them with a melee attack, that creature must make a Constitution saving
            throw or be blinded until the power ends.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Force Chain Lightning (Dark Force)</name>
        <level>6</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>150 feet</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Force Lightning

            You create a bolt of lightning that arcs toward a target of your choice that you can see within range. Three
            bolts then leap from that target to as many as three other targets, each of which must be within 30 feet of
            the first target. A target can be a creature or an object and can be targeted by only one of the bolts.

            A target must make a Dexterity saving throw. The target takes 10d8 lightning damage on a failed save, or
            half as much damage on a successful one.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force slot of 7th level or higher, one additional bolt leaps
            from the first target to another target for each slot level above 6th.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>10d8</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Destroy Droid (Light Force)</name>
        <level>7</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>120 feet (30-foot cube)</range>
        <duration>Up to 1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Disable Droid

            Choose a point that you can see within range. Each droid must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or be
            paralyzed for the duration. At the beginning of each of its turns, the droid takes energy damage equal to
            twice your forcecasting ability modifier and then repeats this saving throw. On a success, the power ends on
            the target.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Beacon of Hope (Light Force)</name>
        <level>3</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Heroism

            This power bestows hope and vitality. Choose any number of creatures within range. For the duration, each
            target has advantage on Wisdom saving throws and death saving throws, and regains the maximum number of hit
            points possible from any healing.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Earthquake (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>8</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>500 feet</range>
        <duration>Up to 1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Eruption

            You create a seismic disturbance at a point on the ground that you can see within range. For the duration,
            an intense tremor rips through the ground in a 100-foot-radius circle centered on that point and shakes
            creatures and structures in contact with the ground in that area.

            The ground in the area becomes difficult terrain. Each creature on the ground that is concentrating must
            make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, the creature’s concentration is broken.

            When you cast this power and at the end of each turn you spend concentrating on it, each creature on the
            ground in the area must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, the creature is knocked prone.

            This power can have additional effects depending on the terrain in the area, as determined by the GM.

            Fissures: Fissures open throughout the power’s area at the start of your next turn after you cast the power.
            A total of 1d6 such fissures open in locations chosen by the GM. Each is 1d10 x 10 feet deep, 10 feet wide,
            and extends from one edge of the power’s area to the opposite side. A creature standing on a spot where a
            fissure opens must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or fall in. A creature that successfully saves moves
            with the fissure’s edge as it opens.

            A fissure that opens beneath a structure causes it to automatically collapse (see below).

            Structures: The tremor deals 50 kinetic damage to any structure in contact with the ground in the area when
            you cast the power and at the start of each of your turns until the power ends. If a structure drops to 0
            hit points, it collapses and potentially damages nearby creatures. A creature within half the distance of a
            structure’s height must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, the creature takes 5d6 kinetic
            damage, is knocked prone, and is buried in the rubble, requiring a DC 20 Strength (Athletics) check as an
            action to escape. The GM can adjust the DC higher or lower, depending on the nature of the rubble. On a
            successful save, the creature takes half as much damage and doesn’t fall prone or become buried.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>1d6</roll>
        <roll>5d6</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Sanctuary (Light Force)</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 bonus action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <duration>1 minute</duration>
        <text>Until the power ends, any creature who targets the warded creature with an attack, a harmful power, or a
            hostile action must first make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the creature must choose a new
            target or lose the attack or power. This power doesn’t protect the warded creature from area effects.

            If the warded creature makes an attack, casts a power that affects an enemy creature, or takes a hostile
            action this power ends.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Improved Force Camouflage (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>4</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Force Camouflage

            A willing creature you touch becomes invisible until the power ends. Anything the target is wearing or
            carrying is invisible as long as it is on the target’s person.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Resistance (Universal Force)</name>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>You touch one willing creature. Once before the power ends, the target can roll a d4 and add the number
            rolled to one saving throw of its choice. It can roll the die before or after the saving throw. The power
            then ends.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Affect Mind (Universal Force)</name>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <duration>1 minute, concentration</duration>
        <text>Choose a target within range that isn’t hostile toward you. The target must make a Wisdom saving throw. On
            a failed save, you have advantage on all Charisma checks directed at that target.

            On a successful save, the creature realizes that you tried to use the Force to influence its mood and
            becomes hostile toward you. A creature prone to violence might attack you. Another creature might seek
            retribution in other ways (at the DM’s discretion), depending on the nature of your interaction with it.
            This power has no effect on droids or constructs.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Sap Vitality (Dark Force)</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>Make a melee force attack against a creature you can reach. On a hit, the target takes 3d10 necrotic
            damage.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by
            1d10 for each slot level above 1st.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>3d10</roll>
        <roll>4d10</roll>
        <roll>5d10</roll>
        <roll>6d10</roll>
        <roll>7d10</roll>
        <roll>8d10</roll>
        <roll>9d10</roll>
        <roll>10d10</roll>
        <roll>11d10</roll>
        <roll>12d10</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Dark Side Tendrils (Dark Force)</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self (10 foot radius)</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>Tendrils of dark energy erupt from you and batter all creatures within 10 feet of you. Each creature in
            that area must make a Strength saving throw. On a failed save, a target takes 2d6 necrotic damage and can’t
            take reactions until its next turn. On a successful save, the creature takes half damage, but suffers no
            other effect.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a power slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by
            1d6 for each slot level above 1st.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>2d6</roll>
        <roll>3d6</roll>
        <roll>4d6</roll>
        <roll>5d6</roll>
        <roll>6d6</roll>
        <roll>7d6</roll>
        <roll>8d6</roll>
        <roll>9d6</roll>
        <roll>10d6</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Improved Battle Meditation (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>5</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self (15-foot radius)</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Battle Meditation

            You exude an aura out to 15 feet that boosts the morale and overall battle prowess you and your allies while
            simultaneously reducing the opposition’s combat-effectiveness by eroding their will to fight.

            Whenever you or a friendly creature within your meditation makes an attack roll or a saving throw, they can
            roll a d6 and add the number rolled to the attack roll or saving throw.

            Whenever a hostile creature starts enters your meditation or starts its turn there, it must make a Charisma
            saving throw. On a failed save, it must roll a d6 and subtract the number rolled from each attack roll or
            saving throw it makes before the end of your next turn. On a successful save, it is immune to this power for
            1 day.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Improved Restoration (Light Force)</name>
        <level>5</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Restoration

            You imbue a creature you touch with positive energy to undo a debilitating effect. You can reduce the
            target’s exhaustion level by one, or end one of the following effects on the target:

            • One effect that charmed the target.
            • One curse, including the target’s attunement to a cursed item.
            • Any reduction to one of the target’s ability scores.
            • One effect reducing the target’s hit point maximum.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Force Body (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <duration>1 hour</duration>
        <text>This power enables you to use your health to fuel your force powers. For the duration, when you cast a
            force power, half the cost is paid by your force points (rounded up) and half the cost is paid by your hit
            points (rounded down). Additionally, your maximum hit points are decreased by this amount while the power is
            active.

            You may end this effect at any time. If you cast a force power that would reduce your hit points to 0, the
            power automatically fails and this effect ends.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Saber Reflect (Universal Force)</name>
        <time>1 reaction*</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>*which you take in response to being hit by a ranged attack.

            In response to being attacked, you raise your weapon to attempt to deflect. When you you use this power, the
            damage you take from the attack is reduced by 1d6. If you reduce the damage to 0, you’re wielding a
            lightweapon or vibroweapon, and the damage is energy or ion, you can reflect the attack at a target within
            range as part of the same reaction. Make a ranged force attack at a target you can see. The attack has a
            normal range of 20 feet and a long range of 60 feet. On a hit, the target takes the triggering attack’s
            normal damage.

            The power’s damage reduction increases by 1d6 when you reach 5th level (2d6), 11th level (3d6), and 17th
            level (4d6).

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>1d6</roll>
        <roll>2d6</roll>
        <roll>3d6</roll>
        <roll>4d6</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Force Immunity (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>4</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>An immobile, faintly shimmering barrier springs into existence around you and remains for the duration.
            The barrier moves with you.

            Any force power of 3rd level or lower cast from outside the barrier can’t affect you, even if the power is
            cast using a higher level force slot. Such a power can target you, but the power has no effect on you.
            Similarly, the area within the barrier is excluded from the areas affected by such powers.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force slot of 5th level or higher, the barrier blocks powers
            of one level higher for each slot level above 4th.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Improved Force Scream (Dark Force)</name>
        <level>5</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self (30-foot radius)</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Force Scream

            You emit a violent scream imbued with the power of the Force. Each creature you choose within 30 feet of you
            must succeed on a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, a creature take 5d6 psychic damage, 5d6 sonic
            damage, is deafened, and is knocked prone. On a successful save, it takes half as much damage and isn’t
            deafened or knocked prone.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>5d6</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Affliction (Dark Force)</name>
        <level>2</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Slow

            Choose a creature that you can see within range. That creature must make a Constitution saving throw. On a
            failed save, the target’s speed is halved, it takes a -2 penalty to AC and Dexterity saving throws, and it
            can’t use reactions. On its turn, it can use either an action or a bonus action, not both. Regardless of the
            creature’s abilities or items, it can’t make more than one melee or ranged attack during its turn.

            If the creature attempts to cast a power with a casting time of 1 action, roll a d20. On an 11 or higher,
            the power doesn’t take effect until the creature’s next turn, and the creature must use its action on that
            turn to complete the power. If it can’t, the power is wasted.

            The creatures makes another Wisdom saving throw at the end of its turn. On a successful save, the effect
            ends.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Disperse Force (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 reaction*</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <duration>1 round</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Saber Ward

            * which you take when you take cold, energy, fire, ion, lightning, or sonic damage

            This power absorbs damage from incoming energy attacks, lessening its effect on you and distributing it
            throughout your body. You have resistance to the triggering damage type until the start of your next turn.
            Also, you gain 5 temporary hit points to potentially absorb the attack. These temporary hit points last
            until the start of your next turn.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force slot of 2nd level or higher, the temporary hit points
            increases by 5 for each slot level above 1st.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Stasis (Light Force)</name>
        <level>5</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>90 feet</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Stun

            Choose up to 3 creatures that you can see within range. Each target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or
            be paralyzed for the duration. This power has no effect on droids or constructs. At the end of each of its
            turns, a target can make another Wisdom saving throw. On a success, the power ends on the target.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force slot of 6th level or higher, you can target an
            additional creature for each slot level above 5th.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Shock (Dark Force)</name>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>120 feet</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>You hurl a bolt of lightning at a target within range, making a ranged power attack. On a hit, the target
            takes 1d10 lightning damage. The lightning ignites flammable objects in the area that aren’t being worn or
            carried.

            This power’s damage increases by 1d10 when you reach 5th level (2d10), 11th level (3d10), and 17th level
            (4d10).

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>1d10</roll>
        <roll>2d10</roll>
        <roll>3d10</roll>
        <roll>4d10</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Eruption (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>6</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>120 feet</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Convulsion

            You cause up to six pillars of stone to burst from places on the ground that you can see within range. Each
            pillar is a cylinder that has a diameter of 5 feet and a height of up to 30 feet. The ground where a pillar
            appears must be wide enough for its diameter, and you can target the ground under a creature if that
            creature is Medium or smaller. Each pillar has AC 5 and 30 hit points. When reduced to 0 hit points, a
            pillar crumbles into rubble, which creates an area of difficult terrain with a 10 - foot radius that lasts
            until the rubble is cleared. Each 5-foot-diameter portion of the area requires at least 1 minute to clear by
            hand.

            If a pillar is created under a creature, that creature must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or be lifted
            by the pillar. A creature can choose to fail the save.

            If a pillar is prevented from reaching its full height because of a ceiling or other obstacle, a creature on
            the pillar takes 6d6 kinetic damage and is restrained, pinched between the pillar and the obstacle. The
            restrained creature can use an action to make a Strength or Dexterity check (the creature’s choice) against
            the power’s save DC. On a success, the creature is no longer restrained and must either move off the pillar
            or fall off it.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force slot of 7th level or higher, you can create two
            additional pillars for each slot level above 6th.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>6d6</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Convulsion (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>3</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>120 feet</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Tremor

            Choose a point you can see on the ground within range. A fountain of churned earth and stone erupts in a
            20-foot cube centered on that point. Each creature in that area must make a Dexterity saving throw. A
            creature takes 3d12 kinetic damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.
            Additionally, the ground in that area becomes difficult terrain until cleared. Each 5-foot-square portion of
            the area requires at least 1 minute to clear by hand.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by
            1d12 for each slot level above 3rd.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>3n12</roll>
        <roll>4n12</roll>
        <roll>5n12</roll>
        <roll>6n12</roll>
        <roll>7n12</roll>
        <roll>8n12</roll>
        <roll>9n12</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Coerce Mind (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>2</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <duration>Up to 8 hours, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Affect Mind

            You suggest a course of activity (limited to a sentence or two) and influence with the Force a creature you
            can see within range that can hear and understand you. Creatures that can’t be charmed are immune to this
            effect. The suggestion must be worded in such a manner as to make the course of action sound reasonable.
            Asking the creature to harm itself automatically negates the effect of the power.

            The target must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, it pursues the course of action you described
            to the best of its ability. The suggested course of action can continue for the entire duration. If the
            suggested activity can be completed in a shorter time, the power ends when the subject finishes what it was
            asked to do.

            You can also specify conditions that will trigger a special activity during the duration. For example, you
            might suggest that a soldier give her speeder to the first vagrant she meets. If the condition isn’t met
            before the power expires, the activity isn’t performed.

            If you or any of your companions damage the target, the power ends. This power has no effect on droids or
            constructs.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Freedom of Movement (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>4</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <duration>1 hour</duration>
        <text>You touch a willing creature. Its movement is unaffected by difficult terrain, and powers and enhanced
            effects can’t reduce its speed or cause it to be paralyzed or restrained.

            The target can spend 5 feet of movement to automatically escape from unenhanced restraints. Additionally,
            being underwater imposes no penalties on its movement or attacks.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Animate Weapon (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>2</level>
        <time>1 bonus action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <duration>1 minute</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Force Disarm

            You select a melee weapon you wield, or one melee weapon within range that is not worn or carried by a
            conscious creature, and use the Force to cause it to levitate, acting as an extension of your will for the
            duration or until you cast this power again. When you use this power, you can cause the weapon to move up to
            20 feet and make a melee force attack against a creature within 5 feet of it. On a hit, the target takes 1d8
            + your forcecasting ability modifier damage. The type is of the normal damage dealt by the weapon.

            While the weapon is animated, on each of your turns you can use a bonus action to move the weapon up to 20
            feet and repeat the attack against a creature within 5 feet of it. At any time, you can end this force power
            to return the animated weapon to your hand.

            An enemy can attempt to gain control of the weapon by making a Strength (Athletics) check against your force
            save DC. On a success, the creature gains control of the weapon and the power ends.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force slot of 3rd level or higher, the weapon’s damage
            increases by 1d8 for every two slot levels above 2nd.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>1d8</roll>
        <roll>2d8</roll>
        <roll>3d8</roll>
        <roll>4d8</roll>
        <roll>5d8</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Darkness (Dark Force)</name>
        <level>2</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <duration>Up to 10 minutes, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Darkness spreads from a point you choose within range to fill a 15-foot-radius sphere until the power
            ends. The darkness spreads around corners. A creature with darkvision can’t see through this darkness, and
            unenhanced light can’t illuminate it.

            If the point you choose is on an object you are holding or one that isn’t being worn or carried, the
            darkness comes from the object and moves with it. Completely covering the source of the darkness with an
            opaque object blocks the darkness.

            If this power’s area overlaps with light created by a 2nd-level power or lower, this power and the light are
            dispelled.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Burst of Speed (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <duration>1 hour</duration>
        <text>You touch a creature. The target’s speed increases by 10 feet until the power ends.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force slot of 2nd level or higher, you can target one
            additional creature for each slot level above 1st.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Guardian, Sentinel, Consular</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Curse (Dark Force)</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Denounce

            Up to three creatures of your choice that you can see within range must make Charisma saving throws.
            Whenever a target that fails this saving throw makes an attack roll or a saving throw before the power ends,
            the target must roll a d4 and subtract the number rolled from the attack roll or saving throw.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force slot of 2nd level or higher, you can target one
            additional creature for each slot level above 1st.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Choke (Dark Force)</name>
        <level>3</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>You make a constricting gesture at a creature within range. The target must make a Constitution saving
            throw. On a failed save target takes 5d8 force damage and is restrained until the end of your next turn. On
            a successful save, the target takes half as much damage and is not restrained.

            You can use a bonus action while the target is restrained to move the target up to 5 feet in any direction.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by
            1d8 for each slot level above 3rd.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Plant Surge (Light Force)</name>
        <level>3</level>
        <time>1 action or 8 hours</time>
        <range>150 feet</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>If you cast this power using 1 action, all normal plants in a 100-foot radius centered on a point become
            overgrown. Moving through the area spends 4 feet of movement for every 1 foot moved. You can exclude areas
            of any size within the power’s area from being affected.

            If you cast this power over 8 hours, all plants in a half-mile radius centered on a point yield twice the
            normal amount of food when harvested for 1 year.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Wound (Dark Force)</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>You make a piercing gesture at a creature within range. Make a ranged force attack against the target. On
            a hit, the target takes 2d8 necrotic damage and must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, it
            is also poisoned until the end of your next turn.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by
            1d8 for each slot level above 1st.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>2d8</roll>
        <roll>3d8</roll>
        <roll>4d8</roll>
        <roll>5d8</roll>
        <roll>6d8</roll>
        <roll>7d8</roll>
        <roll>8d8</roll>
        <roll>9d8</roll>
        <roll>10d8</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Death Field (Dark Force)</name>
        <level>8</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>90 feet (30-foot cube)</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Siphon Life

            You draw the life force from every creature in a 30-foot cube centered on a point you choose within range.
            Each creature in that area must make a Constitution saving throw. A creature takes 10d8 necrotic damage on a
            failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. If you reduce a hostile creature to 0, you gain
            temporary hit points equal to half the damage dealt. This power has no effect on droids or constructs.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>10d8</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Shroud of Darkness (Dark Force)</name>
        <level>4</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Darkness

            You become heavily obscured to others. Dim light within 10 feet of you becomes darkness, and bright light
            becomes dim light.

            Until the power ends, you have resistance to force damage. In addition, whenever a creature within 10 feet
            of you hits you with an attack, it takes 2d8 necrotic damage.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>2d8</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Wall of Light (Light Force)</name>
        <level>6</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>90 feet</range>
        <duration>Up to 10 minutes, Concentration</duration>
        <text>You conjure an immense manifestation of destructive light side Force energy. The wall appears within range
            and lasts for the duration. You can make a straight wall up to 100 feet long, 20 feet high, and 5 feet
            thick, or a ringed wall up to 60 feet in diameter, 20 feet high, and 5 feet thick. The wall provides
            three-quarters cover and its space is difficult terrain.

            When a creature enters the wall’s area for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there, it must make a
            Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, the creature takes 6d10 force damage, or half as much on a
            success.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>6d10</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Turbulence (Light Force)</name>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>120 feet</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>Choose one creature, or choose two creatures that are within 5 feet of each other, within range. A target
            must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or take 1d6 force damage.

            This power’s damage increases by 1d6 when you reach 5th, 11th, and 17th level.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Crush (Dark Force)</name>
        <level>6</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Choke

            You make a crushing gesture at a creature within range. The target must make a Constitution saving throw. On
            a failed save target takes 10d8 force damage and is paralyzed until the end of your next turn. On a
            successful save, the target takes half as much damage and is not paralyzed.

            You can use a bonus action while the target is paralyzed to move the target up to 10 feet in any direction.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force slot of 7th level or higher, the damage increases by
            1d8 for each slot level above 6th.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>10d8</roll>
        <roll>11d8</roll>
        <roll>12d8</roll>
        <roll>13d8</roll>
        <roll>14d8</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Force Breach (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>5</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>120 feet (20-foot cube)</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>Choose a spot within range. All force powers of 5th level or lower in the area end. For each force power
            of 6th level or higher in the area, make an ability check using your forcecasting ability. The DC equals 10
            + the power’s level. On a successful check, the force power ends.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force slot of 6th level or higher, you automatically end the
            effects of a force power on the target if the power’s level is equal to or less than the level of the force
            slot you used.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Breath Control (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <duration>10 minutes</duration>
        <text>You are able to slow your metabolism in such a way that you can stop breathing and resist the effect of
            toxins in your body. If you are poisoned, you neutralize the poison. If more than one poison afflicts you,
            you neutralize one poison that you know is present, or you neutralize one at random.

            For the duration, you have advantage on saving throws against being poisoned, resistance to poison damage,
            and you no longer need to breathe.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Mass Animation (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>5</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>120 feet</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Animate Weapon

            You snag several objects using the force and whip them into the air around you, controlling them to attack
            at your command. Choose up to ten unenhanced objects within range that are not being worn or carried. Medium
            targets count as two objects, Large targets count as four objects, Huge targets count as eight objects. You
            can’t control any object larger than Huge. Each object animates and hovers near you, remaining within 100
            feet of you for the duration. An animated object behaves as though it is was a construct, with AC, hit
            points, and attacks determined by its size, and a flying speed of 30 feet.

            As a bonus action, you can mentally direct any object controlled by this power. If you control multiple
            objects, you can command any or all of them at the same time. You decide what action the object will take
            and where it will move. The objects act at the end of your turn. If you command an object to attack, it can
            make a single melee attack against a creature within 5 feet of it. It makes a slam attack with an attack
            bonus and kinetic damage determined by its size.

            Tiny 20 16 +6 to hit, 1d4 + 3 damage
            Small 25 15 +6 to hit, 1d8 + 2 damage
            Medium 40 13 +5 to hit, 2d6 + 1 damage
            Large 50 10 +6 to hit, 2d10 + 2 damage
            Huge 80 10 +8 to hit, 2d12 + 4 damage

            Force Potency: If you cast this power using a force slot of 6th level or higher, you can animate two
            additional objects for each slot level above 5th.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Telekinetic Burst (Light Force)</name>
        <level>6</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self (60-foot line)</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Telekinetic Storm

            A beam of Force energy flashes out from your hand in a 5-foot-wide, 60-foot-long line. Each creature in the
            line must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 8d6 force damage and is
            knocked prone. On a successful save, it takes half as much damage and isn’t knocked prone.

            You can create a new telekinetic gust as your action on your turn until the power ends.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force slot of 7th level or higher, the damage increases by
            2d6 for each slot level above 6th.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>8d6</roll>
        <roll>10d6</roll>
        <roll>12d6</roll>
        <roll>14d6</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Improved Phasestrike (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>5</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Phasestrike

            Choose up to five creatures you can see within range. Make a melee force attack against each one. On hit, a
            target takes 6d10 force damage. You can then teleport to an unoccupied space you can see within 5 feet of
            one of the creatures you chose.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>6d10</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Spare the Dying (Light Force)</name>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>You touch a living creature that has 0 hit points. The creature becomes stable. This power has no effect
            on droids or constructs.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Lightning Charge (Dark Force)</name>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Varies</range>
        <duration>1 round</duration>
        <text>You imbue your weapon with debilitating force lightning. As part of the action used to cast this power,
            you must make a melee attack with a weapon against one creature within your weapon’s reach, otherwise the
            power fails. On a hit, the target suffers the attack’s normal effects, and the lightning leaps from the
            target to a different creature of your choice that you can see within 5 feet of it. The second creature
            takes lightning damage equal to your forcecasting ability modifier.

            This power’s damage increases when you reach higher levels. At 5th level, the melee attack deals an extra
            1d8 lightning damage to the target, and the lightning damage to the second creature increases to 1d8 + your
            forcecasting ability modifier. Both damage rolls increase by 1d8 at 11th level and 17th level.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>1d8</roll>
        <roll>2d8</roll>
        <roll>3d8</roll>
        <roll>4d8</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Bestow Curse (Dark Force)</name>
        <level>3</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Curse

            You touch a creature, and that creature must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or become cursed for the
            duration of the power. When you cast this power, choose the nature of the curse from the following options:

            • Choose one ability score. While cursed, the target has disadvantage on ability checks and saving throws
            made with that ability score.
            • While cursed, the target has disadvantage on attack rolls against you.
            • While cursed, the target must make a Wisdom saving throw at the start of each of its turns. lf it fails,
            it wastes its action that turn doing nothing.
            • While the target is cursed, your attacks and powers deal an extra 1d8 necrotic damage to the target.

            A remove curse power ends this effect. At the GM’s discretion, you may choose an alternative curse effect,
            but it should be no more powerful than those described above. The GM has final say on such a curse’s effect.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Sever Force (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>3</level>
        <time>1 reaction</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>You attempt to interrupt a creature in the process of casting a force power. If the creature is casting a
            power of 3rd level or lower, its power fails and has no effect. If it is casting a power of 4th level or
            higher, make an ability check using your forcecasting ability. The DC equals 10 + the power’s level. On a
            success, the creature’s power fails and has no effect.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force slot of 4th level or higher, the interrupted power has
            no effect if its level is less than or equal to the level of the force slot you used.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Sense Force (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <duration>Up to 10 minutes, Concentration</duration>
        <text>For the duration, you sense the use of the Force, or its presence in an inanimate object within 30 feet of
            you. If you sense the Force in this way, you can use your action to determine the direction from which it
            originates and, if it’s in line of sight, you see a faint aura around the person or object from which the
            Force emanates.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a 3rd-level force slot, the range increases to 60 feet. When
            you use a 5th-level force slot, the range increases to 500 feet. When you use a 7th-level force slot, the
            range increases to 1 mile. When you use a 9th-level force slot, the range increases to 10 miles.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Improved Phasewalk (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>5</level>
        <time>1 bonus action</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Phasewalk

            You teleport up to 60 feet to an unoccupied space you can see. On each of your turns before the power ends,
            you can use a bonus action to teleport in this way again.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Siphon Life (Dark Force)</name>
        <level>5</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Drain Life

            A tendril of inky darkness reaches out from you, touching a creature you can see within range to drain life
            from it. The target must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a successful save, the target takes 2d8 necrotic
            damage, and the power ends. On a failed save, the target takes 4d8 necrotic damage, and until the power
            ends, you can use your action on each of your turns to automatically deal 4d8 necrotic damage to the target.
            The power ends if you use your action to do anything else, if the target is ever outside the power’s range,
            or if the target has total cover from you.

            Whenever the power deals damage to a target, you regain hit points equal to half the amount of necrotic
            damage the target takes.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force slot of 6th level or higher, the damage increases by
            1d8 for each slot level above 5th.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>2d8</roll>
        <roll>4d8</roll>
        <roll>5d8</roll>
        <roll>7d8</roll>
        <roll>8d8</roll>
        <roll>9d8</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Phasewalk (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>2</level>
        <time>1 bonus action</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>You teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space that you can see.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Improved Revitalize (Light Force)</name>
        <level>7</level>
        <time>10 minutes</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Revitalize

            You return a dead creature you touch to life, provided that it has been dead no longer than 1 hour. If the
            creature’s soul is both willing and at liberty to rejoin the body, the creature returns to life with all its
            hit points.

            This power also neutralizes any poisons and cures diseases that affected the creature at the time it died.

            This power closes all mortal wounds and restores any missing body parts.

            Coming back from the dead is an ordeal. The target takes a -4 penalty to all attack rolls, saving throws,
            and ability checks. Every time the target finishes a long rest, the penalty is reduced by 1 until it
            disappears.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Grasping Vine (Light Force)</name>
        <level>4</level>
        <time>1 bonus action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Plant Surge

            You make a vine sprout from the ground in an unoccupied space you can see. When you cast this power, you can
            make the vine whip a creature up to 30 feet from it, if you can see the target. The creature must pass a
            Dexterity save or be pulled 20 feet directly toward the vine.

            Until the power ends, you can use your bonus action to have the vine lash out again.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Force Technique (Light Force)</name>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Varies</range>
        <duration>1 round</duration>
        <text>You select a weapon being worn or carried by a Large or smaller creature within range. The creature must
            make a Strength or Dexterity saving throw (the creature chooses the ability to use). If the item is being
            worn, this save is made with disadvantage. On a failed save, the creature takes 1d4 force damage and the
            item is pulled directly to you. If you have a free hand, you catch the weapon. Otherwise, it lands at your
            feet.

            This power’s damage increases by 1d4 when you reach 5th level (2d4), 11th level (3d4), and 17th level (4d4).

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Disable Droid (Light Force)</name>
        <level>4</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>90 feet (15-foot cube)</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Stun Droid

            Choose a point that you can see within range. Each droid must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or be
            paralyzed for the duration. At the beginning of each of its turns, the droid takes energy damage equal to
            your forcecasting ability modifier and then repeats this saving throw. On a success, the power ends on the
            target.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Burst (Universal Force)</name>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self (5-foot sphere)</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>You cause the earth to burst from beneath your feet. Each creature within range, other than you, must
            succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or take 1d6 kinetic damage.

            This power’s damage increases by 1d6 when you reach 5th level (2d6), 11th level (3d6), and 17th level (4d6).

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>1d6</roll>
        <roll>2d6</roll>
        <roll>4d6</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Force Barrier (Light Force)</name>
        <level>2</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <duration>8 hours</duration>
        <text>This power bolsters your allies with toughness and resolve. Choose up to three creatures within range.
            Each target’s hit point maximum and current hit points increase by 5 for the duration.

            Force Potency: When you cast this power using a force slot of 3rd level or higher, a target’s hit points
            increase by an additional 5 for each slot level above 2nd.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Force Push/Pull (Universal Force)</name>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>You gain the minor ability to move or manipulate creatures and objects with the Force. When you cast this
            power, you can exert your will on one creature or object that you can see within range, causing the
            appropriate effect below.

            Creature. You use the Force to push or pull on on a target. Make a ranged force attack against the target.
            If the attack hits, the creature takes 1d6 force damage, and if the creature is Large or smaller, it must
            make a Strength saving throw. On a failed save, you push or pull the creature up to 10 feet further or
            closer to you. This damage increases to 2d6 at level 5, 3d6 at level 11, and 4d6 at level 17.

            Object. You move an object that isn’t being worn or carried and weighs up to 10 lbs up to 30 feet in any
            direction, but not beyond the range of this power.

            You can exert fine control on objects with your telekinetic grip, such as manipulating a simple tool,
            opening a door or a container, stowing or retrieving an item from an open container, or pouring the contents
            from a vial.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <roll>1d6</roll>
        <roll>2d6</roll>
        <roll>3d6</roll>
        <roll>4d6</roll>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Ruin (Dark Force)</name>
        <level>7</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Wound

            You channel the dark side of the Force to desecrate a creature you can see within range, causing waves of
            intense pain to assail it. If the target has 100 hit points or fewer, it is subject to crippling pain.
            Otherwise, the power has no effect on it.

            While the target is affected by crippling pain, any speed it has can be no higher than 10 feet. The target
            also has disadvantage on attack rolls, ability checks, and saving throws, other than Constitution saving
            throws. Finally, if the target tries to cast a power, it must first succeed on a Constitution saving throw,
            or the casting fails and the power is wasted.

            A target suffering this pain can make a Constitution saving throw at the end of each of its turns. On a
            successful save, the pain ends.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Aura of Purity (Light Force)</name>
        <level>4</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self (30-foot radius)</range>
        <duration>Up to 10 minutes, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Prerequisite: Restoration

            Purifying energy radiates from you in a 30-foot radius. Until the power ends, the aura moves with you,
            centered on you. Each nonhostile creature in the aura (including you) can’t become diseased, has resistance
            to poison damage, and has advantage on saving throws against effects that cause any of the following
            conditions: blinded, charmed, deafened, frightened, paralyzed, poisoned, and stunned.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Locate Object (Universal Force)</name>
        <level>2</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <duration>1 minute, Concentration</duration>
        <text>Describe or name an object. You sense the direction to the object’s location, as long as its within 1000
            feet of you. If the object is in motion, you know the direction of its movement. The power can locate a
            specific object known to you, as long as you have seen it while within 30 feet of it. Alternatively, the
            power can locate the nearest object of a particular kind. This power can’t locate an object if any thickness
            of lead blocks a direct path between you and the object.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Force Sight (Light Force)</name>
        <level>2</level>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <duration>Up to 10 minutes, Concentration</duration>
        <text>You shift your vision to see through use of the Force; colors fade and inanimate objects appear as shades
            of gray. You gain the following benefits.

            • Living things glow with the power of the Force. Those with an affinity for the light side glow blue, those
            with an affinity for the dark side glow red, and those with no attunement to either side of the Force glow
            yellow. How bright they glow is determined by how strong their connection to the Force is.
            • You gain blindsight to 30 feet.
            • You have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight against living targets within 30 feet.

            Source: SW5e Player&#39;s Handbook
        </text>
        <classes>Consular, Guardian, Sentinel</classes>
    </spell>
</compendium>